<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>slatestarcodex.com on c13u&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.c13u.com/domains/slatestarcodex.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in slatestarcodex.com on c13u&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.c13u.com/domains/slatestarcodex.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Philanthropy</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/socioeconomics/2020-04-26-on-philanthropy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/socioeconomics/2020-04-26-on-philanthropy/</guid>
      <description>Criticism/Defense Of Billionaire Philanthropy  Taxes will probably not go to the same causes, e.g. reforming the bail system, grassroot efforts for migrants, etc.
Foundations are more effective than governments as they do their due diligence, e.g. Bill Gates. Reforming the government is a long battle.
Jack Dorsey (Twitter), set up $1B of his Square stock (28% of net worth) in an LLC to fund efforts for Covid-19, Girl&amp;rsquo;s Health and Education, and Universal Basic Income.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: All Therapy Books [Scott Alexander]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/social-science/psychology/2019-11-20-ssc-all-therapy-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/social-science/psychology/2019-11-20-ssc-all-therapy-books/</guid>
      <description>Book Review: All Therapy Books.  Scott Alexander. Slate Star Codex. https://slatestarcodex.com/2019/11/20/book-review-all-therapy-books/  .  Scott&amp;rsquo;s thesis: Each of the therapy books on their own can be convincing. But they should be taken in the context of All Therapy Books, which as a category are pretty worrying.
 Dodo Bird Verdict  : All psychotherapies are about equally good, and the only things that matters are &amp;ldquo;nonspecific factors&amp;rdquo; like how much patients like their therapist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Slate Star Codex) No Clarity Around Growth Mindset</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/personal_growth/letting_go/2015-04-08-ssc-no-clarity-around-the-growth-mindset/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/personal_growth/letting_go/2015-04-08-ssc-no-clarity-around-the-growth-mindset/</guid>
      <description>No Clarity Around Growth Mindset.  Scott Alexander. Slate Star Codex. https://slatestarcodex.com/2015/04/08/no-clarity-around-growth-mindset-yet/  . Apr 8, 2015.  Growth mindset: people who believe effort - and not ability - determines success are more resilient, skillful, hard-working, perseverant in the face of failure.
Most of the growth mindset experiments prime their subjects, but recent priming experiments have famously failed to replicate. Dweck&amp;rsquo;s experiment:
 Group A: easy test (success) -&amp;gt; final bound-to-fail test Group B: hard test (told they&amp;rsquo;re not working hard enough) -&amp;gt; final bound-to-fail test Group B outperformed Group A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (SSC) The Parable of the Talents</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/personal_growth/an_outlook_on_life/2015-01-31-ssc-the-principle-of-the-talents/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/personal_growth/an_outlook_on_life/2015-01-31-ssc-the-principle-of-the-talents/</guid>
      <description>The Parable of the Talents.  Scott Alexander. Slate Star Codex. https://slatestarcodex.com/2015/01/31/the-parable-of-the-talents/  . Jan 31, 2015.  Overweight people, depressed people, and poor people aren’t fully to blame for their situation – and neither are unintelligent people. It’s accidents of birth all the way down.
Srinivasa Ramanujan:
 Grew up in poverty in a one-room house in small-town India. But a lot of poor people in the US had better conditions/opportunities  Either, a lot of intelligence is innate Or, those poor people are just not trying hard enough.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
