<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Knowing on c13u&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/knowing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Knowing on c13u&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.c13u.com/notes/knowing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Theory, Evolution &amp; Games) Separating Theory from Nonsense via Communication Norms, not Truth</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/knowing/2018-09-08-teg-separating-theory-from-nonsense/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/knowing/2018-09-08-teg-separating-theory-from-nonsense/</guid>
      <description>Separating Theory from Nonsense via Communication Norms, not Truth.  Artem Kaznatcheev. Theory, Evolution &amp;amp; Games. https://egtheory.wordpress.com/2018/09/08/theory-norms/. Sep 8, 2018.  Brian Skinner - how to distinguish good theory from crackpottery  Both theorists and crackpots share an irrational self-confidence A crackpot relies primarily on positive evidence  Thinks hard about a problem, arrives at a theory that feels right, and then publicizes the result.   A theorist incorporates negative evidence:  Ponders hard about a problem, arrives at a theory that feels right and then proceeds to try to disprove that theory Takes time to understand competing theories and compare them against her own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Deep Work &amp; The 30-Hour Method for Learning a New Skill [Azeria Labs]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/knowing/2018-05-26-azeria-labs-importance-of-deep-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/knowing/2018-05-26-azeria-labs-importance-of-deep-work/</guid>
      <description>The Importance of Deep Work &amp;amp; The 30-Hour Method for Learning a New Skill.  Azeria Labs. https://azeria-labs.com/the-importance-of-deep-work-the-30-hour-method-for-learning-a-new-skill/. https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17163251.  30 Hour Deep Work Tryout:
 Scan resources and pick the ones that seem most useful (5 hours) Set up the environment and define structured goals (3 hours) Work towards increasingly difficult goals set in step 2 (22 hours)  Each session should be about 4 hours. It takes about 20min to get into the flow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Syll) What is Ergodicity?</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/knowing/2016-11-23-syll-what-is-ergodicity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/knowing/2016-11-23-syll-what-is-ergodicity/</guid>
      <description>What is Ergodicity?  Lars P. Syll. https://larspsyll.wordpress.com/2016/11/23/what-is-ergodicity-2/. Nov 23, 2016.  A random process is ergodic if all of its statistics can be determined from a sample function of the process. That is, the ensemble averages equal the corresponding time averages with probability one.
Role of Ergodicity in Human Inference  A newspaper has previously printed some inaccurate information, therefore, the newspaper is going to publish inaccurate information in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Read and Know [Paul Graham, Robert Heaton]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/knowing/2014-12-01-reading-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/knowing/2014-12-01-reading-to-know/</guid>
      <description>How to Read.  Robert Heaton. https://robertheaton.com/2018/06/25/how-to-read/. https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17424652. Jun 25, 2018.  Know.  Paul Graham. http://www.paulgraham.com/know.html. Dec 1, 2014.  Choose your content. Some books [and articles] are not worth the effort.
Information overload is one of my major obstacles to reading to know. There are so many pieces out there. I&#39;m biased towards highly upvoted HN submissions. My RSS feeds ran out of control a while back - my queue has +400 pending articles :-/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Age of the Essay [Paul Graham]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/knowing/2004-09-01-pg-the-age-of-the-essay/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/knowing/2004-09-01-pg-the-age-of-the-essay/</guid>
      <description>The Age of the Essay.  Paul Graham. http://www.paulgraham.com/essay.html. Sep 1, 2004.  The purpose of an essay is to figure something out. Ergo, you can&#39;t begin with a statement.
Expressing ideas helps you form them. Writing something that others might read forces you to think well.
Writing also helps me code better. When I have a nasty bug, it&#39;s easy to try out so many ideas such that you lose track of what you&#39;ve learned.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>