<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Knowing on c13u&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/knowing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Knowing on c13u&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/knowing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Theory, Evolution &amp; Games) Separating Theory from Nonsense via Communication Norms, not Truth</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/knowing/2018-09-08-teg-separating-theory-from-nonsense/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/knowing/2018-09-08-teg-separating-theory-from-nonsense/</guid>
      <description>Separating Theory from Nonsense via Communication Norms, not Truth. Artem Kaznatcheev. Theory, Evolution &amp;amp; Games. https://egtheory.wordpress.com/2018/09/08/theory-norms/. 8th Sept, 2018.  Brian Skinner - how to distinguish good theory from crackpottery  Both theorists and crackpots share an irrational self-confidence A crackpot relies primarily on positive evidence  Thinks hard about a problem, arrives at a theory that feels right, and then publicizes the result.   A theorist incorporates negative evidence:  Ponders hard about a problem, arrives at a theory that feels right and then proceeds to try to disprove that theory Takes time to understand competing theories and compare them against her own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Syll) What is Ergodicity?</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/knowing/2016-11-23-syll-what-is-ergodicity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/knowing/2016-11-23-syll-what-is-ergodicity/</guid>
      <description>What is Ergodicity?. Lars P. Syll. https://larspsyll.wordpress.com/2016/11/23/what-is-ergodicity-2/. 23rd Nov, 2016.  A random process is ergodic if all of its statistics can be determined from a sample function of the process. That is, the ensemble averages equal the corresponding time averages with probability one.
Role of Ergodicity in Human Inference  A newspaper has previously printed some inaccurate information, therefore, the newspaper is going to publish inaccurate information in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>