<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fiction on Chege&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fiction on Chege&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Thor: God of Thunder</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/thor-god-of-thunder/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/thor-god-of-thunder/</guid>
      <description>Inspired to read this comic by the upcoming Thor: Love and Thunder   film.
  Motifs [Gorr] As I stand here now, witnessing with my own eyes the first awkward fumblings of life in the void, I see no weeping god. No tears except those shed by the misshapen creatures around me, minutes old and already begging for death. I see no grand plan at work. No benevolent omnipotence at display.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Swamp Thing</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/the-swamp-thing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/the-swamp-thing/</guid>
      <description>The Swamp Thing. Image from dccomics.com
  Motifs [Blind] Loyalty Their master gone, the un-men pause, uncertain of what to do&amp;hellip; They must among themselves for a moment &amp;ndash; and, at least, a decision is reached. For all their existence, they have followed their master blindly &amp;ndash; wherever he might lead&amp;hellip; And there seems no good reason to change that situation now. 
Ignorance Divinity, Maine &amp;ndash; founded circa 1648 &amp;ndash; population: 97 good, god-fearing people &amp;ndash; principal industry: scrambling for an existence &amp;ndash; principal produce: ignorance and fear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TV and Film</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/tv-and-film/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/tv-and-film/</guid>
      <description>Crime Drama Ozark&amp;rsquo;s highlights are Ruth Langmore&amp;rsquo;s 90s&#39; hip hop playlist, Wendy Byrde&amp;rsquo;s sociopathic ambition, and Del Rio&amp;rsquo;s suave. The show follows the Byrde family that has to launder money for the Navarro Cartel. The writers use shortcuts as the show proceeds, and grant excessive plot armor for the Byrde family in subsequent seasons. 
&amp;rsquo;s Bill Dubuque also wrote The Accountant (2016 Film)   , which follows a CPA with high-functioning autism who makes his living by uncooking the books of criminal organizations experiencing internal embezzlement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snow, Glass, Apples</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/gaiman-snow-glass-apples/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/gaiman-snow-glass-apples/</guid>
      <description>Snow, Glass, Apples Stumbled onto  from Hoopla&amp;rsquo;s recommendations.  flips the script and tells the story from the step mother&amp;rsquo;s perspective, and she is also the protagonist.
  Snow White is a vampire. She fed on her father (consensually?), the King, to the point of him being a shadow of a man. Her stepmother, the Queen, was only 18 when the King died. The Queen had witnessed Snow White&amp;rsquo;s vampirism, and so she had a servant kill her by carving out her heart and dump her in the forest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parable of the Sower</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/butler-parable-of-the-sower/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/butler-parable-of-the-sower/</guid>
      <description>Parable of the Sower. A Graphic Novel Adaptation (Original by Butler, 1993).  Damian Duffy; John Jennings; Octavia E. Butler. www.abramsbooks.com  . www.hoopladigital.com  . 2020. ISBN: 978-1-4197-3133-4 .     Parable of the Sower. Credits: www.abramsbooks.com
  Notable Plot Moments &amp;ldquo;A pessimist if I&amp;rsquo;m not careful.&amp;rdquo; She did not just reject pessimism once and become a Pollyanna thereafter. It was an impulse that she had to quell over and and over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Department of Truth</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/tynion-dept-of-truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/tynion-dept-of-truth/</guid>
      <description>The Department of Truth | Image Comics.  James Tynion IV; Martin Simmonds. imagecomics.com  .  Accessed Feb 18, 2022.    Department of Truth (2020 - present) by James Tynion IV. Image from imagecomics.com
  Expecting a modern take on 1984, which I didn&amp;rsquo;t finish because I lost interest.
  Plot Points [Lee Harvey Oswald] The more people believe in something, the more true that thing becomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saga</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/vaughan-saga/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/vaughan-saga/</guid>
      <description>Saga.  Brian Vaughan; Fiona Staples. imagecomics.com  . www.hoopladigital.com  . en.wikipedia.org  .     Saga (2012 - present) by Brian Vaughan. Image from imagecomics.com
  Volumes 1, 2, 3, 6, 7 and 9 have been nominated for the the Hugo Award for Best Graphic Story.  A 6/9 nomination rate implies that the comic is pretty good!
  Themes (Mostly War) Planet Landfall (Alana&amp;rsquo;s) and Wreath (its moon, Marko&amp;rsquo;s) have been in conflict as long as anyone can remember.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>As the Last I May Know</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/huang-as-the-last-i-may-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/huang-as-the-last-i-may-know/</guid>
      <description>As the Last I May Know.  Shi Lian Huang. www.tor.com  .  Accessed Dec 4, 2021.   won the &amp;ldquo;Best Short Story&amp;rdquo; Hugo Award in 2020. 
  Memorable Points Background: Sere missiles can wipe out a city completely. Nyma&amp;rsquo;s nation has been the only recipient of a seres strike. They&amp;rsquo;ve since acquired their own seres stockpile. They&amp;rsquo;re engaged in war with an state that lacks seres weapons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wicked &#43; The Divine</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/gillen-mckelvie-wicdiv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/gillen-mckelvie-wicdiv/</guid>
      <description>Volume 9 was nominated for the 2020 Hugo Award for Best Graphic Story or Comic. However, not very stoked after Book One (Vol 1 and 2). Maybe it gets better? Only Volume 9 has been nominated for a Hugo Award, so maybe check that next time before committing? 
    The Wicked + The Divine. Image credits: wicdiv.com
  ​​The Recurrence. Every 90 years, 12 gods reincarnate on earth for 2 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blood Is Another Word for Hunger</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/solomon-blood-is-another-word-for-hunger/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/solomon-blood-is-another-word-for-hunger/</guid>
      <description>Blood Is Another Word for Hunger.  Rivers Solomon. seattle.bibliocommons.com  . 2019.   Plot Points Sully slays slavers&#39; family after their patriarch dies in battle. She did not feel any remorse nor relief.
The etherworld thrived on the impermissible. A young and tender girl murdering a family, and maintaining her rage after the fact, was so impermissible that it cut a path between dominions.
The etherworld births a teenage Ziza (died 200 years prior) through Sully, and then later births four more revenants, for the five kills that she&amp;rsquo;d committed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LaGuardia</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/okorafor-laguardia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/okorafor-laguardia/</guid>
      <description>LaGuardia.  Nnedi Okorafor; Tana Ford; James Devlin. 2019.    LaGuardia (2019) by Nnedi Okorafor. Image from nnedi.com
  Winner of the 2020 Hugo Award for Best Graphic Novel, and the 2020 Eisner Award for Best Graphic Album - Reprint. 
  Aliens exist (first landed in Nigeria); human-alien in the world. Main character: Future, a Nigerian-American doctor. Future sneaks in LetMeLive, an alien, into America to escape a genocide (largely imperceptible to humans) on LetMeLive&amp;rsquo;s kind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stories of Your Life and Others</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/chiang-stories-of-your-life-and-others/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/chiang-stories-of-your-life-and-others/</guid>
      <description>Stories of Your Life and Others.  Ted Chiang. 2010. ISBN: 9781931520898 .   Tower of Babylon Story focused on Hillalum, who lived during the construction of the Tower of Babel .
 notes that the Hebrew school version was more elaborate than the Old Testament account, e.g. the tower is so tall that it takes a year to climb, and when a man falls to his death, no one mourns, but when a brick is dropped, the brick-layers weep because it will take a year to replace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lathe of Heaven</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/le-guin-lathe-of-heaven/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/le-guin-lathe-of-heaven/</guid>
      <description>Premise: Orr can have &amp;ldquo;effective&amp;rdquo; dreams that retroactively change reality for everyone else, except those who are aware of him dreaming. See  for a refresher on the plot.
Notable Plot Points Prodded by Haber to dream of the end of overpopulation, Orr dreamt of a plague that killed 6B people. But Orr tries to convince himself that the world that was was fiction in his head, so he didn&amp;rsquo;t really kill anyone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sandman</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/neil-gaiman-sandman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/neil-gaiman-sandman/</guid>
      <description>The Sandman (1989 - 1996) by Neil Gaiman. Image from dccomics.com
  Path to comic: Lucifer (Netflix) -&amp;gt; Lucifer (Comic) -&amp;gt; The Sandman (Comic)
Netflix is also adapting the comic, so interested in how it deviates from the source. Ser Brienne of Tarth will be Lucifer. Hype! 
  Love Dream: Sister &amp;ndash; you know how I felt for Nada one. What I feel for her still.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eternals</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/neil-gaiman-eternals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/neil-gaiman-eternals/</guid>
      <description>Eternals (2006) by Neil Gaiman. Image from marvel.com
  Mark Evanier: Can you prove that ancient civilizations weren&amp;rsquo;t visited by space travellers and heralded as gods? Did those aliens alight on this planet eons ago and plant the seeds of our civilization?
The lack of concrete answers for these questions makes Eternals a worthwhile hypothetical. Prometheus addresses a similar question with the concept of Engineers.
  Jack Kirby, 1976: I feel that playing around with this sort of conjecture is highly entertaining, and that we should aim our gunsights at this giant puzzle we&amp;rsquo;ve inherited more often.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
