<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fiction on Chege&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fiction on Chege&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Stories of Your Life and Others</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/chiang-stories-of-your-life-and-others/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/chiang-stories-of-your-life-and-others/</guid>
      <description>Stories of Your Life and Others.  Ted Chiang. 2010. ISBN: 9781931520898.   Tower of Babylon Story focused on Hillalum, who lived during the construction of the Tower of Babel .
 notes that the Hebrew school version was more elaborate than the Old Testament account, e.g. the tower is so tall that it takes a year to climb, and when a man falls to his death, no one mourns, but when a brick is dropped, the brick-layers weep because it will take a year to replace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lathe of Heaven</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/le-guin-lathe-of-heaven/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/le-guin-lathe-of-heaven/</guid>
      <description>Premise: Orr can have &amp;ldquo;effective&amp;rdquo; dreams that retroactively change reality for everyone else, except those who are aware of him dreaming. See  for a refresher on the plot.
Notable Plot Points Prodded by Haber to dream of the end of overpopulation, Orr dreamt of a plague that killed 6B people. But Orr tries to convince himself that the world that was was fiction in his head, so he didn&amp;rsquo;t really kill anyone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sandman</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/neil-gaiman-sandman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/neil-gaiman-sandman/</guid>
      <description>The Sandman (1989 - 1996) by Neil Gaiman. Image from dccomics.com
  Path to comic: Lucifer (Netflix) -&amp;gt; Lucifer (Comic) -&amp;gt; The Sandman (Comic)
Netflix is also adapting the comic, so interested in how it deviates from the source. Ser Brienne of Tarth will be Lucifer. Hype! 
  Love Dream: Sister &amp;ndash; you know how I felt for Nada one. What I feel for her still.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eternals</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/neil-gaiman-eternals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/neil-gaiman-eternals/</guid>
      <description>Eternals (2006) by Neil Gaiman. Image from marvel.com
  Mark Evanier: Can you prove that ancient civilizations weren&amp;rsquo;t visited by space travellers and heralded as gods? Did those aliens alight on this planet eons ago and plant the seeds of our civilization?
The lack of concrete answers for these questions makes Eternals a worthwhile hypothetical. Prometheus addresses a similar question with the concept of Engineers.
  Jack Kirby, 1976: I feel that playing around with this sort of conjecture is highly entertaining, and that we should aim our gunsights at this giant puzzle we&amp;rsquo;ve inherited more often.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
