<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>aosabook.org on Chege's Blog</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/domains/aosabook.org/</link><description>Recent content in aosabook.org on Chege's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.curiosities.dev/domains/aosabook.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>500 Lines or Less</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/todo/computer-science/500-lines-or-less/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/todo/computer-science/500-lines-or-less/</guid><description>The Architecture of Open Source Applications. 500 Lines or Less. aosabook.org . Accessed Jan 19, 2026. Blockcode: A Visual Programming Toolkit. A well-done block language eliminates syntax errors, visually displays available components, and allows localization.
A Continuous Integration System. A dedicated system used to test new code.
Clustering by Consensus. A network protocol designed to support reliable distributed computation.
Contingent: A Fully Dynamic Build System. The problem of dynamic cross-referencing, e.</description></item><item><title>Architecture of Open Source Applications, Vol. 1</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/todo/computer-science/aosa-vol-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/todo/computer-science/aosa-vol-1/</guid><description>The Architecture of Open Source Applications. Volume 1. aosabook.org . Accessed Jan 19, 2026. Asterisk. A server application for making, receiving, and performing custom processing of phone calls.
Audacity. A popular sound recorder and audio editor. One goal is that its user interface should be discoverable: people should be able to sit down without a manual and start using it right away.
The Bourne-Again Shell. Input processing, parsing, the various word expansions and other command processing, and command execution, from the pipeline perspective.</description></item><item><title>Architecture of Open Source Applications, Vol. 2</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/todo/computer-science/aosa-vol-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/todo/computer-science/aosa-vol-2/</guid><description>The Architecture of Open Source Applications. Volume 2. aosabook.org . Accessed Jan 19, 2026. Scalable Web Architecture and Distributed Systems. Key issues to consider when designing large websites, and some of the building blocks used to achieve these goals.
Firefox Release Engineering. Scripts and infrastructure decisions that comprise the complete Firefox rapid release system. Starting with builds and code signing, then customized partner and localization repacks, the QA process, and how we generate updates for every supported version, platform, and localization.</description></item><item><title>The Performance of Open Source Applications</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/todo/computer-science/perf-open-source-apps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/todo/computer-science/perf-open-source-apps/</guid><description>The Architecture of Open Source Applications. The Performance of Open Source Applications. aosabook.org . Accessed Jan 19, 2026. High Performance Networking in Chrome. Many of the sites we use today are not just web pages, they are applications. How do we make the fastest browser?
From SocialCalc to EtherCalc. EtherCalc is an online spreadsheet system optimized towards simultaneous editing, using SocialCalc as its in-browser spreadsheet engine.</description></item></channel></rss>