<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Software Engineering in Practice on Chege's Blog</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/swe-in-practice/</link><description>Recent content in Software Engineering in Practice on Chege's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/swe-in-practice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Playing Politics as a SWE</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/swe-in-practice/playing-swe-politics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/swe-in-practice/playing-swe-politics/</guid><description>Macro-Economics: Interest Rates and You In the 2010s, interest rates were near-zero; investors borrowed a lot of money and spent it on tech companies hoping for outsized returns. Companies desired to attract and retain talent; &amp;ldquo;literally anything&amp;rdquo; is worth spending money on to accumulate engineers.
In 2023, interest rates rose to ~5%. Tech companies now need to make money. If your work isn&amp;rsquo;t clearly connected to company profit, then your position is unstable and on the whims of an executive that personally values your work.</description></item><item><title>Thinking Like a Strong Engineer</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/swe-in-practice/thinking-like-a-strong-swe/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/swe-in-practice/thinking-like-a-strong-swe/</guid><description>Strong Engineers Strong engineers can do things that weaker engineers just can&amp;rsquo;t, even with all the time in the world. Some examples of capabilities:
Solving very difficult bugs, e.g., race conditions across multiple services. Delivering meaningful improvements to the thorniest parts of legacy codebases. Making changes that require a big architectural rework. At the top end of strongest engineers, capabilities become something like &amp;ldquo;improving the SOTA for LLMs&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>3 Maps: Locator, Topographical, and Treasure</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/swe-in-practice/swe-three-maps/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/swe-in-practice/swe-three-maps/</guid><description>These maps already exist but are obscured to you. Be alert to facts that affect your projects or organization. Continually sift information out of the noise around you, e.g., a shift in corporate priorities could mean a platform you&amp;rsquo;d considered but backburnered has become an amazing investment.
The Locator Map: Getting Perspective Time you spend absorbed in any domain increases your depth and understanding, but it comes with some risks, e.</description></item><item><title>Why Have We Stopped?</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/swe-in-practice/why-have-we-stopped/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/swe-in-practice/why-have-we-stopped/</guid><description>Stuck in Traffic Thinking through both sides of these scenarios can help me reduce the times when I (or my team) is the blocker.
Blocked By Another Team Understand and explain. Why is the work is important? What do you want from them and by when? Give them another chance to indicate feasibility and/or alternatives.
Make the work easier. Can you ask for a smaller subset of features?</description></item><item><title>Leading Big Projects</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/swe-in-practice/leading-big-projects/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/swe-in-practice/leading-big-projects/</guid><description>Create clarity for everyone such that they know what they need to do and how it fits into the bigger picture. Communicate openly. Give team members a stage to be publicly competent. Pick up the grunt work that others might not find enjoyable. Allocate time for support work, e.g., reviewing user feedback and error reports. Usually, the reason a project is difficult isn&amp;rsquo;t that you&amp;rsquo;re pushing the boundaries of technology, it&amp;rsquo;s that you&amp;rsquo;re dealing with ambiguity: unclear direction; messy, complicated humans; or legacy systems with behavior you can&amp;rsquo;t predict.</description></item><item><title>Finite Time as a SWE</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/swe-in-practice/finite-time-swe/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/swe-in-practice/finite-time-swe/</guid><description>Deliberately choose what to work on. Part of that is getting priority communicated by interested shareholders.
Empower less-experienced engineers so that they&amp;rsquo;re confident tackling different problems instead of me having to pick up said problems.
Improve my investigation and writing skills so that I can give folks enough context to execute on their own. Mostly communicating intent and trusting others to figure out the nitty gritty details.
Origins of Projects You&amp;rsquo;re invited to join.</description></item><item><title>Productivity for Software Engineers</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/swe-in-practice/2022-12-16-swe-productivity/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/swe-in-practice/2022-12-16-swe-productivity/</guid><description>Measuring Productivity Devs' Diverging Perceptions of Productivity Got interested in measuring it two years into my SWE career.
Initially rated myself based on % of completed daily objectives. The objectives didn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily correspond to work items. Stopped because the numbers were high even on days when I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel productive.
Switched to &amp;ldquo;stuff that affects others&amp;rdquo; (later came to know these are &amp;ldquo;function points&amp;rdquo;). More intuitively captures non-code objectives, e.g., aligning folks on feature specs.</description></item><item><title>Perspectives on Software Engineering</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/swe-in-practice/2022-06-06-perspectives-on-swe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/swe-in-practice/2022-06-06-perspectives-on-swe/</guid><description>On the Clean Code Movement Good enough is good enough. The architectural choices and bugs in the implementation tend to be more impactful, so focus more on those.
Be conservative in what you consider technical debt. It should be something that slows down current/future changes, and not code that doesn&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;feel nice&amp;rdquo;. A code base that is free if technical debt is likely over-emphasizing polish over delivery.
Abstractions and indirections in the name of future-proofing tend to be wrong especially when treading new paths, where you can&amp;rsquo;t reliably predict the future.</description></item></channel></rss>