<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Perspective on c13u&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.c13u.com/tags/perspective/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Perspective on c13u&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.c13u.com/tags/perspective/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Morgan Housel) Immeasurably Important</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/personal_growth/an_outlook_on_life/2018-07-01-housel-immeasurably-important/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/personal_growth/an_outlook_on_life/2018-07-01-housel-immeasurably-important/</guid>
      <description>Immeasurably Important.  Morgan Housel. Collaborative Fund. http://www.collaborativefund.com/blog/immeasurably-important/. Jul 5, 2018.  Filtering out information is an art, not a science, necessitated by the information overload that we live in.
 Watch out for the tendency to only preserve information that meshes with how we think the world should be. If you think the world is all art, you miss how much stuff is too complicated to think about intuitively.  If you think the world is all data, you&#39;ll miss how much is too complicated to summarize in a statistic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Psychology of Money [Morgan Housel]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/personal_growth/an_outlook_on_life/2018-06-01-housel-psychology-of-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/personal_growth/an_outlook_on_life/2018-06-01-housel-psychology-of-money/</guid>
      <description>The Psychology of Money.  Morgan Housel. The Collaborative Fund. http://www.collaborativefund.com/blog/the-psychology-of-money/. Jun 1, 2018.  People underestimate the role played by luck. Given \(N\) investors, if \(N\) is large enough, a couple of them will luck their way into billions.
But every investor seems to be doing due diligence. The successful ones will be more convinced that their methods really work.
Considering the amount of investing books out there, we should be seeing a lot more Warren Buffets in the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Paul Graham) Life is Short</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/personal_growth/an_outlook_on_life/2016-01-01-pg-bullshit-minimizing-path/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/personal_growth/an_outlook_on_life/2016-01-01-pg-bullshit-minimizing-path/</guid>
      <description>Life is Short.  Paul Graham. http://www.paulgraham.com/vb.html. Jan 1, 2016.  Some of it is our own fault (e.g. arguing online). Some of it is forced by circumstances that we choose to endure (e.g. unnecessary meetings at work)
Choosing a bullshit minimizing path is error-prone. Your priorities change over time. Periodically evaluate where you are. It helps to have measurable aspects of your life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (SSC) The Parable of the Talents</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/personal_growth/an_outlook_on_life/2015-01-31-ssc-the-principle-of-the-talents/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/personal_growth/an_outlook_on_life/2015-01-31-ssc-the-principle-of-the-talents/</guid>
      <description>The Parable of the Talents.  Scott Alexander. Slate Star Codex. https://slatestarcodex.com/2015/01/31/the-parable-of-the-talents/. Jan 31, 2015.  Overweight people, depressed people, and poor people aren’t fully to blame for their situation – and neither are unintelligent people. It’s accidents of birth all the way down.
Srinivasa Ramanujan:
 Grew up in poverty in a one-room house in small-town India. But a lot of poor people in the US had better conditions/opportunities  Either, a lot of intelligence is innate Or, those poor people are just not trying hard enough.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>