<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>www.reddit.com on Chege's Blog</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/domains/www.reddit.com/</link><description>Recent content in www.reddit.com on Chege's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.curiosities.dev/domains/www.reddit.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Given Language Models, Why Learn About Large Language Models?</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/large-language-models/why-learn-about-llms/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/large-language-models/why-learn-about-llms/</guid><description>This part of seems pertinent to respond to &amp;ldquo;LLMs are just (auto-complete; Markov chains; [insert pre-existing LM-adjacent tech]) on steroids&amp;rdquo;.
Scale LLMs are massive. From 2018 - 2022, model sizes have increased 5000x. OpenAI&amp;rsquo;s GPT model from June 2018 had 110M parameters; GPT-3 from May 2020 had 175B parameters. LLM providers no longer seem to advertise their parameter counts; GPT-4 was leaked to have 1.8T parameters.</description></item><item><title>Learning Haskell via AoC 2021</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/programming-challenges/advent-of-code/2021/haskell-meta/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/programming-challenges/advent-of-code/2021/haskell-meta/</guid><description>This page contains remarks on Haskell that I encountered when working with source files that span multiple AoC 2021 problems.
and have Haskell solutions. It&amp;rsquo;ll be nice to compare how they solved the problems. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to end up perfecting the wrong approach!
Setting Up Haskell Env for AoC To manage dependencies, Cabal and Stack are pretty popular. Stack incorporates the Cabal build system.</description></item><item><title>AoC 2021 Day 03: Binary Diagnostic</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/programming-challenges/advent-of-code/2021/src/BinaryDiagnostic/03-binary-diagnostic/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/programming-challenges/advent-of-code/2021/src/BinaryDiagnostic/03-binary-diagnostic/</guid><description>Day 3 - Advent of Code 2021. Eric Wastl. adventofcode.com . Accessed Feb 23, 2022. Problem Description Part One The submarine has been making some odd creaking noises, so you ask it to produce a diagnostic report just in case.
The diagnostic report (your puzzle input) consists of a list of binary numbers which, when decoded properly, can tell you many useful things about the conditions of the submarine.</description></item><item><title>NBA 2K25: MyNBA</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/sports/nba2k-mynba/nba2k25-mynba/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/sports/nba2k-mynba/nba2k25-mynba/</guid><description>MyNBA is my favorite playing mode in NBA 2K. Starting out as the GM of the Seattle Supersonics in 1983, how well can I steer the franchise?
Playing all 82 games per season would need \(82 \text{ games/season} \times 41 \text{ seasons} \times 20 \text{ min/game} \approx 47 \text{ days}\) to catch up to today&amp;rsquo;s NBA and that&amp;rsquo;s not accounting for the playoffs. Simulating games is the way to go; might help improve my understanding of the game.</description></item><item><title>Of Builds and Bundlers</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/programming-challenges/flashcards-app/of-builds-and-bundlers/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/programming-challenges/flashcards-app/of-builds-and-bundlers/</guid><description>Moving to TypeScript entails configuring how the JavaScript will be eventually consumed by both the server and the client.
Separating the Client Bundle from the Server Bundle The server code runs in Node while the client code runs in the browser. advises separating the configurations for advantages like faster type-checking and compiling, lower memory usage when using an editor, and improved enforcement of the logical groupings of your program.</description></item><item><title>We The Consumers</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/2021-12-21-we-the-consumers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/2021-12-21-we-the-consumers/</guid><description>Product Differentiation and Price Discrimination Product differentiation seeks to distinguish a product from a competing product to make it more attractive to a specific target market. Price discrimination occurs when the same goods/services are sold at different prices from the same company.
The Captain Samuel Vimes &amp;ldquo;Boots&amp;rdquo; theory of socio-economic unfairness: the rich man who bought the high quality $50 pair of boots would still be using them in 10 years, while the poor man who buys the $10 pair would have spent $100 on boots in the same time, and still be worse off.</description></item><item><title>Investing in Kenya</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/investing-in-kenya/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/investing-in-kenya/</guid><description>Areas to Consider Capital Markets The Central Depository and Settlement Corporation (CDSC) runs the Central Depository System (CDS) that facilitates holding and trading of shares at the Nairobi Stock Exchange (NSE). A Central Depository Agent (CDA) is a Stockbroker, an Investment Bank, or a Custodian Bank, who has been authorized by the CDSC to open accounts in CDS on behalf of investors.
In 2006, an Automatic Trading System was introduced so that orders are matched automatically and executed by stockbrokers on a first-come first-served basis.</description></item></channel></rss>