<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Socio-Economics on c13u&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.c13u.com/socioeconomics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Socio-Economics on c13u&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.c13u.com/socioeconomics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>On Socioeconomic Classes</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/socioeconomics/2020-07-04-socioeconomic-classes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/socioeconomics/2020-07-04-socioeconomic-classes/</guid>
      <description>On the Phenomenon of Bullshit Jobs [] Capitalism is meant to eliminate bullshit jobs, yet layoffs tend to fall on people making, moving, fixing and maintaining things, but not on the salaried paper pushers that effectively work 15 hours a week.
​From a political standpoint, a happy productive population with free time on their hands is mortal to the ruling class. Moreover, work is considered a moral value in itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philanthropy</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/socioeconomics/2020-04-26-on-philanthropy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/socioeconomics/2020-04-26-on-philanthropy/</guid>
      <description>Criticism/Defense Of Billionaire Philanthropy [] Taxes will probably not go to the same causes, e.g. reforming the bail system, grassroot efforts for migrants, etc.
Foundations are more effective than governments as they do their due diligence, e.g. Bill Gates. Reforming the government is a long battle.
Jack Dorsey (Twitter), set up $1B of his Square stock (28% of net worth) in an LLC to fund efforts for Covid-19, Girl&amp;rsquo;s Health and Education, and Universal Basic Income.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Third Base [Scott Galloway]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/socioeconomics/2019-12-13-galloway-third-base/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/socioeconomics/2019-12-13-galloway-third-base/</guid>
      <description>Third Base [] Not recognizing your blessings feeds into the dark side of capitalism and meritocracy: success is a choice, and that those who haven’t achieved success are not unlucky, but unworthy.
I&amp;rsquo;m relatively lucky. I don&amp;rsquo;t know how much of the techie hubris that I bear. I have unresolved feelings about meritocracy and fairness. Race is usually used as a proxy for bridging the gap, e.g. affirmative action at colleges.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>