<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Socio-Economics on Chege's Blog</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/socioeconomics/</link><description>Recent content in Socio-Economics on Chege's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.curiosities.dev/socioeconomics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>On Societal Oppressions</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/socioeconomics/2022-09-18-societal-oppressions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/socioeconomics/2022-09-18-societal-oppressions/</guid><description>Looking for parallels should be done cautiously. For example, the advantaging associated with race may be different from the one associated with heterosexism. It&amp;rsquo;s also hard to disentangle [dis]advantaging where social class, economic class, race, religion, sexuality, ethnic identity, and other factors interact.
Isn&amp;rsquo;t this the crux of intersectionality studies?
Intersectionality identifies multiple factors of advantage and disadvantage. Factors include gender, caste, sex, race, ethnicity, class, sexuality, religion, disability, weight, and physical appearance.</description></item><item><title>Experiments/Theories in Socioeconomics</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/socioeconomics/2020-11-21-experiments-in-social-economics/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/socioeconomics/2020-11-21-experiments-in-social-economics/</guid><description>Programmable Money South Korea&amp;rsquo;s COVID-19 stimulus payments were programmed to expire in Aug 2020, and could only be spent at qualifying shops. Australia&amp;rsquo;s cashless welfare card [currently in pilot stages] cannot be withdrawn as cash, nor used at alcohol, tobacco and gambling joints.
Monzo, a UK-based digital-first mobile baking app, supports IFTTT recipes. This enables budgeting logic, &amp;ldquo;If I spend at KFC, then move $5 to my penalty pot&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>On Socio-Economic Classes</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/socioeconomics/2020-07-04-socioeconomic-classes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/socioeconomics/2020-07-04-socioeconomic-classes/</guid><description>On the Phenomenon of Bullshit Jobs Capitalism is meant to eliminate bullshit jobs, yet layoffs tend to fall on people making, moving, fixing and maintaining things, but not on the salaried paper pushers that effectively work 15 hours a week.
​From a political standpoint, a happy productive population with free time on their hands is mortal to the ruling class. Moreover, work is considered a moral value in itself.</description></item><item><title>Philanthropy</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/socioeconomics/2020-04-26-on-philanthropy/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/socioeconomics/2020-04-26-on-philanthropy/</guid><description>Criticism/Defense Of Billionaire Philanthropy Taxes will probably not go to the same causes, e.g. reforming the bail system, grassroot efforts for migrants, etc.
Admittedly, these are things that the government should be doing, but it seems that the government doesn&amp;rsquo;t do enough. Furthermore, some of these issues so politicized, e.g. immigrants, that government support can be fickle.
Foundations are more effective than governments as they do their due diligence, e.</description></item></channel></rss>