<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on c13u&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.c13u.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on c13u&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.c13u.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>00. Prologue</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/00-prologue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/00-prologue/</guid>
      <description>Holmes had an all-star team: Larry Ellison&#39;s mentor as Chair, Associate Dean of Stanford&#39;s School of Engineering, 30 years IBM experience, 25 years pharma and biotech experience, Panasonic&#39;s chip-making subsidiary head&amp;hellip;
Fraud or not, this is a sick lineup! How could she mess this up?
  Big Pharma spends tens of $B on clinical trials each year. Theranos would enable them to adjust dosage and save 30%. Holmes insisted on revising financial projections upward - assuming all (15+) deals came through - to $1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dependencies and Maintainers [Drew DeVault]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/software-engineering/2020-02-06-deps-and-maintainers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/software-engineering/2020-02-06-deps-and-maintainers/</guid>
      <description>Dependencies and Maintainers. Drew DeVault. https://drewdevault.com/2020/02/06/Dependencies-and-maintainers.html. 2020-02-06.  Sample Crises in OSS left-pad: trivial library that was removed from npm and was unknowingly present in thousands of dependency graphs.
event-stream: maintainer transferred ownership to an unknown individual who added crypto mining
heartbleed, in which a bug in a critical security library caused mass upgrades and panic
DeVault&#39;s Take Asking how to prioritize attention, donations &amp;amp; patches for thousands of OSS library dependencies shouldn&#39;t be a problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>01. Firm Foundations and Castles in the Air</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/malkiel-a-random-walk-down-wall-street/part-1-stocks-and-their-value/malkiel-01-firm-foundations-and-castle-in-the-air/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/malkiel-a-random-walk-down-wall-street/part-1-stocks-and-their-value/malkiel-01-firm-foundations-and-castle-in-the-air/</guid>
      <description>Random walk: future steps or directions cannot be predicted on the basis of past history. Thus, short-run changes in stock prices are unpredictable.
Investing as a Way of Life Today Difference between speculations and investments: time period and predictability of the return.
To stay even, your returns must match inflation (averaged 4% from 1962 to 2018).
With regard to beating inflation, that implies all the money that&#39;s in people&#39;s bank accounts is depreciating, as opposed to maintaining value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>01. A Purposeful Life</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/01-a-purposeful-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/01-a-purposeful-life/</guid>
      <description>Holmes wanted to be a billionaire since childhood. Her parents were from wealth, with medical and military folk. Holmes attended Houston&#39;s most prestigious private school. She spoke her way into Stanford&#39;s Mandarin program, while still in high school. Parents insisted on living a purposeful life.
Worked in lab during school year. Freshman internship at Genome Institute of Singapore: nasal swabs and syringes. There had to be a better way.
Ah, the transformative experience abroad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>01. The Tar Pit</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/software-engineering/mythical-man-month/brooks-01-the-tar-pit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 1974 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/software-engineering/mythical-man-month/brooks-01-the-tar-pit/</guid>
      <description>The fiercer the struggle, the more entangling the tar, and no beast is so strong or so skillful but that he ultimately sinks.
The Programming Systems Product How do 2 programmers in a remodeled garage build an important program that surpasses the best efforts of large teams?
A Program Garage duos typically build a program: complete in itself, ready to be run by the author on the system on which it was developed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02. The Madness of the Crowds</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/malkiel-a-random-walk-down-wall-street/part-1-stocks-and-their-value/malkiel-02-the-madness-of-the-crowds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/malkiel-a-random-walk-down-wall-street/part-1-stocks-and-their-value/malkiel-02-the-madness-of-the-crowds/</guid>
      <description>The Tulip Bulb Craze Virus causes colored stripes in tulip petals. The Dutch valued such bulbs. Prices rose (just when one thought they couldn&#39;t go higher). Let the tulipmania begin.
Note: And that&#39;s where FOMO comes in. You can&#39;t argue with the results. You just want to dip your toes and get out. I watched Bitcoin keep climbing, until I got into the game with $50&amp;hellip;
  Tulip bulbs options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02. The Gluebot</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/02-the-gluebot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/02-the-gluebot/</guid>
      <description>Holmes insisted on using just a prick of blood. Problem: unreproducible results. A miniaturized catridge made storing and using the reagents hard.
You can&#39;t Steve Jobs your way through medical devices. But you can&#39;t change the world by being cynical.
  Costs. Each cartridge cost +$200 to make and was single use. Holmes even purchased a $2m automated packaging line.
Control of Information. The biochemists and the engineers reported up to Holmes and weren&#39;t encouraged to communicate with each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02. The Mythical Man-Month</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/software-engineering/mythical-man-month/brooks-02-the-mythical-man-month/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 1974 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/software-engineering/mythical-man-month/brooks-02-the-mythical-man-month/</guid>
      <description>More software projects have gone awry for lack of calendar time than for all other causes combined.
Why is this cause of disaster so common?  Our estimation techniques assume that all will go well, i.e. each task will take only as long as it &amp;ldquo;ought&amp;rdquo; to take. Our estimating techniques fallaciously confuse effort with progress, hiding the assumption that men and months are interchangeable. Because we are uncertain of our estimates, software managers often lack the courteous stubbornness - if you&#39;re made to wait, it is to serve you better, and to please you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03. Speculative Bubbles from the Sixties into the Nineties</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/malkiel-a-random-walk-down-wall-street/part-1-stocks-and-their-value/malkiel-03-speculative-bubbles-from-the-60s-into-the-90s/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/malkiel-a-random-walk-down-wall-street/part-1-stocks-and-their-value/malkiel-03-speculative-bubbles-from-the-60s-into-the-90s/</guid>
      <description>The Sanity of Institutions Growth, Tronics and Synergy Growth companies such as IBM and Texas Instruments sold at price-earnings multiples of more than 80. Questioning the propriety of such valuations became almost heretical.
Companies plastered &amp;ldquo;tronics&amp;rdquo; in their name. The tronics boom came back to earth in 1962.
Synergy Generates Energy: The Conglomerate Boom  Baker Co. &amp;amp; Electronik Co. have 200k shares outstandings, and $5 earnings per share per year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03. Apple Envy</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/03-apple-envy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/03-apple-envy/</guid>
      <description>Holmes&#39;s Grand Plans. The iPod of health care. Build a personal disease map; reverse engineer cancer and predict evolution of tumors.
Again, if she&#39;s faking this belief, then its sociopathic. But maybe she thought she could do it. Inventors go where no one else dares. They&#39;re ridiculed by society. Here&#39;s to the crazy ones. The misfits. The rebels. The troublemakers.
  Chat ports were blocked to protect proprietary information and trade secrets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04. The Explosive Bubbles of the Early 2000s</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/malkiel-a-random-walk-down-wall-street/part-1-stocks-and-their-value/malkiel-04-the-explosive-bubbles-of-the-early-2000s/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/malkiel-a-random-walk-down-wall-street/part-1-stocks-and-their-value/malkiel-04-the-explosive-bubbles-of-the-early-2000s/</guid>
      <description>Dotcom crash took away $8tn (yearly output of Germany, France, England, Italy, Spain, the Netherlands, and Russia) of market value.
The Internet Bubble The internet had 2 bubble qualities: some new technology &amp;amp; some new business opportunity.
A Broad-Scale High-Tech Bubble Cisco and JDS Uniphase, producers of the backbone of the Internet, sold at +100 P/E.
As usual, companies changed their names to include &amp;ldquo;dot.com&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;dotnet&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;Internet&amp;rdquo;.
   Stock High &amp;lsquo;00 Low &amp;lsquo;01–&amp;lsquo;02 Decline     Amazon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agriculture in Kenya as a Portfolio Problem</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/investing-in-kenya/2020-02-08-agriculture-in-kenya-as-a-portfolio-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/investing-in-kenya/2020-02-08-agriculture-in-kenya-as-a-portfolio-problem/</guid>
      <description>Motivation In 08. A New Walking Shoe: Modern Portfolio Theory, Malkiel introduced me to Modern Portfolio Theory, a technique for reducing portfolio risk, despite risky investments. It made me wonder how similar principles are applied in agriculture. This page is the result of that investigation.
~16% of Kenya&#39;s land is sufficiently fertile and has good rainfall. In 2006, ~75% of working Kenyans are farmers (compared to 80% in 1980). (en.wikipedia.org)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04. Goodbye East Paly</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/04-goodbye-east-paly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/04-goodbye-east-paly/</guid>
      <description>For some terminated employees, Holmes requested a dossier on them for leverage. Mosley (finance guy) had stored porn on his work laptop. Holmes (retroactively) used that as the cause for his termination and lack of stock options.
Matt (IT) wanted to leave to start IT consulting firm. Holmes asking him to use ununionized (mob controlled) movers for a last minute move from East Paly was one of the final straws. Holmes tried asking Matt&#39;s peer to build dossier in exchange for Matt&#39;s position, but they declined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05. Technical and Fundamental Analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/malkiel-a-random-walk-down-wall-street/part-2-how-the-pros-play-the-biggest-game-in-town/malkiel-05-technical-and-fundamental-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/malkiel-a-random-walk-down-wall-street/part-2-how-the-pros-play-the-biggest-game-in-town/malkiel-05-technical-and-fundamental-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Fundamental analysis applies the firm-foundation theory to the selection of individual stocks.
Technical Analysis Study past price movements and trading volume of trading to to predict when to buy/sell a stock. Based on the castle-in-the-air view of stock pricing.
What Can Charts Tell You? Principles of Technical Analysis   All information about earnings, dividends, and the future performance of a company is automatically reflected in the company’s past market prices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05. The Childhood Neighbor</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/05-the-childhood-neighbor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/05-the-childhood-neighbor/</guid>
      <description>Money was a sore point in the Holme&#39;s household. Holmes&#39;s grandparents had squandered away their share of the Fleischmann fortune. Richard Fuisz, a family friend, was a flashy successful businessman.
So in a way, Elizabeth didn&#39;t grow up in wealth? This puts a spin on Chapter 01: A Purposeful Life.
  Fuisz was offended that Elizabeth never consulted him. Fuisz made his money patenting medical inventions that he anticipated other companies would someday want.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06. Technical Analysis and the Random Walk Theory</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/malkiel-a-random-walk-down-wall-street/part-2-how-the-pros-play-the-biggest-game-in-town/malkiel-06-technical-analysis-and-the-random-walk-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/malkiel-a-random-walk-down-wall-street/part-2-how-the-pros-play-the-biggest-game-in-town/malkiel-06-technical-analysis-and-the-random-walk-theory/</guid>
      <description>Is There Momentum in the Stock Market? Past stock prices cannot be used reliably to foretell future movements. Furthermore, transactions costs and taxes make it hard to exploit any short-term momentum.
Flip a fair coin many times. Sequences of heads (or tails) and jumbled up sequences occur with equal probability.
Just What Exactly is a Random Walk? In a random walk, knowing all prior moves is no help in predicting the next move.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06. Sunny</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/06-sunny/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/06-sunny/</guid>
      <description>Elizabeth met Sunny in Stanford&#39;s Mandarin program. She was 18, he was 19 years older and married. Elizabeth had struggled and gotten bullied and Sunny helped her out.
Sunny was arrogant and demeaning to employees. Sunny was a sucker for #hours clocked in. 8 hours a day showed a lack of dedication. But Elizabeth had utmost confidence in him.
That Sunny (COO) and Elizabeth (CEO) were dating wasn&#39;t disclosed to the board.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>07. How Good is Fundamental Analysis? The Efficient Market Hypothesis</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/malkiel-a-random-walk-down-wall-street/part-2-how-the-pros-play-the-biggest-game-in-town/malkiel-07-how-good-is-fundamental-analysis-the-emh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/malkiel-a-random-walk-down-wall-street/part-2-how-the-pros-play-the-biggest-game-in-town/malkiel-07-how-good-is-fundamental-analysis-the-emh/</guid>
      <description>Fundamentalists tout past earnings growth as a most reliable indicator of future growth. But academics have shown that past earnings growth are no help in predicting future growth.
Why is the Crystal Ball So Clouded?  Many of the influential changes that affect earnings prospects are unpredictable. Creative accounting procedures produce dubious reported earnings, e.g. pro forma earnings, pushing due payments to future years, etc. Analysts may make errors, e.g. over-estimating the market size.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>07. Dr. J</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/07-dr-j/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/07-dr-j/</guid>
      <description>FB&#39;s private valuation had doubled to $50b in 6 months. &amp;lsquo;Angry Birds&amp;rsquo; showed an app could be a business. Low interest rates made hedge funds consider private startups.
Walgreens Dr. J - Walgreens Innovation. Theranos tests could boost revenues. Walgreens agrees to prepurchase $50m of cartridges and loan Theranos $25m.
Walgreens: we can&#39;t risk a scenario where CVS has a deal with them in 6 months and it ends up being real.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>08. A New Walking Shoe: Modern Portfolio Theory</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/malkiel-a-random-walk-down-wall-street/part-3-the-new-investment-technology/malkiel-08-modern-portfolio-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/malkiel-a-random-walk-down-wall-street/part-3-the-new-investment-technology/malkiel-08-modern-portfolio-theory/</guid>
      <description>Many academics agree that to beat the market, one needs to assume greater risk - as opposed to trying to predict the market.
Defining Risk: The Dispersion of Returns    Business Conditions Possibility of Occurrence Expected Return (R)     &amp;ldquo;Normal&amp;rdquo; economic conditions \(\frac{1}{3}\) 10%   Rapid real growth without inflation \(\frac{1}{3}\) 30%   Recession with inflation (stagflation) \(\frac{1}{3}\) –10%    $$ \mathbb{E}[R] = \frac{1}{3}(.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>08. The miniLab</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/08-minilab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/08-minilab/</guid>
      <description>The miniLab, 4S for short, stemmed from the need for a device that could perform more than just one class of tests. Theranos value prop was now minituarization, as opposed to invention. Current blood analyzers used too much blood and did too few tests.
Kent, de-facto Chief Architect of the miniLab, had raised $215k on Kickstarter for his bike lights side project. Elizabeth and Sunny wanted the patent to be transferred to Theranos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>09. Reaping Reward By Increasing Risk</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/malkiel-a-random-walk-down-wall-street/part-3-the-new-investment-technology/malkiel-09-reaping-reward-by-increasing-risk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/malkiel-a-random-walk-down-wall-street/part-3-the-new-investment-technology/malkiel-09-reaping-reward-by-increasing-risk/</guid>
      <description>The mystical perfect risk measure is still beyond our grasp. That said, here are some common ones:
Beta and Systematic Risk Systematic risk of a security arises from the variability of the general stock market. Diversification does not reduce this risk.
Unsystematic risk is the remaining variability that is due to a company&#39;s particular factors, e.g. a strike. Diversification reduces this risk. There is no reason for extra compensation.
Beta is a measure of the systematic risk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>09. The Wellness Play</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/09-the-wellness-play/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/09-the-wellness-play/</guid>
      <description>Safeway was doing poorly. Burd teased with a &amp;lsquo;wellness play&amp;rsquo;. He expected the clinics&amp;rsquo; to recoup the $350m renovation costs. Testing and rewarding employees would reduce Safeway&#39;s health care costs.
Theranos would courier samples to Palo Alto for testing. Theranos used a lancet on the index finger AND the good old hypodermic needle to the arm. The results could take 2 weeks as opposed to near-instantaneous. Theranos&#39;s results tended to be way off, unless they had been outsourced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10. Behavioral Finance</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/malkiel-a-random-walk-down-wall-street/part-3-the-new-investment-technology/malkiel-10-behavioral-finance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/malkiel-a-random-walk-down-wall-street/part-3-the-new-investment-technology/malkiel-10-behavioral-finance/</guid>
      <description>Behavioralists believe that investors are not rational in present and future valuations of securities.
Furthermore, there are substantial barriers to efficient arbitrage (selling overpriced securities short and buying underpriced ones).
The Irrational Behavior of Individual Investors Overconfidence Example: in a survey, 94% of male respondents believed that their athleticism was above average.
Hindsight bias makes the world seem predictable. Investors might think they can beat the market.
The tendency of &amp;ldquo;growth&amp;rdquo; stocks to underperform &amp;ldquo;value&amp;rdquo; stocks shows how overoptimistic growth forecasts are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10. Who Is LTC Shoemaker?</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/10-who-is-ltc-shoemaker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/10-who-is-ltc-shoemaker/</guid>
      <description>Elizabeth had successfully pitched to James Mattis, 4-star General, about deploying Theranos in Afghanistan. General Mattis was known to look out for his troops.
Elizabeth&#39;s plan around regulation - the real blood analysis would be beamed to California to be done by professionals; only the CLIA compliance for the Palo Alto lab was needed - no FDA.
Lt. Col. Shoemaker, responsible for the army&#39;s compliance with medical regulations, was openly critical of the Theranos&amp;rsquo; workaround.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11. New Methods of Portfolio Construction: Smart Beta and Risk Parity</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/malkiel-a-random-walk-down-wall-street/part-3-the-new-investment-technology/malkiel-11-smart-beta-and-risk-parity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/malkiel-a-random-walk-down-wall-street/part-3-the-new-investment-technology/malkiel-11-smart-beta-and-risk-parity/</guid>
      <description>Smart Beta Using relatively passive-rule based strategies to gain greater than market returns without assuming more risk than investing in a low-cost total stock market index fund.
The Sharpe Ratio: (excess return over the risk-free rate) / (risk of the strategy). The risk-free rate is usually the return from a 3-month treasury bill. Higher Sharpe Ratios are better.
Smart beta argues that pure indexing (weighting by market cap) is not optimal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11. Lighting a Fuisz</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/11-lighting-a-fuisz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/11-lighting-a-fuisz/</guid>
      <description>Elizabeth sued Richard Fuisz claiming he used Joe &amp;amp; John Fuisz to steal confidential information at McDermott Will &amp;amp; Emery, in order to build the rival patent. Note that John thought his father, Richard, was overbearing.
David Boies was legendary: antitrust against MSFT, Al Gore on contested 2000 election, overturning ban on gay marriage in CA. He also intimidated opponents with private investigators.
There was paranoia that Quest Diagnostics and Laboratory Corporation of America were thirsty for Theranos&#39;s blood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12. Ian Gibbons</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/12-ian-gibbons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/12-ian-gibbons/</guid>
      <description>Ian&#39;s specialty was immunoassays. His contentions: the devices fell short of the lab bench&#39;s accuracy; there was little communication between groups; Elizabeth&#39;s dishonesty about Theranos&amp;rsquo; capbilities.
Ian confided in Channing Robertson, who parroted to Elizabeth, who fired Ian.
But his colleagues lobbied him back in. He was in a demoted position though. Paul, previous mentee turned manager, was more compromising with the engineers.
Ian was dismayed that Elizabeth&#39;s name was usually in 1st place on patents despite negligible scientific contribution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13. Chiat\Day</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/13-chiat-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/13-chiat-day/</guid>
      <description>Chiat\Day was the agency that Apple had used. Therefore, Theranos would too.
Patrick (Chiat\Day) was enamored by Elizabeth&#39;s mission. The website models featured all demographics. Elizabeth scheduled Wednesday meetings because that&#39;s how Apple did it.
Stan Fiorito (Chiat\Day) was more circumspect. Sunny&#39;s sales targets had measly research. How were they affording $6m/year retainer?
Elizabeth claimed Theranos was saving soldiers&amp;rsquo; lives in Afghanistan. She wanted bold claims:
 800 tests on a drop of blood More accurate than traditional lab testing Tests ready in &amp;lt; 30min Tests approved by the FDA and endorsed by key medical centers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>14. Going Live</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/14-going-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/14-going-live/</guid>
      <description>Theranos&#39;s Lab was divided into two. The upstairs one, CLIA-certified, was full of commercial diagnostic equipment. The downstairs one had Theranos&#39;s tech.
2.5 years of the miniLab&#39;s development. But it was still a work in progress. In medical device standards, 3 years is a short time.
Sycophants were promoted. Many employees were on H1-B, so they needed Theranos&#39;s employment.
After LTC Shoemaker, Elizabeth scrapped the remote diagnostics. The samples were to be couriered to Palo Alto.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>15. Unicorn</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/15-unicorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/15-unicorn/</guid>
      <description>Elizabeth used Shultz&#39;s connections to get a WSJ Weekend Interview to coincide with the launch. The interview was a friendly setting, with a pro-business &amp;amp; anti-regulation ethos.
Theranos was about to launch. Its devices were being used by the military too. Elizabeth offered Don Lucas a discount investment opportunity - $15m at a $6b valuation; 7 years ago, Theranos was valued at $40m.
Uber had raised $361m at $3.5b. Spotify raised $250m at $4b.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>16. The Grandson</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/16-the-grandson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/16-the-grandson/</guid>
      <description>The Edison&#39;s innards were mostly a pipette fastened to a robotic arm. But it had a [buggy] touchscreen interface, so&amp;hellip;
A test is considered precise if its coefficient of variation (CV) is below 10%. Data runs that failed to meet the threshold were discarded. Of six values, Theranos only reported the median to the patient.
Theranos also argued that proficiency testing results were assessed by comparing them to its peers&amp;rsquo; results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>17. Fame</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/17-the-fame/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/17-the-fame/</guid>
      <description>Richard and Joe Fuisz were tired and battered. They had already spent $2m+ on their defense. What if they lost and were made to cover Theranos&#39;s legal expenses?
Richard agreed to withdraw patent in exchange for Theranos withdrawing its suit. The Fuiszes had lost. But Joe demanded a public apology from Theranos.
Roger Parloff, Fortune Magazine&#39;s legal correspondent saw the settlement in Litigation Daily. After speaking to Shultz, Perry, Kissinger, Nunn, Mattis and the 2 new directors: Kovacevich (former Wells Fargo CEO) and Frist (former Senate majority leader), came the June 2014 cover story that catapulted Elizabeth to fame: This CEO Is Out for Blood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>18. The Hippocratic Oath</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/18-the-hippocratic-oath/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/18-the-hippocratic-oath/</guid>
      <description>Alan talked Elizabeth and Sunny out of running HIV tests on diluted finger-stick samples - unreliable potassium and cholesterol results were bad enough.
Alan was tired of convincing physicians that blood test results were sound and accurate. He chose to resign and asked his name be taken off the lab&#39;s CLIA license. Alan got served with an affidavit.
How could Alan go against the most fabled SV unicorn? The litigation would bankrupt him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>19. The Tip</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/19-the-tip/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/19-the-tip/</guid>
      <description>Alan retrieved the proficiency testing email chain through a whistleblower law firm. He forwarded the thread to Carreyrou. The thread showed Sunny admonishing Alan &amp;amp; Mark for running proficiency tests on the Edison and admitting that the device had &amp;ldquo;failed&amp;rdquo; the test. Elizabeth was copied on most of the emails.
Carreyrou tracked Carmen Washington, who had complained about Theranos&#39;s blood tests in Walgreens. 3 of her patients had received questionable test results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20. The Ambush</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/20-the-ambush/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/20-the-ambush/</guid>
      <description>Charlotte: I doubt if Theranos&#39;s &amp;lsquo;box&amp;rsquo; is real. Henry [Kissinger] doubts too and he&#39;s been saying he wants out.
Tyler got served with an affidavit stating that he&#39;d never spoken to any third parties about Theranos and that he&#39;d give names of [ex]employees who he knew had talked to WSJ.
George: Tyler isn&#39;t a snitch. Finding out who spoke to WSJ is Theranos&#39;s problem.
Tyler declined to name WSJ&#39;s other sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>21. Trade Secrets</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/21-trade-secrets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/21-trade-secrets/</guid>
      <description>David Boies led the pack.
Tyler is a young and unqualified. Many of your sources are disgruntled ex-employees who are equally unreliable. We do not consent to your publication of our trade secrets. [Well, we do not consent to waiving our journalistic privileges].
Delegation acknowledged ownership of commercial blood analyzers, but for comparison purposes only. Of the Siemens ADVIA and special dilution on the ADVIA, the delegation invoked trade secrets. On how many tests the Edison did: trade secret!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>22. La Mattanza</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/22-la-mattanza/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/22-la-mattanza/</guid>
      <description>The FDA had approved Theranos&#39;s finger-stick tests for HSV-1. But to be fair, the herpes test is a qualtitative (yes/no) test. Most tests are quantitative. Arizona was about to pass a law (lobbied for by yours truly) to allow citizens to get blood tested without a doctor&#39;s order.
Elizabeth had also gotten cozy with the Obama administration.
Instead of showing an error message, the miniLab&#39;s screen now showed the test&#39;s progress slowing to a crawl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>23. Damage Control</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/23-damage-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/23-damage-control/</guid>
      <description>Rupert Murdoch led the most recent $430m funding round with $125m. He followed his gut: he&#39;d invested $150k in Uber for it to become $50m.
The investment packket forecasted (profit revenue) of ($330m, $1b) in 2015 and ($505m, $2b) in 2016. Furthermore, Theranos had lined up Cox Enterprises, The Waltons, New England Patriots owner, Carlos Slim, controller of Fiat Chrysler.
Elizabeth brought up Carreyrou&#39;s story to Murdoch, but Murdoch declined to intervene - saying he trusted the paper&#39;s editors to handle the matter fairly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>24. The Empress Has No Clothes</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/24-the-empress-has-no-clothes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/24-the-empress-has-no-clothes/</guid>
      <description>[3 weeks before first article] Erika Cheung&#39;s email to Gary Yamamoto (CMS) spurred the surprise inspection on Theranos&#39;s labs in less than 3 days. They found so many problems and missing documentation that they planned to return. When they returned, WSJ&#39;s article was out and there was pressure. CMS released a letter calling Theranos an &amp;ldquo;immediate jeopardy to patient health and safety&amp;rdquo;.
Theranos claimed to have fixed many of the deficiencies, and that the problems had no bearing on the soundness of its proprietary tech.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epilogue</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/25-epilogue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/25-epilogue/</guid>
      <description>March 14, 2018: SEC charges Theranos, Homes and Balwani with conducting &amp;ldquo;an elaborate, years-long fraud&amp;rdquo;. To resolve SEC&#39;s civil charges, Elizabeth was forced to relinquish her voting control, give back a big chunk of stock, pay a $500k penalty and not be an officer/director in a public company for 10 years.
Sunny didn&#39;t join Theranos until late 2009. Elizabeth had already been misleading pharmaceutical companies for years about the readiness of her tech.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook to Pay $550 Million to Settle Facial Recognition Suit [The New York Times]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/privacy/2020-01-29-fb-550m-fine-for-facial-recognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/privacy/2020-01-29-fb-550m-fine-for-facial-recognition/</guid>
      <description>Facebook to Pay $550 Million to Settle Facial Recognition Suit. Natasha Singer; Mike Isaac. The New York Times. https://www.nytimes.com/2020/01/29/technology/facebook-privacy-lawsuit-earnings.html. 2020-01-29.  Illinois&amp;rsquo; biometric privacy law requires companies to obtain written permission before collecting a person’s biometrics. Residents have the right to sue for up to $5,000 per violation.
Facebook&#39;s Tag Suggestions harvested facial data without getting written consent nor telling Illinois users for how long the data would be kept.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Do People Invest in the US?</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/2019-12-24-how-people-invest-in-the-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/2019-12-24-how-people-invest-in-the-us/</guid>
      <description>Index Funds and 401(k) Accounts  I assume the return is ~5% There are 4 types of retirement accounts, each with tradeoffs (en.wikipedia.org)  401(k), Roth 401(k), Traditional IRA and Roth IRA   The return of lazy portfolios (set and forget) is ~6% (compounded) over 15 years as of 2018 (finpage.blog)  Notes from /r/investing&#39;s FAQ (reddit.com)  The FAQ emphasizes reading books  I don&#39;t see the urgency. It&#39;s not as if I&#39;ll be picking my own stocks&amp;hellip; Maybe it&#39;s for me to know when to call bullshit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investing in Capital Markets</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/investing-in-kenya/2019-12-24-capital-markets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/investing-in-kenya/2019-12-24-capital-markets/</guid>
      <description>The Stock Market To trade in the NSE, open a CDS account with a CDA (some commercial banks, stockbrokers, investment banks).
In 2006, an Automatic Trading System was introduced so that orders are matched automatically and executed by stockbrokers on a first-come first-served basis. Govt bonds have also been added to the ATS. Securities lending, short-selling and same day turnaround trades are not yet permitted. (kestrelcapital.com)
I guess that&#39;s why quant funds are not a thing in Kenya.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investment Vehicles in Kenya</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/investing-in-kenya/2019-12-24-investment-vehicles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/investing-in-kenya/2019-12-24-investment-vehicles/</guid>
      <description>Investing through Groups (Chamas) www.kaig.org has developed a Chama Handbook to boost accountability and profitability.
But chamas have a higher chance of being guided by friendships than profitability. For instance, how do I go about picking a chama? It&#39;s most likely a referral from a friend who&#39;s already in a chama.
  Kenya USA Diaspora Sacco  Mavuno Term Deposit pays 8% interest for &amp;gt;1m KES and &amp;lt;2m KES deposited for a year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s All About Real Estate</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/investing-in-kenya/2019-12-24-its-all-about-real-estate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/investing-in-kenya/2019-12-24-its-all-about-real-estate/</guid>
      <description>Identifying Real Estate Opportunities   Portals:
 www.housejumia.co.ke www.buyrentkenya.com www.propertyleo.com www.kenyareal.com www.property24.co.ke    The Kenyan Diaspora Homes &amp;amp; Investments Expo
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting a Business in Kenya</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/investing-in-kenya/2019-12-24-starting-a-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/investing-in-kenya/2019-12-24-starting-a-business/</guid>
      <description>http://www.invest.go.ke/ has 3 components:
 A database on Vision 2030 projects and mega-investment opportunities An investor guide: labor matters, taxes, investor rights, etc. eRegulations platform: setting up and running businesses.  Many steps need to be completed in Kenya. Appoint an agent if need be.
Types of business vehicles: sole proprietorship, company, foreign company with local branch, LLP, partnership</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Curious Case of African ETFs</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/investing-in-kenya/2019-12-24-the-curious-case-of-african-etfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/investing-in-kenya/2019-12-24-the-curious-case-of-african-etfs/</guid>
      <description> etfdb.com has ETFs tracking regions. Surprised that Kenya isn&#39;t on it. And they&#39;re all losing money - best (over 5 years) is SA at -14.59%, Nigeria is at -64%.   Why all the PR on Africa being the next big investment scene?  Of course, Kenya&#39;s the premier investment destination (invest.go.ke)   Am I reading this right?? SOXL (semiconductors) ETF has &amp;gt;700% return over 5 years etfdb.com    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are the Basic Ideas On Investing?</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/2019-12-24-basic-ideas-behind-investing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/2019-12-24-basic-ideas-behind-investing/</guid>
      <description>Things to invest in  (Least risk) Bonds, Stocks, Startups (Most Risk).  Why not start a business?    The Amount of Money  Some investments only make sense in bulk for they have low margins, e.g. stocks  The risk tolerance  The higher the risk, the higher the reward The law protects investors, e.g. startup investors in the US must be accredited  The Time Frame  Maybe 10 years?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Scott Galloway] Third Base</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/people_affairs/socioeconomics/2019-12-13-galloway-third-base/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/people_affairs/socioeconomics/2019-12-13-galloway-third-base/</guid>
      <description>Third Base. Scott Galloway. No Mercy, No Malice. https://www.profgalloway.com/third-base/. 2019-12-13.  I don’t know much about physics but constantly reference Galileo despite knowing little besides the fact that he dared challenge the church.
:-) Dunning–Kruger Effect: a cognitive bias in which people assess their cognitive ability as greater than it is. (en.wikipedia.org)
  Masayoshi Son turned $20m into Alibaba into $100b. But he&#39;s mistaking luck in VC for his superior intuition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[BBC] Crows Could be the Smartest Animal Other Than Primates</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/science/biology/2019-12-11-bbc-crows-might-be-the-smartest-animal-other-than-primates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/science/biology/2019-12-11-bbc-crows-might-be-the-smartest-animal-other-than-primates/</guid>
      <description>Crows Could be the Smartest Animal Other Than Primates. BBC. https://www.bbc.com/future/article/20191211-crows-could-be-the-smartest-animal-other-than-primates. 2019-12-11.  New Caledonian crows make hooked tools from soft twigs to scoop insects out of holes. Other animals that use tools: chimpanzees, parrots, alligators and crabs.
The crows found the desired stems even when they had been disguised with leaves from a different plant species.
There are anecdotes of crow intelligence too, e.g. using cars at a crosslight to crush cashews in Japan (more in this HN thread)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Hacker News) Must and Must Not: On Writing Documentation</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/writing/2019-12-09-hn-on-writing-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/writing/2019-12-09-hn-on-writing-documentation/</guid>
      <description>Must and Must Not: On Writing Documentation. Hacker News. https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21743100. Dec 9th, 2019.    Revise documentation, many times, on separate days. What seemed perfectly clear yesterday will come across as ambiguous/confusing today.
  Beware of ambiguities, especially those that bubble between native speakers and non-native ones e.g.
 &amp;ldquo;X may not do Y&amp;rdquo;  X possibly doesn&#39;t do Y It&#39;s strictly forbidden that X do Y   &amp;ldquo;X Must Not&amp;rdquo;  Not a must =&amp;gt; You don&#39;t have to, but you can It&#39;s strictly forbidden      Put yourself into different roles, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We ran the numbers, and there really is a pipeline problem in eng hiring. [interviewing.io]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2019-12-03-there-is-a-pipeline-problem-in-eng-hiring/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2019-12-03-there-is-a-pipeline-problem-in-eng-hiring/</guid>
      <description>We ran the numbers, and there really is a pipeline problem in eng hiring.. Aline Lerner. http://blog.interviewing.io/we-ran-the-numbers-and-there-really-is-a-pipeline-problem-in-eng-hiring/. https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21694348. 2019-12-03.  Wait, but research shows:
 STEM in early education is unfriendly to children from underrepresented backgrounds Lack of a level playing field and unequal access to quality STEM education Hostile university culture in male-dominated CS programs Biased hiring practices Non-inclusive work environments cause higher churn of underrepresented folk.  Systemic issues can be hard to fix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[SSC] Book Review: All Therapy Books</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/people_affairs/psychology/2019-11-20-ssc-all-therapy-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/people_affairs/psychology/2019-11-20-ssc-all-therapy-books/</guid>
      <description>Book Review: All Therapy Books. Scott Alexander. Slate Star Codex. https://slatestarcodex.com/2019/11/20/book-review-all-therapy-books/.  Scott&#39;s thesis: Each of the therapy books on their own can be convincing. But they should be taken in the context of All Therapy Books, which as a category are pretty worrying.
All psychotherapy books bring up the (controversial) Dodo Bird Verdict – All psychotherapies are about equally good, and the only things that matters are &amp;ldquo;nonspecific factors&amp;rdquo; like how much patients like their therapist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Top 10 Tracks</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/autogenerated/top-10-tracks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/autogenerated/top-10-tracks/</guid>
      <description>   RankTrackArtistChange   {% for track in site.data.top_songs %}  {{ track.rank }} {{ track.track_name }} {{ track.artist_name }} {% if track.rank_delta  0 %} &amp;#9650; {{ track.rank_delta }} {% elsif track.rank_delta &amp;#9660; {{ track.rank_delta | abs }} {% elsif track.rank_delta == 0 %}  -  {% else %} New!  {% endif %}  {% endfor %}  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESG Stocks Are Graded on a Curve [Matt Levine]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/2019-11-11-esg-stocks-are-graded-on-a-curve/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/2019-11-11-esg-stocks-are-graded-on-a-curve/</guid>
      <description>ESG Stocks Are Graded on a Curve. Matt Levine. Money Stuff. https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2019-11-11/esg-stocks-are-graded-on-a-curve. 2019-11-11.  Investors often want (1) what they want plus (2) a label that validates what they want.
BlackRock designs its sustainable funds to match risk/return of broad market indexes while including the highest ESG-rated companies in each sector - the grading is on a curve.
8/10 of the biggest U.S. sustainable funds are invested in oil-and-gas companies (wsj.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The New Dot Com Bubble is Here: It’s Called Online Advertising [The Correspondent]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/2019-11-06-the-new-dotcom-bubble-is-online-advertising/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/2019-11-06-the-new-dotcom-bubble-is-online-advertising/</guid>
      <description>The New Dot Com Bubble is Here: It’s Called Online Advertising. The Correspondent. https://thecorrespondent.com/100/the-new-dot-com-bubble-is-here-its-called-online-advertising/13228924500-22d5fd24.  In 2018, $273b was spent on digital ads. But are ad platforms any good at manipulating us?
Tadelis, Econ Prof at UCB stint @ eBay: Consultants: paying for sponsored links for people that searched for &amp;lsquo;eBay&amp;rsquo; was a $245.6m return, not a $20m expense.
Selection Effect: What if the ad clickers were going to use eBay anyway?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AT&amp;T to pay $60m in settlement for slowing cellphone data on unlimited plans [Reuters]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/2019-11-05-att-pay-60m-in-settlement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/2019-11-05-att-pay-60m-in-settlement/</guid>
      <description>AT&amp;amp;T to pay $60m in settlement for slowing cellphone data on unlimited plans. Reuters. https://www.reuters.com/article/us-at-t-settlement/att-will-pay-60-million-over-u-s-allegations-it-lied-in-unlimited-data-pledge-government-idUSKBN1XF26Q.    Complaint filed in 2014 by the FTC: AT&amp;amp;T charged smartphone users for &amp;lsquo;unlimited&amp;rsquo; data plans, but throttled them after ~2GB within a month.
  AT&amp;amp;T: None of these allegations were ever proved in court. We were fully prepared to defend ourselves, but decided settling was in the best interests of consumers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cards from 03 Oct, 2019 to 20 Oct, 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/autogenerated/2019-10-20-flashcards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/autogenerated/2019-10-20-flashcards/</guid>
      <description>These set of flashcards can all be viewed at cards.c13u.com/browse . I own the site and I guarantee no funny business. It&#39;s more convenient for me to send you there than to replicate the contents on this page. Hope you find something interesting!   Elementary Operations on a System of Linear Equations?     What is a system of linear equations? What elementary operations are there on such a system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cards from 01 Sep, 2019 to 03 Oct, 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/autogenerated/2019-10-03-flashcards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/autogenerated/2019-10-03-flashcards/</guid>
      <description>These set of flashcards can all be viewed at cards.c13u.com/browse . I own the site and I guarantee no funny business. It&#39;s more convenient for me to send you there than to replicate the contents on this page. Hope you find something interesting!   Hidden Costs of Item Deletion in C++     Why is the first method less efficient than the second one in C++?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cards from 04 Aug, 2019 to 01 Sep, 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/autogenerated/2019-09-01-flashcards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/autogenerated/2019-09-01-flashcards/</guid>
      <description>These set of flashcards can all be viewed at cards.c13u.com/browse . I own the site and I guarantee no funny business. It&#39;s more convenient for me to send you there than to replicate the contents on this page. Hope you find something interesting!   The Multiverse Theory     Why do some cosmologists think that creation of an infinite space happens an infinite number of times? What are the consequences of an infinite multiverse?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Search of Influential Academic Publications</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/blog/2019-06-16-most-important-papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/blog/2019-06-16-most-important-papers/</guid>
      <description>I recently downloaded citations data from  Aminer  . I seek interesting papers to read during my free time [note]. The database has the following structure:   Table Columns Remarks   papers paper_id, title, venue, year, number of citations, abstract 3,079,007 papers from 1936 to 2018   authors name, appearance order, paper_id 1,766,547 distinct names (out of 9,476,165 names)   paper_references paper_id, cited_paper_id 25,166,994 references     Approach 1: Citation Count  For one, we can answer that with a SQL query: SELECT papers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The New York Times Sells Premium Ads Based on How an Article Makes You Feel [Poynter]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2019-04-10-nyt-sells-ads-based-on-how-an-article-makes-you-feel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2019-04-10-nyt-sells-ads-based-on-how-an-article-makes-you-feel/</guid>
      <description>The New York Times Sells Premium Ads Based on How an Article Makes You Feel. Rick Edmonds. Poynter. https://www.poynter.org/business-work/2019/the-new-york-times-sells-premium-ads-based-on-how-an-article-makes-you-feel/. 2019-04-10.  The NYT piloted ad placements based on the emotions certain articles evoke.
The average lift to an ad is 40% NYT can charge more for those ads.
Will the newsroom be tasked with producing lots of emotional stories? NYT&#39;s claims:
 The newsroom turned out plenty of emotionally charged stories, anyhow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standing Against Hate [Facebook]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2019-03-27-fb-standing-against-hate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2019-03-27-fb-standing-against-hate/</guid>
      <description>Standing Against Hate. https://about.fb.com/news/2019/03/standing-against-hate/. https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19503094. 2019-03-27.  Main Article We now ban praise, support and representation of white nationalism and separatism on FB and Instagram
We didn&#39;t ban them before because their broader concepts, e.g. American pride and Basque separatism, are an important part of people&#39;s identity.
Experts in race relations have confirmed that white nationalism and separatism cannot be meaningfully separated from white supremacy and organized hate groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Doesn’t Make Money Because It Isn’t Designed To Make Money [Ian Bicking]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/miscellaneous/2019-03-18-open-source-doesnt-make-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/miscellaneous/2019-03-18-open-source-doesnt-make-money/</guid>
      <description>Open Source Doesn’t Make Money Because It Isn’t Designed To Make Money. Ian Bicking. http://www.ianbicking.org/blog/2019/03/open-source-doesnt-make-money-by-design.html. 2019-03-18.  A [fallacious] Just World hypothesis: if something has utility, if it helps people, if it’s something the world needs, if it empowers other people, then there should be a revenue opportunity.
Classical scratch-your-own-itch open source software is built by programmers for programmers. And it is wildly successful, but it’s selling to people who aren’t willing to pay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Counterintuitive Competitive Advantages [Morgan Housel]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/on-starting-a-business/2019-03-13-counterintuitive-competitive-advantages/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/on-starting-a-business/2019-03-13-counterintuitive-competitive-advantages/</guid>
      <description>Counterintuitive Competitive Advantages. Morgan Housel. Collaborative Fund. https://www.collaborativefund.com/blog/counterintuitive-competitive-advantages/. 2019-03-13.  Growing big antlers requires lots of Ca and Ph, which are rare. Small antlers were required to survive low-food winters, but big antlers were required to impress females to mate. The Irish elk spiraled to extinction.
I get the analogy that Housel is trying to paint, but this seems like an oversimplification. Sure, big antlers are sexy, but if small antlers are all that&#39;s left on the menu, I don&#39;t think female antlers will think &amp;ldquo;pass&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Trauma Floor: The Secret Lives of FB Moderators in America [The Verge]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2019-02-25-the-secret-lives-of-fb-mods-in-america/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2019-02-25-the-secret-lives-of-fb-mods-in-america/</guid>
      <description>The Trauma Floor: The Secret Lives of FB Moderators in America. Casey Newton. The Verge. https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/25/18229714/cognizant-facebook-content-moderator-interviews-trauma-working-conditions-arizona. 2019-02-25.  Moderators in Phoenix will make just $28,800 per year — while the average FB employee has a total compensation of $240,000.
Team leaders micro-manage content moderators&amp;rsquo; every bathroom break. Two Muslim employees were ordered to stop praying during their 9min/day of allotted &amp;ldquo;wellness time&amp;rdquo;.
Employees can be fired after making just a handful of errors a week, and those who remain live in fear of former colleagues returning to seek vengeance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Shady Economics of Buy-One-Get-One Free Deals [The Hustle]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/2019-02-17-shady-economics-of-buy-one-get-one-free-deals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/2019-02-17-shady-economics-of-buy-one-get-one-free-deals/</guid>
      <description>The Shady Economics of Buy-One-Get-One Free Deals. Zachary Crockett. The Hustle. https://thehustle.co/are-buy-one-get-one-free-deals-worth-it/. 2019-02-17.  BOGO goods are usually low-demand, non-efficient, lacking in quality and/or close to the expiration date. The BOGO deal is usually a 50% discount off of the manufacturer’s suggested retail price (MSRP). And oftentimes, this price is artificially marked up to begin with.
 MyPillow offered BOGO deal on their pillows, but really just doubled the price of the first pillow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FB Under Pressure to Halt Rise of Anti-Vaccination Groups [The Guardian]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2019-02-12-fb-versus-antivaxx-groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2019-02-12-fb-versus-antivaxx-groups/</guid>
      <description>FB Under Pressure to Halt Rise of Anti-Vaccination Groups. Ed Pilkington, Jessica Glenza. The Guardian. https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2019/feb/12/facebook-anti-vaxxer-vaccination-groups-pressure-misinformation. 2019-02-12.  Vitamin C &amp;amp; Orthomolecular Medicine for Optimal Health. Closed Group. 49,000 approved members.
 Gironda, an admin, sells high-dose Vitamin C in bulk through Revitalize Wellness. The &amp;lsquo;shop now&amp;rsquo; button links to her firm. Revitalize Wellness carries a disclaimer saying that its products are “not intended to treat, diagnose, cure or prevent disease”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESG! The Meme [Epsilon Theory]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/2019-01-29-esg-the-meme/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/2019-01-29-esg-the-meme/</guid>
      <description>Kobayashi Maru. Epsilon Theory. https://www.epsilontheory.com/kobayashi-maru/. 2019-01-29.  Environmental, Social and Governance Investing. So general as to be meaningless: marketing BS (thinking &amp;lsquo;holistically&amp;rsquo; about ESG risk factors as part of the investment process) to impact investing (providing wholesale financing for community lending initiatives).
ESG! The meme is about selling portfolios as virtue signaling devices. It moves the conversation away from fees and performance to values. Don&#39;t you want to make a difference?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Monetizing Encrypted Messaging by Analyzing Metadata [Twitter]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/privacy/2019-01-25-fb-monetizing-encrypted-messages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/privacy/2019-01-25-fb-monetizing-encrypted-messages/</guid>
      <description>Facebook Monetizing Encrypted Messaging by Analyzing Metadata. @SarahJamieLewis. https://twitter.com/SarahJamieLewis/status/1088914192847917056. 2019-01-25.  Claim: FB will track relationships and social groups and make that information accessible to law enforcement. FB is a corporation that needs to make money; surveillance makes them money.
Contention: Actual privacy and security must protect metadata as well as content.
Cwtch by OpenPrivacy aims to minimize metadata exposed by apps used. It&#39;s built on Tor. Challenges: message latency, server reliability &amp;amp; discovery, (online) first contact problem for key exchange.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why are glasses so expensive? [LA Times]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/2019-01-22-why-are-glasses-so-expensive/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/2019-01-22-why-are-glasses-so-expensive/</guid>
      <description>Why are glasses so expensive? The eyewear industry prefers to keep that blurry. David Lazurus. LA Times. https://www.latimes.com/business/lazarus/la-fi-lazarus-why-are-eyeglasses-so-expensive-20190122-story.html. 2019-01-22.   Column: How badly are we being ripped off on eyewear? Former industry execs tell all. David Lazurus. LA Times. https://www.latimes.com/business/lazarus/la-fi-lazarus-glasses-lenscrafters-luxottica-monopoly-20190305-story.html. 2019-03-05.    Luxottica bought everyone. They set whatever prices they please.
 Luxottica owns and licenses Armani, Brooks Brothers, Burberry, Chanel, Coach, DKNY, Dolce &amp;amp; Gabbana, Michael Kors, Oakley, Oliver Peoples, Persol, Polo Ralph Lauren, Ray-Ban, Tiffany, Valentino, Vogue and Versace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Less Wrong) I Want It My Way</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/overly_convenient_excuses/2019-01-04-lw-i-want-it-my-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/overly_convenient_excuses/2019-01-04-lw-i-want-it-my-way/</guid>
      <description>I Want It My Way!. Nick Hayes. Less Wrong. https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/WiDh3ca3C7GgrNXAn/i-want-it-my-way. 4th Jan, 2019.  Letting go of how you think things should be lets you see how things are. Consequently, you&#39;ll be able to get better results.
Wanting it my way: I believe that failure is bad, and that if I fail, then I personally am I failure. So I have those two things conflated. Then anything I do risks failing, especially new things, so I&#39;d better not do the new things, then.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (DHH) You Probably Won&#39;t Make it to the Top</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/letting_go/2018-11-22-dhh-you-probably-wont-make-it-to-the-top/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/letting_go/2018-11-22-dhh-you-probably-wont-make-it-to-the-top/</guid>
      <description>You Probably Won&amp;#39;t Make it to the Top. David Heinemeier Hansson (DHH). Signal vs. Noise. https://m.signalvnoise.com/youre-probably-won-t-make-it-to-the-top-8d2146abb790. 22nd Nov, 2018.  Fallacy: If you really set your mind to it, you can do it. Get to the very top. Beat out all the others. That’s how I did it. I just wanted it more, worked hard, and eventually all my dreams came true. I won’t say it’s easy, but it’s up to you!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Housel) Humble Exits</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/letting_go/2018-10-24-housel-humble-exits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/letting_go/2018-10-24-housel-humble-exits/</guid>
      <description>Humble Exits. Morgan Housel. The Collaborative Fund. https://www.collaborativefund.com/blog/humble-exits/. 24th Oct, 2018.  Jack Welch declined $110m for a 10th season of Seinfeld because he was done with the show. He wanted to end the show on the same kind of peak.
The show was based on recreating real events from his and Larry David&#39;s normal life. They were running out of material because it had been so long since they experienced a normal life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Sivan) Innovation Africa &amp; Water Availability</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/innovation_in_africa/2018-10-01-innovation-africa-and-water-availability/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/innovation_in_africa/2018-10-01-innovation-africa-and-water-availability/</guid>
      <description>Innovation Africa &amp;amp; Water Availability. Sivan (InnoAfrica). Talks at The Keller Center. 2018.  Bring in Israeli solar panels and drip irrigation. Pump water from the large reservoirs below. Cost $7,000.
Adapting to community: 6-8 weeks on committees, bank accounts; mobile charging stations and barbershops using solar panels for sustainability. Can&#39;t sell the water, but you can subsidize it with complementary products.
Set up remote monitoring with real time stats in order to schedule maintenance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Does a Market Work? [CS Colloquia]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/2018-10-01-how-does-a-market-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/2018-10-01-how-does-a-market-work/</guid>
      <description>Objectives: low latency, high throughput &amp;amp; high reliability.
The messages are quite brief, e.g. the ITCH protocol uses 32 bytes per message.
Trading firm listens to broadcasts on buys, sells, deletes on ITCH broadcasts. Online sorting to identify profitable trades.
Matching engine operates on a first-come-first-served basis. Earlier orders with better price get traded first.
Markets run at 50 microsecond scales.
Single market peaks at 10Gbps. Peaks are correlated, e.g. &amp;ldquo;Shit!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Chinese Govt Controls the Media [SoECS]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2018-10-01-chinese-media-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2018-10-01-chinese-media-control/</guid>
      <description>Seeing government influence through coordination of sensitive coverage, localization of negative news &amp;amp; crowding out other stories on the front page.
Structural topic models (LDA + context, e.g. topic prevalence, choice of words) analyze fundamental aspect of the news that can&#39;t be changed.
Instead of assuming news follows events, investigate!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons Learned in Tech Policy [SoECS]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2018-10-01-lessons-learned-in-tech-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2018-10-01-lessons-learned-in-tech-policy/</guid>
      <description>Local governments face severe constraints. Liaising with big tech for employees on sabbaticals could alleviate this.
State legislators may have unfounded opinions, but they have the sway, so work with them.
Rural-urban differences. Rural folk were more active. Urban folks wrote angry blogs and that was it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wolf that Tried to Play Nice [SoECS]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2018-10-01-the-wolf-that-tried-to-play-nice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2018-10-01-the-wolf-that-tried-to-play-nice/</guid>
      <description>AT&amp;amp;T restricted FaceTime from running on some data plans. Justifications?
 FaceTime is preloaded, therefore 100% of users have it FaceTime wasn&#39;t efficient in network usage. The capacity was asymmetrical, but video chat is symmetrical  Interestingly enough, AT&amp;amp;T required Apple to greenlight it, which they did. AT&amp;amp;T worked with top developers to teach network etiquette.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computers Can Solve Your Problem. You May Not Like the Answer. [Boston Globe]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2018-09-21-boston-public-school-equity-algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2018-09-21-boston-public-school-equity-algorithm/</guid>
      <description>Computers Can Solve Your Problem. You May Not Like the Answer. What happened when Boston Public Schools tried for equity with an algorithm. David Scharfenberg. The Boston Globe. https://apps.bostonglobe.com/ideas/graphics/2018/09/equity-machine/. 2018-09-21.  Teens need their sleep: sleep-deprived teens are at increased risk for poor academic performance, binge drinking, and suicide.
BPS laid out the algorithm’s four guiding principles:
 Increase the number of high school students starting school after 8am Decrease the number of elementary school students dismissed after 4pm Accommodate the needs of special education students wherever possible Generate transportation savings that could be reinvested in the schools  Officials picked a solution that attempted to balance several goals — student health, cost savings, and parental happiness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Mathematicians Can&#39;t Find the Hay in a Haystack [Quanta Magazine]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/mathematics/2018-09-17-cant-find-hay-in-a-hay-stack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/mathematics/2018-09-17-cant-find-hay-in-a-hay-stack/</guid>
      <description>Why Mathematicians Can’t Find the Hay in a Haystack. Kevin Hartnett. https://www.quantamagazine.org/why-mathematicians-cant-find-the-hay-in-a-haystack-20180917/. 2018-09-17.  Irrational numbers occupy most of the number line. If you were to pick a number on the number line at random, there is literally a 100% chance that it will be irrational (probabilities with inifinities are spooky). Yet, we almost never encounter irrational numbers for we can&#39;t write them down.
The shapes we know best - lines, parabolas, circles, spheres - are the needles, for they can be expressed by simple equations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Theory, Evolution &amp; Games) Separating Theory from Nonsense via Communication Norms, not Truth</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/knowing/2018-09-08-teg-separating-theory-from-nonsense/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/knowing/2018-09-08-teg-separating-theory-from-nonsense/</guid>
      <description>Separating Theory from Nonsense via Communication Norms, not Truth. Artem Kaznatcheev. Theory, Evolution &amp;amp; Games. https://egtheory.wordpress.com/2018/09/08/theory-norms/. 8th Sept, 2018.  Brian Skinner - how to distinguish good theory from crackpottery  Both theorists and crackpots share an irrational self-confidence A crackpot relies primarily on positive evidence  Thinks hard about a problem, arrives at a theory that feels right, and then publicizes the result.   A theorist incorporates negative evidence:  Ponders hard about a problem, arrives at a theory that feels right and then proceeds to try to disprove that theory Takes time to understand competing theories and compare them against her own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is the Lean Startup Dead? [Steve Blank]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/on-starting-a-business/2018-09-05-is-the-lean-startup-dead/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/on-starting-a-business/2018-09-05-is-the-lean-startup-dead/</guid>
      <description>Is the Lean Startup Dead?. Steve Blank. https://steveblank.com/2018/09/05/is-the-lean-startup-dead/. 2018-09-05.  Katzenberg (Paramount, Disney Studios &amp;amp; DreamWorks) has raised $1.75b for NewTV, a startup banking on consumers wanting a subscription for 10-minute programs on mobile.
They renamed to quibi.com/. At least that makes them more searchable on Google. &amp;ldquo;NewTV&amp;rdquo; searches lead to newtv.org, a community media center for the residents of Newton, Massachusetts.
  After the rubble of the dotcom crash, startups and investors needed a lean approach to survive long enough to generate revenue and profits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Stuff On the Internet (#1)</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/blog/2018-08-30-random-walk-on-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/blog/2018-08-30-random-walk-on-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>(April 2018) An Apology for the Internet 
Remember &amp;lsquo;Seasons in the Sun&amp;rsquo;? I thought it was Westlife&#39;s but turns out Terry Jacks is the real owner. Combine that melody and some witty criticism of current technological trends and you get Joy of Tech&#39;s comic. Cheers to more cat memes in the sun. Also, relevant XKCD!
Burrito Time by Dos Toros As much as I advocate for not being glued to the phone, it&#39;s hard to hate the brilliant marketing: one notification sent every day at a random time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Trajectory of Great Ideas [Morgan Housel]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/on-starting-a-business/2018-08-14-trajectory-of-great-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/on-starting-a-business/2018-08-14-trajectory-of-great-ideas/</guid>
      <description>The Trajectory of Great Ideas. Morgan Housel. Collaborative Fund. https://www.collaborativefund.com/blog/ideas/. 2018-08-14.  Sears. Blockbuster. Nokia. AOL. You had a great idea. You discovered a beautiful beach to lay on, but other people didn&#39;t just follow you and lay down themselves; they built condos and restaurants while you were watching the sunset. Soon your great idea loses its appeal.
But you put so much work into the great idea that it&#39;s become an inseparable part of your identity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google&#39;s Project Dragonfly [The Intercept]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/privacy/2018-08-01-google-project-dragonfly/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/privacy/2018-08-01-google-project-dragonfly/</guid>
      <description>Google Plans to Launch Censored Search Engine in China, Leaked Documents Reveal [The Intercept]. Ryan Gallagher. The Intercept. https://theintercept.com/2018/08/01/google-china-search-engine-censorship/. 2018-08-01.  Project Dragonfly A censored version of Google search that blacklists websites and search terms about human rights, democracy, religion and peaceful protests.
China has 750m people; 80% of its internet access is on Android. There&#39;s $$$ to be made.
Between 2006 and 2010, Google had maintained a censored Google Search, but was heavily criticized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Average Age of a Successful Startup Founder is 45 [Harvard Business]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/on-starting-a-business/2018-07-11-average-age-of-successful-founder-is-45/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/on-starting-a-business/2018-07-11-average-age-of-successful-founder-is-45/</guid>
      <description>The Average Age of a Successful Startup Founder is 45. Harvard Business Review. https://hbr.org/2018/07/research-the-average-age-of-a-successful-startup-founder-is-45. 2018-07-11.  There&#39;s a variation among industries: software tends to 40, while oil/gas/biotech tends to 47.
Even Gates, Jobs, Bezos, Brin &amp;amp; Page had their growth rates peak when they were middle aged.
Different definitions of success, e.g. employment growth, sales growth, IPO/acquisition, came to the same conclusion.
VCs may not be looking for growth potential.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Love B2B over B2C [Atrium]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/on-starting-a-business/2018-07-11-why-i-love-b2b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/on-starting-a-business/2018-07-11-why-i-love-b2b/</guid>
      <description>Why I Love B2B over B2C. Justin Kan. Atrium. https://www.atrium.co/blog/b2b-vs-b2c/. 2018-07-11.  B2B customers will actually pay for your product. You have a clear execution path - they&#39;ll tell you and pay for features. Companies don&#39;t quickly flip flop between products. Consumers are too price sensitive and finicky.
B2B customers are rational, and thus understandable. They care about:
 Does this solution solve my problem? Is it an important enough solution that I will pay for it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Morgan Housel) Immeasurably Important</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/an_outlook_on_life/2018-07-01-housel-immeasurably-important/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/an_outlook_on_life/2018-07-01-housel-immeasurably-important/</guid>
      <description>Immeasurably Important. Morgan Housel. Collaborative Fund. http://www.collaborativefund.com/blog/immeasurably-important/. 5th July, 2018.  Filtering out information is an art, not a science, necessitated by the information overload that we live in.
 Watch out for the tendency to only preserve information that meshes with how we think the world should be. If you think the world is all art, you miss how much stuff is too complicated to think about intuitively.  If you think the world is all data, you&#39;ll miss how much is too complicated to summarize in a statistic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IBM Watson&#39;s Health Saga</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/2018-06-25-ibm-watsons-health-saga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/2018-06-25-ibm-watsons-health-saga/</guid>
      <description>Layoffs at Watson Health Reveal IBM’s Problem with AI. Eliza Strickland. IEEE. https://spectrum.ieee.org/the-human-os/robotics/artificial-intelligence/layoffs-at-watson-health-reveal-ibms-problem-with-ai. https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17393560. 2018-06-25.   Jefferies gives IBM Watson a Wall Street reality check. John Mannes. https://techcrunch.com/2017/07/13/jefferies-gives-ibm-watson-a-wall-street-reality-check/. https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=14766793. 2017-07-13.    IBM acquired Phytel, Explorys and Truven for their troves of healthcare data and proprietary analytics.
  From 2010 to 2015, IBM has spent +$15bn and Watson is still not profitable.
  Marketed abilities: scan literature &amp;amp; patient history to recommend cancer treatment plans, offer preventative medicine &amp;amp; medical imaging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>U.S. Files Criminal Charges Against Elizabeth Holmes and Ramesh Balwani [WSJ]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/2018-06-15-theranos-disaster/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/2018-06-15-theranos-disaster/</guid>
      <description>U.S. Files Criminal Charges Against Elizabeth Holmes and Ramesh Balwani. John Carreyrou. The Wall Street Journal. https://www.wsj.com/articles/u-s-files-criminal-charges-against-theranoss-elizabeth-holmes-ramesh-balwani-1529096005. https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17323485. 2018-06-15.   (Ask HN) Holmes has 200 Patents. If tech didn&amp;#39;t work, why not noticed?. Hacker News. https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17328664. 2018-06-18.   Theranos Lessons. Morgan Housel. Collaborative Fund&amp;#39;s Blog. https://www.collaborativefund.com/blog/theranos-lessons/. 2019-06-19.   This CEO is Out for Blood. Roger Parloff. https://www.fortune.com/2014/06/12/theranos-blood-holmes/. https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=7951019. 2014-06-12.  Holmes and COO charged with wire fraud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Psychology of Money [Morgan Housel]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/an_outlook_on_life/2018-06-01-housel-psychology-of-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/an_outlook_on_life/2018-06-01-housel-psychology-of-money/</guid>
      <description>The Psychology of Money. Morgan Housel. The Collaborative Fund. http://www.collaborativefund.com/blog/the-psychology-of-money/. 2018-06-01.  Luck and risk are different sides of the same coin. People underestimate the role of luck and risk. There are a billion investors. By sheer chance, we expect a couple of them to be billionaires predominantly off luck. But it&#39;s hard to point fingers after the fact.
 Some people are born into families that encourage education; others are against it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Azeria Labs) The Importance of Deep Work &amp; The 30-Hour Method for Learning a New Skill</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/a_guide_to_creativity/2018-05-26-azeria-labs-importance-of-deep-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/a_guide_to_creativity/2018-05-26-azeria-labs-importance-of-deep-work/</guid>
      <description>The Importance of Deep Work &amp;amp; The 30-Hour Method for Learning a New Skill. Azeria Labs. https://azeria-labs.com/the-importance-of-deep-work-the-30-hour-method-for-learning-a-new-skill/. https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17163251.  30 Hour Deep Work Tryout:
 Scan resources and pick the ones that seem most useful (5 hours) Set up the environment and define structured goals (3 hours) Work towards increasingly difficult goals set in step 2 (22 hours)  Each session should be about 4 hours. It takes about 20min to get into the flow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Apology for the Internet - How It Went Wrong [Intelligencer]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/privacy/2018-04-16-an-apology-for-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/privacy/2018-04-16-an-apology-for-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>An Apology for the Internet - How It Went Wrong. Noah Kulwin. NY Mag. http://nymag.com/intelligencer/2018/04/an-apology-for-the-internet-from-the-people-who-built-it.html. 2018-04-16.  Start with hippie good intentions. A generation embracing new technology as a tool to transform the world for good.
 Can Duruk: You were going to Facebook not to work but to make the world more open and connected.  Mix in capitalism on steroids. To save the world, you first need to take it over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cambridge Analytica Uncovered: Secret filming reveals election tricks [Channel 4]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2018-03-19-cambridge-analytica-uncovered/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2018-03-19-cambridge-analytica-uncovered/</guid>
      <description>Cambridge Analytica Uncovered: Secret filming reveals election tricks. Channel 4 News. https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mpbeOCKZFfQ. 2018-03-19.  Pay people to take surveys but through an app. Mine their profile data, and also crawl their friends.
Identify swayable voters and their sensitivities. Craft targeted ads. Play on (unconscious) fears and hopes.
Elections are about emotions, not facts. Data science and social media can help us make sense of and manipulate the chaos.
An alternative argument: political misinformation is&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Competitive Edges Die [Morgan Housel]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/on-starting-a-business/2018-02-08-why-competitive-edges-die/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/on-starting-a-business/2018-02-08-why-competitive-edges-die/</guid>
      <description>Why Competitive Edges Die. Morgan Housel. Collaborative Fund. https://www.collaborativefund.com/blog/why-competitive-advantages-die/. 2018-02-08.  The Beginner&#39;s Mind Being right is the enemy of staying right because it leads you to forget the way the world works.
Knowing you have a competitive advantage reduces the incentive to explore other ideas, especially when those ideas conflict with your chosen strategy.
The Burden of Being Profitable Nothing to lose is a wonderful thing to have. Having a quarterly dividend to maintain is what happens after you build something great.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Betting on Things That Never Change [Morgan Housel]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/2017-07-20-betting-on-things-that-never-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/2017-07-20-betting-on-things-that-never-change/</guid>
      <description>Betting on Things That Never Change. Morgan Housel. Collaborative Fund. https://www.collaborativefund.com/blog/betting-on-things-that-never-change/. 2017-07-20.  Change by itself is hard. Investors have to spot it before it&#39;s obvious. Consumers have to change their behaviors to make it viable. These two points repel each other.
Sears bet the Internet changed nothing. Beenz bet the Internet changed everything - creating a points-based currency valid only at online merchants. Amazon bet the Internet changed distribution, but rooted its strategy in selection and low prices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[The Atlantic] Brainless Slime That Can Learn by Fusing</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/science/biology/2016-12-21-brainless-slime-that-can-learn-by-fusing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/science/biology/2016-12-21-brainless-slime-that-can-learn-by-fusing/</guid>
      <description>Brainless Slime That Can Learn by Fusing. The Atlantic. https://www.theatlantic.com/science/archive/2016/12/the-brainless-slime-that-can-learn-by-fusing/511295/. 2016-12-21.  Most people thought that it was impossible for a cell to learn. Maybe brains are not prerequisites for complex and interesting behavior.
If one part of the plasmodium touches something attractive, like food, it pulses more quickly and widens. If another part meets something repulsive, like light, it pulses more slowly and shrinks. By adding up all of these effects, the plasmodium flows in the best possible direction without a single conscious thought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Syll) What is Ergodicity?</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/knowing/2016-11-23-syll-what-is-ergodicity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/knowing/2016-11-23-syll-what-is-ergodicity/</guid>
      <description>What is Ergodicity?. Lars P. Syll. https://larspsyll.wordpress.com/2016/11/23/what-is-ergodicity-2/. 23rd Nov, 2016.  A random process is ergodic if all of its statistics can be determined from a sample function of the process. That is, the ensemble averages equal the corresponding time averages with probability one.
Role of Ergodicity in Human Inference  A newspaper has previously printed some inaccurate information, therefore, the newspaper is going to publish inaccurate information in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Trade of the Century: When George Soros Broke the British Pound [Priceonomics]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/2016-06-17-when-soros-broke-the-british-pound/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/2016-06-17-when-soros-broke-the-british-pound/</guid>
      <description>The Trade of the Century: When George Soros Broke the British Pound. Rohin Dhar. Priceonomics. https://priceonomics.com/the-trade-of-the-century-when-george-soros-broke/. 2016-06-17.  Before the EU, Europe had the ERM to fix their exchange rates with the Deutschmark within 6% of the agreed upon rate.
Keeping the exchange rate fixed requires governments to nudge the rate, e.g.
 Use reserves of foreign currency to buy up their own currency Set high interest rates to entice lenders to buy their currency  Margaret Thatcher (PM) opposed the fixed exchange rates but lost the vote to Major, an ERM proponent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Read a Paper [Keshav]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/science/2016-02-17-how-to-read-a-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/science/2016-02-17-how-to-read-a-paper/</guid>
      <description>How to Read a Paper. S. Keshav. David R. Cheriton School of Computer Science, University of Waterloo. https://blizzard.cs.uwaterloo.ca/keshav/home/Papers/data/07/paper-reading.pdf. 2016-02-17.  The First Pass (5 - 10 min) Objectives: category, context, validity of assumptions, contributions and quality of writing.
 Carefully read the title, abstract, and introduction. Read the section and sub-section headings, but ignore everything else Glance at the math to determine the underlying theoretical foundations Read the conclusions. Mentally tick off references that you&#39;ve already read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Paul Graham) Life is Short</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/an_outlook_on_life/2016-01-01-pg-bullshit-minimizing-path/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/an_outlook_on_life/2016-01-01-pg-bullshit-minimizing-path/</guid>
      <description>Life is Short. Paul Graham. http://www.paulgraham.com/vb.html. Jan 2016.  Some of it is our own fault (e.g. arguing online). Some of it is forced by circumstances that we choose to endure (e.g. unnecessary meetings at work)
Choosing a bullshit minimizing path is error-prone. Your priorities change over time. Periodically evaluate where you are. It helps to have measurable aspects of your life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So You Want to Reform Democracy [Medium]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2015-11-22-so-you-want-to-reform-democracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2015-11-22-so-you-want-to-reform-democracy/</guid>
      <description>So You Want to Reform Democracy. Joshua Tauberer. https://medium.com/civic-tech-thoughts-from-joshdata/so-you-want-to-reform-democracy-7f3b1ef10597. 2015-11-22.  If there was an idea that could &amp;lsquo;fix&amp;rsquo; democracy, it would have been thought-up already. If you don&#39;t see your idea out there, it’s because it didn’t work the hundreds of other times someone tried it.
Let’s tell representatives what their constituents think. Then they HAVE to vote with us!
 They don’t necessarily want to know what their constituents are thinking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Slate Star Codex) No Clarity Around Growth Mindset</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/letting_go/2015-04-08-ssc-no-clarity-around-the-growth-mindset/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/letting_go/2015-04-08-ssc-no-clarity-around-the-growth-mindset/</guid>
      <description>No Clarity Around Growth Mindset. Scott Alexander. Slate Star Codex. https://slatestarcodex.com/2015/04/08/no-clarity-around-growth-mindset-yet/. 8th April, 2015.  Growth mindset: people who believe effort - and not ability - determines success are more resilient, skillful, hard-working, perseverant in the face of failure.
Most of the growth mindset experiments prime their subjects, but recent priming experiments have famously failed to replicate. Dweck&#39;s experiment:
 Group A: easy test (success) -&amp;gt; final bound-to-fail test Group B: hard test (told they&#39;re not working hard enough) -&amp;gt; final bound-to-fail test Group B outperformed Group A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Eliezer Yudkowsy) Against Rationalization</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/against_rationalization/2015-02-01-yudkowsky-against-rationalization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/against_rationalization/2015-02-01-yudkowsky-against-rationalization/</guid>
      <description>Against Rationalization. Eliezer Yudkowsky. Rationality: From AI to Zombies. Feb 2015.  In real life, you have to gather evidence, which may be costly. At some point you have to decide that you have enough evidence to stop and choose. A motivated skeptic asks if the evidence compels them to accept the conclusion; a motivated credulist asks if the evidence allows them to accept the conclusion.
Suspect motivated stopping when you close off the search, after coming to a comfortable conclusion, and yet there is a lot of fast cheap evidence you haven&#39;t gathered yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Yudkowsky) 0 and 1 Are Not Probabilities</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/overly_convenient_excuses/2015-02-01-yudkowsky-0-and-1-are-not-probabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/overly_convenient_excuses/2015-02-01-yudkowsky-0-and-1-are-not-probabilities/</guid>
      <description>0 And 1 Are Not Probabilities. Eliezer Yudkowsky. Rationality: From AI to Zombies. Feb 2015.  $$ O = \frac{P}{1 - P},\ \ \ P = \frac{O}{1 + O} $$
When you transform probabilities to odds, 0 goes to 0, but 1 goes to infinity. Now the absolute truth doesn&#39;t look like it should be easy to reach.
When you transform probabilities to odds, 0.502 and 0.503 goes to 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Yudkowsky) Letting Go</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/letting_go/2015-12-01-yudkowsky-letting-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/letting_go/2015-12-01-yudkowsky-letting-go/</guid>
      <description>Letting Go. Eliezer Yudkowsky. Rationality: From AI to Zombies. Feb 2015.  Learn when to admit failure It&#39;s important to have a watershed moment, the moment of humbling realization. To acknowledge a fundamental problem, not to divide it into palatable bite-size mistakes.
Not all mistakes are disguised successes. Don&#39;t paint all failures as learning experiences.
LTCM were exploiting market inefficiencies. Other people learned of the tricks. LTCM didn&#39;t lose hope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Yudkowsky) Lotteries</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/overly_convenient_excuses/2015-02-01-yudkowsky-lotteries-a-waste-of-hope/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/overly_convenient_excuses/2015-02-01-yudkowsky-lotteries-a-waste-of-hope/</guid>
      <description>Lotteries: A Waste of Hope. Eliezer Yudkowsky. Rationality: From AI to Zombies. Feb 2015.   New Improved Lottery. Eliezer Yudkowsky. Rationality: From AI to Zombies. Feb 2015.  The lottery is a sink of emotional energy. It encourages people to invest in their dreams, their hopes for a better future, into an infinitesimal probability.
People can&#39;t devalue the emotional force of pleasant anticipation by a factor of .0000001 without dropping the line of reasoning entirely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Yudkowsky) The Proper Use of Humility</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/overly_convenient_excuses/2015-02-01-yudkowsky-the-proper-use-of-humility/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/overly_convenient_excuses/2015-02-01-yudkowsky-the-proper-use-of-humility/</guid>
      <description>The Proper Use of Humility. Eliezer Yudkowsky. Rationality: From AI to Zombies. Feb 2015.  To be humble is to take specific actions in anticipation of your own errors. To confess your fallibility and then do nothing about it is not humble; it is boasting of your modesty.
Good humility: Engineer humbly designs fail-safe mechanisms into machinery, even though they are damn sure the machinery won&#39;t fail.
Bad humility: But who can really know whether evolution is correct?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Yudkowsky) The Third Alternative</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/overly_convenient_excuses/2015-02-01-yudkowsky-the-third-alternative/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/overly_convenient_excuses/2015-02-01-yudkowsky-the-third-alternative/</guid>
      <description>The Third Alternative. Eliezer Yudkowsky. Rationality: From AI to Zombies. Feb 2015.  If Santa-belief is destroyed by truth, the children will lose their sense of wonder and stop behaving nicely. It does not follow that Santa-ism is the best of all possible alternatives.
People justify questionable policy by pointing to a supposed benefit over the null action. The search for alternatives can go on forever, so one needs a stopping criterion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Yudkowsky) There&#39;s Still a Chance, Right?</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/overly_convenient_excuses/2015-02-01-yudkowsky-overly-convenient-theres-still-a-chance-right/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/overly_convenient_excuses/2015-02-01-yudkowsky-overly-convenient-theres-still-a-chance-right/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;#39;s Still a Chance, Right?. Eliezer Yudkowsky. Rationality: From AI to Zombies. Feb 2015.  &amp;ldquo;Humans and chimps have 98% shared DNA.&amp;rdquo; Maybe the DNA is just similar by coincidence. You say the odds are tiny, but there&#39;s still a chance, right?
The problem is that probability theory sometimes lets us calculate a chance which is, indeed, too tiny to be worth the mental space to keep track of it - but by that time, you&#39;ve already calculated it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (SSC) The Parable of the Talents</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/an_outlook_on_life/2015-01-31-ssc-the-principle-of-the-talents/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/an_outlook_on_life/2015-01-31-ssc-the-principle-of-the-talents/</guid>
      <description>The Parable of the Talents. Scott Alexander. Slate Star Codex. https://slatestarcodex.com/2015/01/31/the-parable-of-the-talents/. 31st Jan, 2015.  Overweight people, depressed people, and poor people aren’t fully to blame for their situation – and neither are unintelligent people. It’s accidents of birth all the way down.
Srinivasa Ramanujan:
 Grew up in poverty in a one-room house in small-town India. But a lot of poor people in the US had better conditions/opportunities  Either, a lot of intelligence is innate Or, those poor people are just not trying hard enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Heaton, Graham) How to Read and Know</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/a_guide_to_creativity/2014-12-01-reading-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/a_guide_to_creativity/2014-12-01-reading-to-know/</guid>
      <description>How to Read. Robert Heaton. https://robertheaton.com/2018/06/25/how-to-read/. https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17424652. June 25th, 2018.   Know. Paul Graham. http://www.paulgraham.com/know.html. Dec 2014.   Choose your content. Some books are not worth the effort. Reading and experience train your model of the world. Your mind is like a compiled program for which you&#39;ve lost the source code. At a different time, re-reading the book will be compiled differently because your world model has probably matured more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do Things That Don&#39;t Scale [Paul Graham]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/on-starting-a-business/2013-07-01-do-things-that-dont-scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/on-starting-a-business/2013-07-01-do-things-that-dont-scale/</guid>
      <description>Do Things That Don&amp;#39;t Scale. Paul Graham. http://www.paulgraham.com/ds.html. 2013-07-01.  Recruit manually. Don&#39;t send links. Set them up on the spot.
Ask how big the startup would be if you did the right things, not whether you&#39;re currently changing the world.
Delight your initial customers. Tim Cook can&#39;t send handwritten notes, but you can.
If you can solve the problem manually, do so while gradually automating the most pressing bottlenecks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Get Startup Ideas [Paul Graham]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/on-starting-a-business/2012-11-01-how-to-get-startup-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/on-starting-a-business/2012-11-01-how-to-get-startup-ideas/</guid>
      <description>How to Get Startup Ideas. Paul Graham. http://www.paulgraham.com/startupideas.html. 2012-11-01.  Err on the side of having competitors, but make sure that you have a thesis that everyone else is overlooking, e.g. Google wasn&#39;t averse to users leaving google.com ASAP
The Startup Idea Matrix, (B2B Edition, B2C Edition) is a good start for knowing who to google.
  In college, take classes in different areas in lieu of taking entrepreneurship classes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Doctors Die [Zocalo]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/2011-11-30-how-doctors-die/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/2011-11-30-how-doctors-die/</guid>
      <description>How Doctors Die. Zocalo Public Square. https://www.zocalopublicsquare.org/2011/11/30/how-doctors-die/ideas/nexus/.  Doctors tend to be fairly serene when faced with death themselves. They know enough about modern medicine to know its limits. They go gently into that good night - no heroics; no CPR.
Sometimes, a family really means &amp;lsquo;do everything&amp;rsquo;, but often they mean &amp;lsquo;do everything that’s reasonable.&amp;rsquo; But they may not know what’s reasonable.
People have unrealistic expectations of what doctors can accomplish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Submarine [Paul Graham]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/2005-04-01-the-submarine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/2005-04-01-the-submarine/</guid>
      <description>The Submarine. Paul Graham. http://www.paulgraham.com/submarine.html. 2005-04.  Many people rely on social proof to form opinions; therein lies the power of PR.
PR firms are not dishonest for they need good reputation with news outlets. But PR firms serve overworked reporters with selective truths.
The firms feed the same story to different publications at once. Readers see similar stories in multiple places and assume a new trend has come.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Paul Graham) The Age of the Essay</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/a_guide_to_creativity/2004-09-01-pg-the-age-of-the-essay/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/a_guide_to_creativity/2004-09-01-pg-the-age-of-the-essay/</guid>
      <description>The Age of the Essay. Paul Graham. http://www.paulgraham.com/essay.html. Sept 2004.  An essay is something that you write to try and figure out something. By definition, you can&#39;t begin with a statement.
Expressing ideas helps you form them. Writing something that others might read forces you to think well.
Think of the essay as an idea graph. At each node, contrary to Geoffrey&#39;s Principle of Least Astonishment for UIs, branch out to the most interesting related idea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About c13u</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m Chege Gitau. I was born and raised in Kenya. My hobbies include basketball, video games, reading books &amp;amp; blogs and drinking plain milk.
I blog because it helps me improve my clarity. It also reminds me that I have something worth saying. I envision my posts taking the form of interesting questions. More often than not, my training as a computer scientist will avail tools to help me answer those questions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>