<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on c13u&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.c13u.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on c13u&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.c13u.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Investing in Capital Markets</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/investing/investing-in-kenya/2019-12-24-capital-markets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/investing/investing-in-kenya/2019-12-24-capital-markets/</guid>
      <description>The Stock Market To trade in the NSE, open a CDS account with a CDA (some commercial banks, stockbrokers, investment banks).
In 2006, an Automatic Trading System was introduced so that orders are matched automatically and executed by stockbrokers on a first-come first-served basis. Govt bonds have also been added to the ATS. Securities lending, short-selling and same day turnaround trades are not yet permitted. (kestrelcapital.com)
I guess that&#39;s why quant funds are not a thing in Kenya.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investment Vehicles in Kenya</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/investing/investing-in-kenya/2019-12-24-investment-vehicles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/investing/investing-in-kenya/2019-12-24-investment-vehicles/</guid>
      <description>Investing through Groups (Chamas) www.kaig.org has developed a Chama Handbook to boost accountability and profitability.
But chamas have a higher chance of being guided by friendships than profitability. For instance, how do I go about picking a chama? It&#39;s most likely a referral from a friend who&#39;s already in a chama.
  Kenya USA Diaspora Sacco  Mavuno Term Deposit pays 8% interest for &amp;gt;1m KES and &amp;lt;2m KES deposited for a year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Curious Case of African ETFs</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/investing/investing-in-kenya/2019-12-24-the-curious-case-of-african-etfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/investing/investing-in-kenya/2019-12-24-the-curious-case-of-african-etfs/</guid>
      <description> etfdb.com has ETFs tracking regions. Surprised that Kenya isn&#39;t on it. And they&#39;re all losing money - best (over 5 years) is SA at -14.59%, Nigeria is at -64%.   Why all the PR on Africa being the next big investment scene?  Of course, Kenya&#39;s the premier investment destination (invest.go.ke)   Am I reading this right?? SOXL (semiconductors) ETF has &amp;gt;700% return over 5 years etfdb.com    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Top 10 Tracks</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/autogenerated/top-10-tracks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/autogenerated/top-10-tracks/</guid>
      <description>   RankTrackArtistChange   {% for track in site.data.top_songs %}  {{ track.rank }} {{ track.track_name }} {{ track.artist_name }} {% if track.rank_delta  0 %} &amp;#9650; {{ track.rank_delta }} {% elsif track.rank_delta &amp;#9660; {{ track.rank_delta | abs }} {% elsif track.rank_delta == 0 %}  -  {% else %} New!  {% endif %}  {% endfor %}  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cards from 03 Oct, 2019 to 20 Oct, 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/autogenerated/2019-10-20-flashcards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/autogenerated/2019-10-20-flashcards/</guid>
      <description>These set of flashcards can all be viewed at cards.c13u.com/browse . I own the site and I guarantee no funny business. It&#39;s more convenient for me to send you there than to replicate the contents on this page. Hope you find something interesting!   Elementary Operations on a System of Linear Equations?     What is a system of linear equations? What elementary operations are there on such a system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cards from 01 Sep, 2019 to 03 Oct, 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/autogenerated/2019-10-03-flashcards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/autogenerated/2019-10-03-flashcards/</guid>
      <description>These set of flashcards can all be viewed at cards.c13u.com/browse . I own the site and I guarantee no funny business. It&#39;s more convenient for me to send you there than to replicate the contents on this page. Hope you find something interesting!   Hidden Costs of Item Deletion in C++     Why is the first method less efficient than the second one in C++?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cards from 04 Aug, 2019 to 01 Sep, 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/autogenerated/2019-09-01-flashcards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/autogenerated/2019-09-01-flashcards/</guid>
      <description>These set of flashcards can all be viewed at cards.c13u.com/browse . I own the site and I guarantee no funny business. It&#39;s more convenient for me to send you there than to replicate the contents on this page. Hope you find something interesting!   The Multiverse Theory     Why do some cosmologists think that creation of an infinite space happens an infinite number of times? What are the consequences of an infinite multiverse?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Search of Influential Academic Publications</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/blog/2019-06-16-most-important-papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/blog/2019-06-16-most-important-papers/</guid>
      <description>I recently downloaded citations data from  Aminer  . I seek interesting papers to read during my free time [note]. The database has the following structure:   Table Columns Remarks   papers paper_id, title, venue, year, number of citations, abstract 3,079,007 papers from 1936 to 2018   authors name, appearance order, paper_id 1,766,547 distinct names (out of 9,476,165 names)   paper_references paper_id, cited_paper_id 25,166,994 references     Approach 1: Citation Count  For one, we can answer that with a SQL query: SELECT papers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Stuff On the Internet (#1)</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/blog/2018-08-30-random-walk-on-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/blog/2018-08-30-random-walk-on-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>(April 2018) An Apology for the Internet 
Remember &amp;lsquo;Seasons in the Sun&amp;rsquo;? I thought it was Westlife&#39;s but turns out Terry Jacks is the real owner. Combine that melody and some witty criticism of current technological trends and you get Joy of Tech&#39;s comic. Cheers to more cat memes in the sun. Also, relevant XKCD!
Burrito Time by Dos Toros As much as I advocate for not being glued to the phone, it&#39;s hard to hate the brilliant marketing: one notification sent every day at a random time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About c13u</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m Chege Gitau. I was born and raised in Kenya. My hobbies include basketball, video games, reading books &amp;amp; blogs and drinking plain milk.
I blog because it helps me improve my clarity. It also reminds me that I have something worth saying. I envision my posts taking the form of interesting questions. More often than not, my training as a computer scientist will avail tools to help me answer those questions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>