<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>www.nytimes.com on Chege's Blog</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/domains/www.nytimes.com/</link><description>Recent content in www.nytimes.com on Chege's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.curiosities.dev/domains/www.nytimes.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bad Blood [Book]</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/</guid><description>Bad Blood: Secrets and Lies in a Silicon Valley Startup. Carreyrou, John. May 21, 2018. ISBN: 9781524731663 . Theranos shocked me. Before joining uni, Holmes was a role model to me - she was going to make it big despite being so young. Part of me wants to understand that she wasn&amp;rsquo;t a villain through and through. Maybe she was an inventor who built magnificent castles on a foundation of sand.</description></item><item><title>Tracking and Data Collection</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/cos432-information-security/14-privacy/02-tracking-and-data-collection/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/cos432-information-security/14-privacy/02-tracking-and-data-collection/</guid><description>Tracking on the Internet Screenshot from a 2012 study of third-party online tracking. The red boxes show content (at least the visible ones) served by third parties.
When the browser requests a third-party resource embedded on a web page, the snippet below is a subset of the HTTP headers sent by the browser to the third party.
GET http://youtube.com/watch?v=gHStnhGx1P Cookie: id=35c192bcfe0000b1... Referer: http://www.nytimes.com/ The combination of the cookie and the referrer makes third-party tracking possible.</description></item><item><title>Thoughts on Academic Research</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/knowing/2021-06-15-on-academic-research/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/knowing/2021-06-15-on-academic-research/</guid><description>Going to a talk is difficult for everyone because nobody understands the whole thing, but it&amp;rsquo;s especially difficult for undergraduates because they still expect to.
is a rich resource for understanding scholarly literature. Browse it. Some of the listed items are familiar, e.g. Google Scholar, SCImago, Sci-Hub, but it&amp;rsquo;d be informative to zoom out to the larger picture, e.g. good alternatives to Google Scholar.
Why Even Read Papers?</description></item><item><title>Wall Street Potpourri</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/2021-01-30-potpurri/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/2021-01-30-potpurri/</guid><description>Maximizing the Value for Shareholders Suing a company for not following its code of ethics and therefore misleading investors doesn&amp;rsquo;t fly, but Signet Jewelers settled for $240m . Signet&amp;rsquo;s 70k female employees sued for discrimination, but the class action is yet to be resolved.
Tom Toro&amp;rsquo;s New Yorker cartoon : Yes, the planet got destroyed. But for a beautiful moment in time we created a lot of value for shareholders.</description></item><item><title>Health Ethics</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/2020-05-02-health-ethics/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/2020-05-02-health-ethics/</guid><description>Harden, a liberal behavior geneticist, is publishing a book, &amp;ldquo;The Genetic Lottery: Why DNA Matters for Social Equality&amp;rdquo;. Watch this space as it casts doubt on prevailing social justice thesis that environmental factors, and not genetics, influence behavior or social outcomes.
Check back in Sept 2022 (one year from now).
Faster Human Trials In 1986, AZT (AIDS treatment) showed 1/145 deaths compared to the placebo&amp;rsquo;s 16/137. 6,000 AIDS patients were offered AZT, helping it get to the public much faster.</description></item><item><title>Facebook to Pay $550 Million to Settle Facial Recognition Suit</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/www/the-battle-for-the-web/2020-01-29-fb-550m-fine-for-facial-recognition/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/www/the-battle-for-the-web/2020-01-29-fb-550m-fine-for-facial-recognition/</guid><description>Facebook to Pay $550 Million to Settle Facial Recognition Suit. Natasha Singer; Mike Isaac. www.nytimes.com . Jan 29, 2020. Illinois' biometric privacy law requires companies to obtain written permission before collecting a person’s biometrics. Residents have the right to sue for up to $5,000 per violation.
Facebook&amp;rsquo;s Tag Suggestions harvested facial data without getting written consent nor telling Illinois users for how long the data would be kept.</description></item><item><title>On DNA Testing</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/2018-09-18-on-dna-testing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/2018-09-18-on-dna-testing/</guid><description>The human genome has sequences of nucleotide base pairs that are repeated over and over again. At each locus of interest, a person has two sets of repeats inherited from each parent. Each possible difference at a locus is an allele. The combinations of the possible differences at multiple loci form a DNA profile that can be used to tie suspects to a crime scene.
The Accuracy of DNA Testing is Wanting 74/108 crime labs erroneously incriminated a suspect during a mock study.</description></item></channel></rss>