<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Part II: How the Pros Play the Biggest Game in Town on Chege&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/malkiel-a-random-walk-down-wall-street/part-2-how-the-pros-play-the-biggest-game-in-town/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Part II: How the Pros Play the Biggest Game in Town on Chege&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.curiosities.dev/business/malkiel-a-random-walk-down-wall-street/part-2-how-the-pros-play-the-biggest-game-in-town/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>05. Technical and Fundamental Analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/malkiel-a-random-walk-down-wall-street/part-2-how-the-pros-play-the-biggest-game-in-town/malkiel-05-technical-and-fundamental-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/malkiel-a-random-walk-down-wall-street/part-2-how-the-pros-play-the-biggest-game-in-town/malkiel-05-technical-and-fundamental-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Fundamental analysis applies the firm-foundation theory to the selection of individual stocks.
Technical Analysis Study past price movements and trading volume of trading to to predict when to buy/sell a stock. Based on the castle-in-the-air view of stock pricing.
What Can Charts Tell You? Principles of Technical Analysis   All information about earnings, dividends, and the future performance of a company is automatically reflected in the company’s past market prices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06. Technical Analysis and the Random Walk Theory</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/malkiel-a-random-walk-down-wall-street/part-2-how-the-pros-play-the-biggest-game-in-town/malkiel-06-technical-analysis-and-the-random-walk-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/malkiel-a-random-walk-down-wall-street/part-2-how-the-pros-play-the-biggest-game-in-town/malkiel-06-technical-analysis-and-the-random-walk-theory/</guid>
      <description>Is There Momentum in the Stock Market? Past stock prices cannot be used reliably to foretell future movements. Furthermore, transactions costs and taxes make it hard to exploit any short-term momentum.
Flip a fair coin many times. Sequences of heads (or tails) and jumbled up sequences occur with equal probability.
Just What Exactly is a Random Walk? In a random walk, knowing all prior moves is no help in predicting the next move.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>07. How Good is Fundamental Analysis? The Efficient Market Hypothesis</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/malkiel-a-random-walk-down-wall-street/part-2-how-the-pros-play-the-biggest-game-in-town/malkiel-07-how-good-is-fundamental-analysis-the-emh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/malkiel-a-random-walk-down-wall-street/part-2-how-the-pros-play-the-biggest-game-in-town/malkiel-07-how-good-is-fundamental-analysis-the-emh/</guid>
      <description>Fundamentalists tout past earnings growth as a most reliable indicator of future growth. But academics have shown that past earnings growth are no help in predicting future growth.
Why is the Crystal Ball So Clouded?  Many of the influential changes that affect earnings prospects are unpredictable. Creative accounting procedures produce dubious reported earnings, e.g. pro forma earnings, pushing due payments to future years, etc. Analysts may make errors, e.g. over-estimating the market size.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
