<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bad Blood [Book] on c13u&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bad Blood [Book] on c13u&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>00. Prologue</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/00-prologue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/00-prologue/</guid>
      <description>Holmes had an all-star team: Larry Ellison&#39;s mentor as Chair, Associate Dean of Stanford&#39;s School of Engineering, 30 years IBM experience, 25 years pharma and biotech experience, Panasonic&#39;s chip-making subsidiary head&amp;hellip;
Fraud or not, this is a sick lineup! How could she mess this up?
  Big Pharma spends tens of $B on clinical trials each year. Theranos would enable them to adjust dosage and save 30%. Holmes insisted on revising financial projections upward - assuming all (15+) deals came through - to $1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>01. A Purposeful Life</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/01-a-purposeful-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/01-a-purposeful-life/</guid>
      <description>Holmes wanted to be a billionaire since childhood. Her parents were from wealth, with medical and military folk. Holmes attended Houston&#39;s most prestigious private school. She spoke her way into Stanford&#39;s Mandarin program, while still in high school. Parents insisted on living a purposeful life.
Worked in lab during school year. Freshman internship at Genome Institute of Singapore: nasal swabs and syringes. There had to be a better way.
Ah, the transformative experience abroad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02. The Gluebot</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/02-the-gluebot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/02-the-gluebot/</guid>
      <description>Holmes insisted on using just a prick of blood. Problem: unreproducible results. A miniaturized catridge made storing and using the reagents hard.
You can&#39;t Steve Jobs your way through medical devices. But you can&#39;t change the world by being cynical.
  Costs. Each cartridge cost +$200 to make and was single use. Holmes even purchased a $2m automated packaging line.
Control of Information. The biochemists and the engineers reported up to Holmes and weren&#39;t encouraged to communicate with each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03. Apple Envy</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/03-apple-envy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/03-apple-envy/</guid>
      <description>Holmes&#39;s Grand Plans. The iPod of health care. Build a personal disease map; reverse engineer cancer and predict evolution of tumors.
Again, if she&#39;s faking this belief, then its sociopathic. But maybe she thought she could do it. Inventors go where no one else dares. They&#39;re ridiculed by society. Here&#39;s to the crazy ones. The misfits. The rebels. The troublemakers.
  Chat ports were blocked to protect proprietary information and trade secrets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04. Goodbye East Paly</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/04-goodbye-east-paly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/04-goodbye-east-paly/</guid>
      <description>For some terminated employees, Holmes requested a dossier on them for leverage. Mosley (finance guy) had stored porn on his work laptop. Holmes (retroactively) used that as the cause for his termination and lack of stock options.
Matt (IT) wanted to leave to start IT consulting firm. Holmes asking him to use ununionized (mob controlled) movers for a last minute move from East Paly was one of the final straws. Holmes tried asking Matt&#39;s peer to build dossier in exchange for Matt&#39;s position, but they declined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05. The Childhood Neighbor</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/05-the-childhood-neighbor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/05-the-childhood-neighbor/</guid>
      <description>Money was a sore point in the Holme&#39;s household. Holmes&#39;s grandparents had squandered away their share of the Fleischmann fortune. Richard Fuisz, a family friend, was a flashy successful businessman.
So in a way, Elizabeth didn&#39;t grow up in wealth? This puts a spin on Chapter 01: A Purposeful Life.
  Fuisz was offended that Elizabeth never consulted him. Fuisz made his money patenting medical inventions that he anticipated other companies would someday want.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06. Sunny</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/06-sunny/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/06-sunny/</guid>
      <description>Elizabeth met Sunny in Stanford&#39;s Mandarin program. She was 18, he was 19 years older and married. Elizabeth had struggled and gotten bullied and Sunny helped her out.
Sunny was arrogant and demeaning to employees. Sunny was a sucker for #hours clocked in. 8 hours a day showed a lack of dedication. But Elizabeth had utmost confidence in him.
That Sunny (COO) and Elizabeth (CEO) were dating wasn&#39;t disclosed to the board.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>07. Dr. J</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/07-dr-j/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/07-dr-j/</guid>
      <description>FB&#39;s private valuation had doubled to $50b in 6 months. &amp;lsquo;Angry Birds&amp;rsquo; showed an app could be a business. Low interest rates made hedge funds consider private startups.
Walgreens Dr. J - Walgreens Innovation. Theranos tests could boost revenues. Walgreens agrees to prepurchase $50m of cartridges and loan Theranos $25m.
Walgreens: we can&#39;t risk a scenario where CVS has a deal with them in 6 months and it ends up being real.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>08. The miniLab</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/08-minilab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/08-minilab/</guid>
      <description>The miniLab, 4S for short, stemmed from the need for a device that could perform more than just one class of tests. Theranos value prop was now minituarization, as opposed to invention. Current blood analyzers used too much blood and did too few tests.
Kent, de-facto Chief Architect of the miniLab, had raised $215k on Kickstarter for his bike lights side project. Elizabeth and Sunny wanted the patent to be transferred to Theranos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>09. The Wellness Play</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/09-the-wellness-play/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/09-the-wellness-play/</guid>
      <description>Safeway was doing poorly. Burd teased with a &amp;lsquo;wellness play&amp;rsquo;. He expected the clinics&amp;rsquo; to recoup the $350m renovation costs. Testing and rewarding employees would reduce Safeway&#39;s health care costs.
Theranos would courier samples to Palo Alto for testing. Theranos used a lancet on the index finger AND the good old hypodermic needle to the arm. The results could take 2 weeks as opposed to near-instantaneous. Theranos&#39;s results tended to be way off, unless they had been outsourced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10. Who Is LTC Shoemaker?</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/10-who-is-ltc-shoemaker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/10-who-is-ltc-shoemaker/</guid>
      <description>Elizabeth had successfully pitched to James Mattis, 4-star General, about deploying Theranos in Afghanistan. General Mattis was known to look out for his troops.
Elizabeth&#39;s plan around regulation - the real blood analysis would be beamed to California to be done by professionals; only the CLIA compliance for the Palo Alto lab was needed - no FDA.
Lt. Col. Shoemaker, responsible for the army&#39;s compliance with medical regulations, was openly critical of the Theranos&amp;rsquo; workaround.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>