<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bad Blood [Book] on c13u&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bad Blood [Book] on c13u&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>00. Prologue</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/00-prologue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/00-prologue/</guid>
      <description>Holmes had an all-star team: Larry Ellison&#39;s mentor as Chair, Associate Dean of Stanford&#39;s School of Engineering, 30 years IBM experience, 25 years pharma and biotech experience, Panasonic&#39;s chip-making subsidiary head&amp;hellip;
Fraud or not, this is a sick lineup! How could she mess this up?
  Big Pharma spends tens of $B on clinical trials each year. Theranos would enable them to adjust dosage and save 30%. Holmes insisted on revising financial projections upward - assuming all (15+) deals came through - to $1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>01. A Purposeful Life</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/01-a-purposeful-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/01-a-purposeful-life/</guid>
      <description>Holmes wanted to be a billionaire since childhood. Her parents were from wealth, with medical and military folk. Holmes attended Houston&#39;s most prestigious private school. She spoke her way into Stanford&#39;s Mandarin program, while still in high school. Parents insisted on living a purposeful life.
Worked in lab during school year. Freshman internship at Genome Institute of Singapore: nasal swabs and syringes. There had to be a better way.
Ah, the transformative experience abroad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02. The Gluebot</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/02-the-gluebot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/02-the-gluebot/</guid>
      <description>Holmes insisted on using just a prick of blood. Problem: unreproducible results. A miniaturized catridge made storing and using the reagents hard.
You can&#39;t Steve Jobs your way through medical devices. But you can&#39;t change the world by being cynical.
  Costs. Each cartridge cost +$200 to make and was single use. Holmes even purchased a $2m automated packaging line.
Control of Information. The biochemists and the engineers reported up to Holmes and weren&#39;t encouraged to communicate with each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03. Apple Envy</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/03-apple-envy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/03-apple-envy/</guid>
      <description>Holmes&#39;s Grand Plans. The iPod of health care. Build a personal disease map; reverse engineer cancer and predict evolution of tumors.
Again, if she&#39;s faking this belief, then its sociopathic. But maybe she thought she could do it. Inventors go where no one else dares. They&#39;re ridiculed by society. Here&#39;s to the crazy ones. The misfits. The rebels. The troublemakers.
  Chat ports were blocked to protect proprietary information and trade secrets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04. Goodbye East Paly</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/04-goodbye-east-paly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/carreyrou-bad-blood/04-goodbye-east-paly/</guid>
      <description>For some terminated employees, Holmes requested a dossier on them for leverage. Mosley (finance guy) had stored porn on his work laptop. Holmes (retroactively) used that as the cause for his termination and lack of stock options.
Matt (IT) wanted to leave to start IT consulting firm. Holmes asking him to use ununionized (mob controlled) movers for a last minute move from East Paly was one of the final straws. Holmes tried asking Matt&#39;s peer to build dossier in exchange for Matt&#39;s position, but they declined.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>