<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>astralcodexten.substack.com on Chege&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/domains/astralcodexten.substack.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in astralcodexten.substack.com on Chege&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.curiosities.dev/domains/astralcodexten.substack.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Academic Research</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/knowing/2021-06-15-on-academic-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/knowing/2021-06-15-on-academic-research/</guid>
      <description>Going to a talk is difficult for everyone because nobody understands the whole thing, but it&amp;rsquo;s especially difficult for undergraduates because they still expect to. 
   is a rich resource for understanding scholarly literature. Browse it. Some of the listed items are familiar, e.g. Google Scholar, SCImago, Sci-Hub, but it&amp;rsquo;d be informative to zoom out to the larger picture, e.g. good alternatives to Google Scholar.
  Why Even Read Papers?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fables in Service of Capitalism</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/optimism_and_deception/not-a-story-the-capitalists-would-tell-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/optimism_and_deception/not-a-story-the-capitalists-would-tell-you/</guid>
      <description>Environmentalism Over the last 70 years, less than 10% of plastic waste has been recycled - it&amp;rsquo;s uneconomical. Recycling shifts attention from the environmental impact of plastics and their overproduction to the consumer&amp;rsquo;s willingness to recycle. Reducing and reusing is a much better environmental strategy. 
Betting (and Gambling) I&amp;rsquo;m seeing more prominent gambling sites and ads compared to when I was growing up. Based on my peers, SportPesa made lots of headway in Kenya (few companies can claim to sponsor English Premier League teams).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Learning</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/knowing/2020-05-02-on-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/knowing/2020-05-02-on-learning/</guid>
      <description>Mental Attitude While Learning Distinguish Mere Facts From Conclusions or Opinions Discriminate between mere statements of facts, necessary conclusions which follow therefrom, and mere opinions which they seem to render reasonable. There&amp;rsquo;s no need to perform an experiment to verify that the atomic weight of oxygen is 16. That the sum of the angles of a plane triangle equals two right angles is not a mere fact, but an inevitable truth.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
