<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>astralcodexten.substack.com on Chege&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/domains/astralcodexten.substack.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in astralcodexten.substack.com on Chege&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.curiosities.dev/domains/astralcodexten.substack.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Academic Research</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/knowing/2021-06-15-on-academic-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/knowing/2021-06-15-on-academic-research/</guid>
      <description>Going to a talk is difficult for everyone because nobody understands the whole thing, but it&amp;rsquo;s especially difficult for undergraduates because they still expect to. 
   is a rich resource for understanding scholarly literature. Browse it. Some of the listed items are familiar, e.g. Google Scholar, SCImago, Sci-Hub, but it&amp;rsquo;d be informative to zoom out to the larger picture, e.g. good alternatives to Google Scholar.
  How to Read a Paper  The First Pass (5 - 10 min) Objectives: category, context, validity of assumptions, contributions and quality of writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fables in Service of Capitalism</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/optimism_and_deception/not-a-story-the-capitalists-would-tell-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/optimism_and_deception/not-a-story-the-capitalists-would-tell-you/</guid>
      <description>Over the last 70 years, less than 10% of plastic waste has been recycled - it&amp;rsquo;s uneconomical. Recycling shifts attention from the environmental impact of plastics and their overproduction to the consumer&amp;rsquo;s willingness to recycle. Reducing and reusing is a much better environmental strategy. 
Slots are increasingly designed for addiction, e.g. quick simple games, adding &amp;ldquo;near misses&amp;rdquo;, more ways to win (and therefore more &amp;ldquo;near misses&amp;rdquo; if one doesn&amp;rsquo;t bet on the additional ways), losses disguised as wins, random but weighted outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Learning</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/knowing/2020-05-02-on-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/knowing/2020-05-02-on-learning/</guid>
      <description>On &amp;ldquo;Doing Your Research&amp;rdquo; Of late, the phrase &amp;ldquo;do your research&amp;rdquo; has been popular , with some pushing back claiming that lay people tend to entrench their initial opinions and should defer to the consensus of scientific experts . How does one spot the scientific consensus?
Maybe by surveying the publications   of the relevant field. Indexing and abstracting services provide abstracts of publications and references to documents , and may thus prove useful.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
