<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Privacy on c13u&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.c13u.com/tags/privacy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Privacy on c13u&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.c13u.com/tags/privacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The New York Times Sells Premium Ads Based on How an Article Makes You Feel [Poynter]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2019-04-10-nyt-sells-ads-based-on-how-an-article-makes-you-feel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2019-04-10-nyt-sells-ads-based-on-how-an-article-makes-you-feel/</guid>
      <description>The New York Times Sells Premium Ads Based on How an Article Makes You Feel. Rick Edmonds. Poynter. https://www.poynter.org/business-work/2019/the-new-york-times-sells-premium-ads-based-on-how-an-article-makes-you-feel/. 2019-04-10.  The NYT piloted ad placements based on the emotions certain articles evoke.
The average lift to an ad is 40% NYT can charge more for those ads.
Will the newsroom be tasked with producing lots of emotional stories? NYT&#39;s claims:
 The newsroom turned out plenty of emotionally charged stories, anyhow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Monetizing Encrypted Messaging by Analyzing Metadata [Twitter]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2019-01-25-fb-monetizing-encrypted-messages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2019-01-25-fb-monetizing-encrypted-messages/</guid>
      <description>Facebook Monetizing Encrypted Messaging by Analyzing Metadata. @SarahJamieLewis. https://twitter.com/SarahJamieLewis/status/1088914192847917056. 2019-01-25.  Claim: FB will track relationships and social groups and make that information accessible to law enforcement. FB is a corporation that needs to make money; surveillance makes them money.
Contention: Actual privacy and security must protect metadata as well as content.
Cwtch by OpenPrivacy aims to minimize metadata exposed by apps used. It&#39;s built on Tor. Challenges: message latency, server reliability &amp;amp; discovery, (online) first contact problem for key exchange.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Apology for the Internet - How It Went Wrong [Intelligencer]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2018-04-16-an-apology-for-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2018-04-16-an-apology-for-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>An Apology for the Internet - How It Went Wrong. Noah Kulwin. NY Mag. http://nymag.com/intelligencer/2018/04/an-apology-for-the-internet-from-the-people-who-built-it.html. 2018-04-16.  Start with hippie good intentions. A generation embracing new technology as a tool to transform the world for good.
 Can Duruk: You were going to Facebook not to work but to make the world more open and connected.  Mix in capitalism on steroids. To save the world, you first need to take it over.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>