<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>git-scm.com on Chege's Blog</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/domains/git-scm.com/</link><description>Recent content in git-scm.com on Chege's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.curiosities.dev/domains/git-scm.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>06. Version Control (Git)</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/the-missing-cs-semester/06-version-control-git/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/the-missing-cs-semester/06-version-control-git/</guid><description>Version Control Systems track changes to a folder and its contents in a series of snapshots. Each snapshot encapsulates the entire state of files/folders within a top-level directory.
Git&amp;rsquo;s interface is a leaky abstraction. While the interface is at times ugly, its underlying design and ideas are beautiful. A bottom-up explanation of Git therefore makes more sense.
The abstraction is leaky in the sense that to wield it effectively, the user must understand the underlying data model, e.</description></item><item><title>Testing in a Monorepo</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/programming-challenges/flashcards-app/testing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/programming-challenges/flashcards-app/testing/</guid><description>Testing Web Components While any test framework can work, it&amp;rsquo;s better to test web components in a browser environment because that&amp;rsquo;s where they&amp;rsquo;ll be used. Node-based frameworks would require too much shimming of DOM calls that&amp;rsquo;d make the tests unrepresentative. and are good options for browser-based testing.
is powered by ES-build, and so is the client-side of the app; let&amp;rsquo;s go down this path and see where it leads.</description></item><item><title>Software Engineering Journal Reviews</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/2022-01-16-swe-journal-reviews/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/2022-01-16-swe-journal-reviews/</guid><description>Formal Software Design Alloy is an open-source language and analyzer for software modeling. An Alloy model is a collection of constraints that describe a set of structures, e.g. all possible security configurations of a web application. Alloy&amp;rsquo;s tool, the Alloy Analyzer is a solver that takes the constraints of a model and finds structures that satisfy them.
📑 The Alloy Analyzer leverages a SAT solver, and this precludes Alloy from analyzing optimization problems.</description></item><item><title>[ToDo] Site Health</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/todo/site-health/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/todo/site-health/</guid><description>Things that make the personal website better, but are orthogonal to adding new content.
🟡 Achieve parity between .md and .html content files. Right now, the scripts treat .md as the identifier for site content, which means .html files lack full YAML.
🟡 Add a --augment_all parameter to src/augment_yaml.py. Useful when adding new augmentations that need to be applied to all files.
The current augment_yaml.py uses the changelist from git to determine which files need augmentation.</description></item></channel></rss>