<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Wilson, Greg on Chege's Blog</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/cited-authors/Wilson-Greg/</link><description>Recent content in Wilson, Greg on Chege's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.curiosities.dev/cited-authors/Wilson-Greg/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Software Design By Example: A Tool-Based Introduction with JavaScript</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/todo/computer-science/software-design-by-example-js/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/todo/computer-science/software-design-by-example-js/</guid><description>Software Design by Example. A Tool-Based Introduction with JavaScript. Greg Wilson. third-bit.com . Accessed Jan 20, 2026. Also contains exercises at the end of each chapter.
Systems Programming. List a directory. Callback functions. Anonymous functions. Select a set of files. Copying a set of files.
Asynchronous Programming. Manage async executions. How promises work. Chain operations. How real promises are different. Build tools with promises.</description></item><item><title>Software Design By Example: A Tool-Based Introduction with Python</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/todo/computer-science/software-design-by-example-python/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/todo/computer-science/software-design-by-example-python/</guid><description>Software Design by Example. A Tool-Based Introduction with Python. Greg Wilson. third-bit.com . Accessed Jan 20, 2026. Objects and Classes. What is a natural way to represent real-world &amp;ldquo;things&amp;rdquo; in code, and how can we organize that code so that it&amp;rsquo;s easier to understand, test, and extend?
Finding Duplicate Files. Comparing each file to others is unworkably slow for large sets of files. How about generating a short label that depends only on the file contents and comparing that instead?</description></item></channel></rss>