<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mirhoseini, Azalia on Chege's Blog</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/cited-authors/Mirhoseini-Azalia/</link><description>Recent content in Mirhoseini, Azalia on Chege's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.curiosities.dev/cited-authors/Mirhoseini-Azalia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CS 329A: Self-Improving AI Agents</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/todo/ai-and-machine-learning/cs329a-self-improving-ai-agents/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/todo/ai-and-machine-learning/cs329a-self-improving-ai-agents/</guid><description>Stanford CS329A | Self-Improving AI Agents. Azalia Mirhoseini; Aakanksha Chowdhery; Mert Yuksekgonul; Jon Saad-Falcon. cs329a.stanford.edu . Accessed Jul 11, 2025. Test-time Compute Scaling Large Language Monkeys: Scaling Inference Compute with Repeated Sampling Archon; An Architecture Search Framework for Inference-Time Techniques Scaling LLM Test-Time Compute Optimally Can Be More Effective Than Scaling Model Parameters Self-Improvement Techniques with Verifiers: Training Verifiers to Solve Math Word Problems Let&amp;rsquo;s Verify Step by Step Math-Shepherd: Verify and Reinforce LLMs Step-by-step Without Human Annotations Self-Improvement Techniques with RL Constitutional AI: Harmlessness from AI Feedback STaR: Bootstrapping Reasoning With Reasoning Beyond Human Data: Scaling Self-Training for Problem-Solving with Language Models Self-Improvement Techniques with Search Thinking Fast and Slow with Deep Learning and Tree Search Competitive-level Code Generation with AlphaCode AlphaCode 2 Technical Report Open-ended Agent Learning in the Era of Foundation Models The AI Scientist: Towards Fully Automated Open-Ended Scientific Discovery Automated Design of Agentic Systems Augmenting LLMs with Tool Use/Actions ReAct: Synergizing Reasoning and Acting in Language Models Toolformer: Language Models Can Teach Themselves to Use Tools RLEF: Grounding Code LLMs in Execution Feedback with Reinforcement Learning Planning and Multi-Step Reasoning Language Agent Tree Search Unifies Reasoning, Acting, and Planning in Language Models LLMs Still Can&amp;rsquo;t Plan; Can LRMs?</description></item></channel></rss>