<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>doi.org on Chege&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/domains/doi.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content in doi.org on Chege&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.curiosities.dev/domains/doi.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reviews of WWW Proceedings</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/www/2021-10-12-reviews-of-www-proceedings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/www/2021-10-12-reviews-of-www-proceedings/</guid>
      <description>32nd ACM Conference on Hypertext and Social Media (HT &amp;lsquo;21) Reconstructing Ireland&amp;rsquo;s Lost History through the Beyond 2022 Project  Aims to create a virtual 3-D reconstruction of the &amp;ldquo;Record Treasury&amp;rdquo; of the Public Record Office of Ireland in Dublin. The original one was destroyed in Ireland&amp;rsquo;s Civil War of 1922. Reassembling will use copies, transcripts and records scattered among archival partners.
The full text of  discusses challenges presented by the Beyond 2022 project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journal Reviews on Fairness</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/bias-and-fairness/2021-10-04-journal-reviews-on-fairness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/bias-and-fairness/2021-10-04-journal-reviews-on-fairness/</guid>
      <description>WWW &amp;lsquo;21: Proceedings of the Web Conference 2021 User-oriented Fairness in Recommendation  Showed that active users who only account for a small proportion enjoy much higher recommendation quality than the majority inactive users. They propose a re-ranking approach by adding constraints over the evaluation metrics.
There&amp;rsquo;s a subtlety here. Although the active users are the minority, the recommender considers them the majority as they are the ones providing a lot of the training data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Markets</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/trading-and-investing/2021-10-04-online-markets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/trading-and-investing/2021-10-04-online-markets/</guid>
      <description>WWW &amp;lsquo;21: Proceedings of the Web Conference 2021 REST: Relational Event-Driven Stock Trend Forecasting REST, an event-driven stock trend forecasting framework, that overcomes two limitations of existing event-driven models. Models the stock context, and learns the effect of event information on the stocks under different contexts. Constructs a stock graph and designs a new propagation layer to propagate the effect of event information from related stocks. 
The value of stock trend forecasting is not unanimous, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Dangers of Stochastic Parrots: Can Language Models Be Too Big? 🦜</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/bias-and-fairness/2021-03-03-on-the-dangers-of-stochastic-parrots/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/bias-and-fairness/2021-03-03-on-the-dangers-of-stochastic-parrots/</guid>
      <description>The paper is written in a period when NLP practitioners are producing bigger (# of parameters; size of training data) language models (LMs), and pushing the top scores on benchmarks.
  Environmental Risks Large LMs consume a lot of resources, e.g. training a single BERT base model on GPUs was estimated to use as much energy as a trans-American flight.
Marginalized communities are doubly punished. They are least likely to benefit from LMs, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On DNA Testing</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/2018-09-18-on-dna-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/2018-09-18-on-dna-testing/</guid>
      <description>The human genome has sequences of nucleotide base pairs that are repeated over and over again. At each locus of interest, a person has two sets of repeats inherited from each parent. Each possible difference at a locus is an allele. The combinations of the possible differences at multiple loci form a DNA profile that can be used to tie suspects to a crime scene. 
The Accuracy of DNA Testing is Wanting  74/108 crime labs erroneously incriminated a suspect during a mock study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gene-Free Model of Expertise</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/sports/epstein-sports-gene/01-gene-free-model-of-expertise/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/sports/epstein-sports-gene/01-gene-free-model-of-expertise/</guid>
      <description>Reaction Times are Overrated Elite athletes do not display superior reaction times to those of average people; most hover at 200ms.
However, games are played at speeds where 200ms is too slow, e.g. 100-mph baseballs, 130-mph tennis serves, etc.
A reaction time of less than 100ms is deemed a false start in track and field sprints. 
  Superior Perception Athletes outperformed novices when asked if there was a ball in a rapidly flashed slide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toward a Theory of Medical Fallibility</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/1976-01-01-toward-a-theory-of-medical-fallibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1976 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/1976-01-01-toward-a-theory-of-medical-fallibility/</guid>
      <description>Medical care is like the opposite of moving fast and breaking things. If it&amp;rsquo;s so taboo to admit error, then that could make errors more common because fewer people are learning from past errors.
  Norms for Scientific Activity and the Sources of Error &amp;ldquo;Science&amp;rdquo; is taken to mean &amp;ldquo;Natural Science&amp;rdquo;.
  Internal norms derive from a cognitive pursuit of science. They are:
 Focus on the central rather than the peripheral problems of the science in in question.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
