<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>github.com on Chege&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/domains/github.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in github.com on Chege&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.curiosities.dev/domains/github.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>02. The Subject</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/writing/the-new-strategy-of-style/02-subject-and-thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/writing/the-new-strategy-of-style/02-subject-and-thesis/</guid>
      <description>The Subject The number of words aren&amp;rsquo;t intuitive to me. Adults tend to read non-fiction at 238 words per minute.  So a good test for how appropriate a piece of writing is, &amp;ldquo;Can the writer cover X in N minutes?&amp;rdquo;
Hugo uses 213 WPM, while Medium uses 265 WPM, suggesting Medium has a bias for skimming over close reading. 
I wonder if a browser extension that rates the appropriateness of articles given their subject and their word count is a feasible/desirable thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03. Cross-Site Request Forgery (XSRF)</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/cos432-information-security/11-web-security/03-cross-site-request-forgery/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/cos432-information-security/11-web-security/03-cross-site-request-forgery/</guid>
      <description>Cross-site Request Forgery (XSRF) &amp;lt;img src=&amp;#34;http://bank.com/transfer?from=from_ID&amp;amp;to=to_ID&amp;amp;value=1000&amp;#34;&amp;gt; Because the user is logged in and has a cookie, the victim site trusts the user&amp;rsquo;s browser.
The attacker gets user/browser to execute command on victim site, e.g. request a link, post a form. The command has permanent effects.
A frame can navigate its immediate children. Why is it designed such that it can&amp;rsquo;t navigate its children too?
Consider a website with a login frame, where the user inputs passwords.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journal Reviews on Fairness</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/bias-and-fairness/2021-10-04-journal-reviews-on-fairness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/bias-and-fairness/2021-10-04-journal-reviews-on-fairness/</guid>
      <description>Meta Instead of changing the data or learners in multiple ways and then see if fairness improves,  postulate that the root causes of bias are the prior decisions that generated the training data. These affect (a) what data was selected, and (b) the labels assigned to the examples. They propose the \(\text{Fair-SMOTE}\) (Fair Synthetic Minority Over Sampling Technique) algorithm which (1) removes biased labels (via situation testing: if the model&amp;rsquo;s prediction for a data point changes once all of the data points&#39; protected attributes  are flipped, then that label is biased and the data point is discarded), and (2) rebalances internal distributions such that based on a protected attribute, examples are equal in both positive and negative classes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Vulnerabilities Introduced by Dependencies</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/2020-11-14-software-dependencies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/2020-11-14-software-dependencies/</guid>
      <description>Bloated Dependencies A bloated dependency is one which is packaged in the application binary, but is not needed to run the application.
There are two levels to this: (1) a source file declares a dependency on foo but never actually uses foo, and (2) the application as a whole never uses foo. An optimal de-bloating solution would first address (1) and then tackle (2).
Some languages may have better tooling than others when it comes to automatically de-bloating their dependencies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ML Usefulness to a Dev</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/machine-learning/ml-crash-course/ml-concepts/01-introduction-to-ml/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/machine-learning/ml-crash-course/ml-concepts/01-introduction-to-ml/</guid>
      <description>Link to Original Video   ML Usefulness to a Dev  Reduce time spent programming, e.g. manually crafted spellchecker with rules of thumb vs. feeding ML model some examples.  How many words are there in English? Is it hard to have a huge set of all the possible words? How do spellcheckers do it?
Hunspell is the most popular OSS , and it was being used by Chromium , but on Chromium for Windows, the Windows Spellcheck is used .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ML Usefulness to a Dev</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/machine-learning/perspectives-on-ml/gdev-intro-to-ml/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/machine-learning/perspectives-on-ml/gdev-intro-to-ml/</guid>
      <description>Link to Original Video   ML Usefulness to a Dev  Reduce time spent programming, e.g. manually crafted spellchecker with rules of thumb vs. feeding ML model some examples.  How many words are there in English? Is it hard to have a huge set of all the possible words? How do spellcheckers do it?
Hunspell is the most popular OSS , and it was being used by Chromium , but on Chromium for Windows, the Windows Spellcheck is used .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Socio-Economic Classes</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/socioeconomics/2020-07-04-socioeconomic-classes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/socioeconomics/2020-07-04-socioeconomic-classes/</guid>
      <description>On the Phenomenon of Bullshit Jobs  Capitalism is meant to eliminate bullshit jobs, yet layoffs tend to fall on people making, moving, fixing and maintaining things, but not on the salaried paper pushers that effectively work 15 hours a week.
​From a political standpoint, a happy productive population with free time on their hands is mortal to the ruling class. Moreover, work is considered a moral value in itself.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
