<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Optimism and Deception on Chege&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/optimism_and_deception/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Optimism and Deception on Chege&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.curiosities.dev/business/optimism_and_deception/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Is The Price Right?</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/optimism_and_deception/2021-01-24-is-the-price-right/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/optimism_and_deception/2021-01-24-is-the-price-right/</guid>
      <description>Motivated by the markup done by LensCrafters    Terms like &amp;ldquo;medical-grade&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;military-grade&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;organic&amp;rdquo; often make consumers over-estimate the products&#39; good qualities. Sometimes the test itself is too easy to pass.
For instance, &amp;ldquo;military-grade&amp;rdquo; comes from specs by the military to enable interchangeability between manufacturers. Saying something is military-grade without quoting some mil-spec, e.g. shock tests, is bogus.  
Costco Kirkland is more likely to be high quality because Costco demands it from the supplier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fables in Service of Capitalism</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/optimism_and_deception/not-a-story-the-capitalists-would-tell-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/optimism_and_deception/not-a-story-the-capitalists-would-tell-you/</guid>
      <description>Over the last 70 years, less than 10% of plastic waste has been recycled - it&amp;rsquo;s uneconomical. Recycling shifts attention from the environmental impact of plastics and their overproduction to the consumer&amp;rsquo;s willingness to recycle. Reducing and reusing is a much better environmental strategy. 
Slots are increasingly designed for addiction, e.g. quick simple games, adding &amp;ldquo;near misses&amp;rdquo;, more ways to win (and therefore more &amp;ldquo;near misses&amp;rdquo; if one doesn&amp;rsquo;t bet on the additional ways), losses disguised as wins, random but weighted outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AT&amp;T to pay $60m in settlement for slowing cellphone data on unlimited plans</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/optimism_and_deception/2019-11-05-att-pay-60m-in-settlement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/optimism_and_deception/2019-11-05-att-pay-60m-in-settlement/</guid>
      <description>AT&amp;amp;T to pay $60m in settlement for slowing cellphone data on unlimited plans.  https://www.reuters.com/article/us-at-t-settlement/att-will-pay-60-million-over-u-s-allegations-it-lied-in-unlimited-data-pledge-government-idUSKBN1XF26Q  . Nov 5, 2019.     Complaint filed in 2014 by the FTC: AT&amp;amp;T charged smartphone users for &amp;lsquo;unlimited&amp;rsquo; data plans, but throttled them after ~2GB within a month.
  AT&amp;amp;T: None of these allegations were ever proved in court. We were fully prepared to defend ourselves, but decided settling was in the best interests of consumers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Shady Economics of Buy-One-Get-One Free Deals [The Hustle]</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/optimism_and_deception/2019-02-17-shady-economics-of-buy-one-get-one-free-deals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/optimism_and_deception/2019-02-17-shady-economics-of-buy-one-get-one-free-deals/</guid>
      <description>The Shady Economics of Buy-One-Get-One Free Deals.  Zachary Crockett. https://thehustle.co/are-buy-one-get-one-free-deals-worth-it/  . Feb 17, 2019.   BOGO goods are usually low-demand, non-efficient, lacking in quality and/or close to the expiration date. The BOGO deal is usually a 50% discount off of the manufacturer’s suggested retail price (MSRP). And oftentimes, this price is artificially marked up to begin with.
 MyPillow offered BOGO deal on their pillows, but really just doubled the price of the first pillow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wolf that Tried to Play Nice [SoECS]</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/optimism_and_deception/2018-10-01-the-wolf-that-tried-to-play-nice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/optimism_and_deception/2018-10-01-the-wolf-that-tried-to-play-nice/</guid>
      <description>AT&amp;amp;T restricted FaceTime from running on some data plans. Justifications?
 FaceTime is preloaded, therefore 100% of users have it FaceTime wasn&amp;rsquo;t efficient in network usage. The capacity was asymmetrical, but video chat is symmetrical  Interestingly enough, AT&amp;amp;T required Apple to greenlight it, which they did. AT&amp;amp;T worked with top developers to teach network etiquette.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Submarine [Paul Graham]</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/optimism_and_deception/2005-04-01-the-submarine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/optimism_and_deception/2005-04-01-the-submarine/</guid>
      <description>The Submarine.  Paul Graham. http://www.paulgraham.com/submarine.html  . Apr 1, 2005.   Many people rely on social proof to form opinions; therein lies the power of PR.
PR firms are not dishonest for they need good reputation with news outlets. But PR firms serve overworked reporters with selective truths.
The firms feed the same story to different publications at once. Readers see similar stories in multiple places and assume a new trend has come.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
