<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Trading and Investing on Chege&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/trading-and-investing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Trading and Investing on Chege&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.curiosities.dev/trading-and-investing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Online Markets</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/trading-and-investing/2021-10-04-online-markets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/trading-and-investing/2021-10-04-online-markets/</guid>
      <description>WWW &amp;lsquo;21: Proceedings of the Web Conference 2021 REST: Relational Event-Driven Stock Trend Forecasting REST, an event-driven stock trend forecasting framework, that overcomes two limitations of existing event-driven models. Models the stock context, and learns the effect of event information on the stocks under different contexts. Constructs a stock graph and designs a new propagation layer to propagate the effect of event information from related stocks. 
The value of stock trend forecasting is not unanimous, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wall Street Potpourri</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/trading-and-investing/2021-01-30-potpurri/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/trading-and-investing/2021-01-30-potpurri/</guid>
      <description>Maximizing the Value for Shareholders Suing a company for not following its code of ethics and therefore misleading investors doesn&amp;rsquo;t fly, but Signet Jewelers settled for $240m . Signet&amp;rsquo;s 70k female employees sued for discrimination, but the class action is yet to be resolved. 
 Tom Toro&amp;rsquo;s New Yorker cartoon   : Yes, the planet got destroyed. But for a beautiful moment in time we created a lot of value for shareholders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Future of Corporate Governance Part I: The Problem of Twelve</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/trading-and-investing/2018-10-03-problem-of-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/trading-and-investing/2018-10-03-problem-of-12/</guid>
      <description>The Problem of Twelve: In the near future, roughly 12 individuals will have practical power over majority of US public companies.
A Short History of Corporations  In the first stage, entrepreneurs get money from savings, &amp;ldquo;friends, family, and fools&amp;rdquo;, and VCs. Securities law restricts this to sophisticated investors only.
On generating revenue and stability, the entrepreneur takes the firm public (IPO) under oversight from the SEC. Ownership is separated from control, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wall Street University: USD 101</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/trading-and-investing/2020-05-02-wall-street-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/trading-and-investing/2020-05-02-wall-street-101/</guid>
      <description>Short Selling  Say $A shares are selling at $100, but I think they&amp;rsquo;re overpriced. So I borrow 10 shares, pay my brokerage interest and post some collateral. I then sell the shares for $1,000.
Whoever buys my shares has no idea that I do not own them. In a naked short, I do not actually borrow or ensure that the security can be borrowed within the standard 3-day settlement period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Do People Invest in the US?</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/trading-and-investing/2019-12-24-how-people-invest-in-the-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/trading-and-investing/2019-12-24-how-people-invest-in-the-us/</guid>
      <description>Index Funds and 401(k) Accounts  I assume the return is ~5% There are 4 types of retirement accounts, each with tradeoffs (en.wikipedia.org)    401(k), Roth 401(k), Traditional IRA and Roth IRA   The return of lazy portfolios (set and forget) is ~6% (compounded) over 15 years as of 2018 (finpage.blog)     Notes from /r/investing&amp;rsquo;s FAQ (reddit.com)     The FAQ emphasizes reading books  I don&amp;rsquo;t see the urgency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are the Basic Ideas On Investing?</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/trading-and-investing/2019-12-24-basic-ideas-behind-investing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/trading-and-investing/2019-12-24-basic-ideas-behind-investing/</guid>
      <description>Things to invest in  (Least risk) Bonds, Stocks, Startups (Most Risk).  Why not start a business?    The Amount of Money  Some investments only make sense in bulk for they have low margins, e.g. stocks  The risk tolerance  The higher the risk, the higher the reward The law protects investors, e.g. startup investors in the US must be accredited  The Time Frame  Maybe 10 years?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Does a Market Work? [CS Colloquia]</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/trading-and-investing/2018-10-01-how-does-a-market-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/trading-and-investing/2018-10-01-how-does-a-market-work/</guid>
      <description>Objectives: low latency, high throughput &amp;amp; high reliability.
The messages are quite brief, e.g. the ITCH protocol uses 32 bytes per message.
Trading firm listens to broadcasts on buys, sells, deletes on ITCH broadcasts. Online sorting to identify profitable trades.
Matching engine operates on a first-come-first-served basis. Earlier orders with better price get traded first.
Markets run at 50 microsecond scales.
Single market peaks at 10Gbps. Peaks are correlated, e.g. &amp;ldquo;Shit!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Betting on Things That Never Change [Morgan Housel]</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/trading-and-investing/2017-07-20-betting-on-things-that-never-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/trading-and-investing/2017-07-20-betting-on-things-that-never-change/</guid>
      <description>Betting on Things That Never Change.  Morgan Housel. https://www.collaborativefund.com/blog/betting-on-things-that-never-change/  . Jul 20, 2017.   Change by itself is hard. Investors have to spot it before it&amp;rsquo;s obvious. Consumers have to change their behaviors to make it viable. These two points repel each other.
Sears bet the Internet changed nothing. Beenz bet the Internet changed everything - creating a points-based currency valid only at online merchants. Amazon bet the Internet changed distribution, but rooted its strategy in selection and low prices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Trade of the Century: When George Soros Broke the British Pound [Priceonomics]</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/trading-and-investing/2016-06-17-when-soros-broke-the-british-pound/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/trading-and-investing/2016-06-17-when-soros-broke-the-british-pound/</guid>
      <description>The Trade of the Century: When George Soros Broke the British Pound.  Rohin Dhar. https://priceonomics.com/the-trade-of-the-century-when-george-soros-broke/  . Jun 17, 2016.   Before the EU, Europe had the ERM to fix their exchange rates with the Deutschmark within 6% of the agreed upon rate.
Keeping the exchange rate fixed requires governments to nudge the rate, e.g.
 Use reserves of foreign currency to buy up their own currency Set high interest rates to entice lenders to buy their currency  Margaret Thatcher (PM) opposed the fixed exchange rates but lost the vote to Major, an ERM proponent.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
