<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book II: How to Actually Change Your Mind on c13u&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.c13u.com/knowing/yudkowsky-rationality/02-how-to-actually-change-your-mind/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book II: How to Actually Change Your Mind on c13u&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.c13u.com/knowing/yudkowsky-rationality/02-how-to-actually-change-your-mind/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Overly Convenient Excuses</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/knowing/yudkowsky-rationality/02-how-to-actually-change-your-mind/01-overly-convenient-excuses/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/knowing/yudkowsky-rationality/02-how-to-actually-change-your-mind/01-overly-convenient-excuses/</guid>
      <description>The Proper Use of Humility Confessing your fallibility but doing nothing about it braggery, not humility. Designing fail-safe machinery is good humility. Dismissing evidence for evolution because we can&#39;t really know for sure that evolution is correct is misplaced humility.
The Third Alternative Sometimes we justify questionable policy by claiming its absence is undesirable, e.g. believing in Santa makes children behave nicely, and therefore Santa-ism is the best of all possible alternatives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Against Rationalization</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/knowing/yudkowsky-rationality/02-how-to-actually-change-your-mind/03-against-rationalization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/knowing/yudkowsky-rationality/02-how-to-actually-change-your-mind/03-against-rationalization/</guid>
      <description>Gathering evidence IRL may be expensive. When picking a stopping point, ask whether the collected evidence compels the conclusion, not whether it allows the conclusion.
Check your motivations. Are you ignoring fast cheap evidence because you already have a comfortable conclusion? Are you holding out for expensive slow evidence because the conclusion is uncomfortable?
A probabilistic model can take a few hits. But we sometimes assume a true theory can have no failures and a false theory can have no success.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>