<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on c13u&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.c13u.com/categories/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on c13u&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.c13u.com/categories/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Signal Is Finally Bringing Its Secure Messaging To the Masses [Andy Greenberg]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/computer-science/2020-02-14-signal-secure-messaging-to-the-masses/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/computer-science/2020-02-14-signal-secure-messaging-to-the-masses/</guid>
      <description>Signal Is Finally Bringing Its Secure Messaging To the Masses. Andy Greenberg. https://www.wired.com/story/signal-encrypted-messaging-features-mainstream/. https://it.slashdot.org/story/20/02/14/2216214/signal-is-finally-bringing-its-secure-messaging-to-the-masses#comments. https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=22326731. 2020-02-14.  Attracting the Masses Brian Acton (WhatsApp cofounder) injected $50m into the Signal Foundation, allowing them to grow from 3 to 50 full-timers.
You&#39;d think that at Signal&#39;s dominance, getting $$$ shouldn&#39;t be a problem. But VCs expect a multiple return and Signal doesn&#39;t look like it will monetize soon.
  Signal has added support for iPad, ephemeral images and video, downloadable customizable &amp;ldquo;stickers,&amp;rdquo; and emoji reactions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dependencies and Maintainers [Drew DeVault]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/computer-science/2020-02-06-deps-and-maintainers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/computer-science/2020-02-06-deps-and-maintainers/</guid>
      <description>Dependencies and Maintainers. Drew DeVault. https://drewdevault.com/2020/02/06/Dependencies-and-maintainers.html. 2020-02-06.  Sample Crises in OSS left-pad: trivial library that was removed from npm and was unknowingly present in thousands of dependency graphs.
event-stream: maintainer transferred ownership to an unknown individual who added crypto mining
heartbleed, in which a bug in a critical security library caused mass upgrades and panic
DeVault&#39;s Take Asking how to prioritize attention, donations &amp;amp; patches for thousands of OSS library dependencies shouldn&#39;t be a problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t touch my clipboard [Alex Ellis]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/computer-science/2020-02-17-dont-touch-my-clipboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/computer-science/2020-02-17-dont-touch-my-clipboard/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;#39;t touch my clipboard: You can (but shouldn&amp;#39;t) change how people copy text from your website.. Alex Ellis. https://alexanderell.is/posts/taking-over-my-clipboard/. https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=22352674. 2020-02-17.  How much is too much? Complaint: author selected &amp;amp; copied an em dash ( - ) character from https://www.thepunctuationguide.com/em-dash.html, but here&#39;s what the site put into the clipboard:
— From https://www.thepunctuationguide.com/em-dash.html © 2020 thepunctuationguide.com There&#39;s a tradeoff between attribution and changing things outside a site&#39;s scope.
Apple&#39;s iBooks does this too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tech Startups Are Flooding Kenya With Apps Offering High-Interest Loans [Bloomberg]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/2020-02-12-high-interest-digital-loans-kenya/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/2020-02-12-high-interest-digital-loans-kenya/</guid>
      <description>Tech Startups Are Flooding Kenya With Apps Offering High-Interest Loans. Zeke Faux. Bloomberg New Economy. https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2020-02-12/tech-startups-are-flooding-kenya-with-apps-offering-high-interest-loans. https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=22307002.  Tala&#39;s Version of Events Empowering female entrepreneurs around the world - Mexico, Philippines, India &amp;amp; Kenya.
69% of global adult population is not covered by credit bureaus. Using non-traditional data, more people can get scored.
Credit brings opportunity and choice. We help people be in control of their finances.
The Situation on the Ground Tala generates credit ratings from phone data: text messages, location data, contacts, and call logs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook to Pay $550 Million to Settle Facial Recognition Suit [The New York Times]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/privacy/2020-01-29-fb-550m-fine-for-facial-recognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/privacy/2020-01-29-fb-550m-fine-for-facial-recognition/</guid>
      <description>Facebook to Pay $550 Million to Settle Facial Recognition Suit. Natasha Singer; Mike Isaac. The New York Times. https://www.nytimes.com/2020/01/29/technology/facebook-privacy-lawsuit-earnings.html. 2020-01-29.  Illinois&amp;rsquo; biometric privacy law requires companies to obtain written permission before collecting a person’s biometrics. Residents have the right to sue for up to $5,000 per violation.
Facebook&#39;s Tag Suggestions harvested facial data without getting written consent nor telling Illinois users for how long the data would be kept.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Third Base [Scott Galloway]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/people_affairs/socioeconomics/2019-12-13-galloway-third-base/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/people_affairs/socioeconomics/2019-12-13-galloway-third-base/</guid>
      <description>Third Base. Scott Galloway. No Mercy, No Malice. https://www.profgalloway.com/third-base/. 2019-12-13.  I don’t know much about physics but constantly reference Galileo despite knowing little besides the fact that he dared challenge the church.
:-) Dunning–Kruger Effect: a cognitive bias in which people assess their cognitive ability as greater than it is. (en.wikipedia.org)
  Masayoshi Son turned $20m into Alibaba into $100b. But he&#39;s mistaking luck in VC for his superior intuition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Hacker News) Must and Must Not: On Writing Documentation</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/writing/2019-12-09-hn-on-writing-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/writing/2019-12-09-hn-on-writing-documentation/</guid>
      <description>Must and Must Not: On Writing Documentation. Hacker News. https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21743100. Dec 9th, 2019.    Revise documentation, many times, on separate days. What seemed perfectly clear yesterday will come across as ambiguous/confusing today.
  Beware of ambiguities, especially those that bubble between native speakers and non-native ones e.g.
 &amp;ldquo;X may not do Y&amp;rdquo;  X possibly doesn&#39;t do Y It&#39;s strictly forbidden that X do Y   &amp;ldquo;X Must Not&amp;rdquo;  Not a must =&amp;gt; You don&#39;t have to, but you can It&#39;s strictly forbidden      Put yourself into different roles, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We ran the numbers, and there really is a pipeline problem in eng hiring. [interviewing.io]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2019-12-03-there-is-a-pipeline-problem-in-eng-hiring/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2019-12-03-there-is-a-pipeline-problem-in-eng-hiring/</guid>
      <description>We ran the numbers, and there really is a pipeline problem in eng hiring.. Aline Lerner. http://blog.interviewing.io/we-ran-the-numbers-and-there-really-is-a-pipeline-problem-in-eng-hiring/. https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21694348. 2019-12-03.  Wait, but research shows:
 STEM in early education is unfriendly to children from underrepresented backgrounds Lack of a level playing field and unequal access to quality STEM education Hostile university culture in male-dominated CS programs Biased hiring practices Non-inclusive work environments cause higher churn of underrepresented folk.  Systemic issues can be hard to fix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[SSC] Book Review: All Therapy Books</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/people_affairs/psychology/2019-11-20-ssc-all-therapy-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/people_affairs/psychology/2019-11-20-ssc-all-therapy-books/</guid>
      <description>Book Review: All Therapy Books. Scott Alexander. Slate Star Codex. https://slatestarcodex.com/2019/11/20/book-review-all-therapy-books/.  Scott&#39;s thesis: Each of the therapy books on their own can be convincing. But they should be taken in the context of All Therapy Books, which as a category are pretty worrying.
All psychotherapy books bring up the (controversial) Dodo Bird Verdict – All psychotherapies are about equally good, and the only things that matters are &amp;ldquo;nonspecific factors&amp;rdquo; like how much patients like their therapist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESG Stocks Are Graded on a Curve [Matt Levine]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/2019-11-11-esg-stocks-are-graded-on-a-curve/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/2019-11-11-esg-stocks-are-graded-on-a-curve/</guid>
      <description>ESG Stocks Are Graded on a Curve. Matt Levine. Money Stuff. https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2019-11-11/esg-stocks-are-graded-on-a-curve. 2019-11-11.  Investors often want (1) what they want plus (2) a label that validates what they want.
BlackRock designs its sustainable funds to match risk/return of broad market indexes while including the highest ESG-rated companies in each sector - the grading is on a curve.
8/10 of the biggest U.S. sustainable funds are invested in oil-and-gas companies (wsj.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The New Dot Com Bubble is Here: It’s Called Online Advertising [The Correspondent]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/2019-11-06-the-new-dotcom-bubble-is-online-advertising/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/2019-11-06-the-new-dotcom-bubble-is-online-advertising/</guid>
      <description>The New Dot Com Bubble is Here: It’s Called Online Advertising. The Correspondent. https://thecorrespondent.com/100/the-new-dot-com-bubble-is-here-its-called-online-advertising/13228924500-22d5fd24.  In 2018, $273b was spent on digital ads. But are ad platforms any good at manipulating us?
Tadelis, Econ Prof at UCB stint @ eBay: Consultants: paying for sponsored links for people that searched for &amp;lsquo;eBay&amp;rsquo; was a $245.6m return, not a $20m expense.
Selection Effect: What if the ad clickers were going to use eBay anyway?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AT&amp;T to pay $60m in settlement for slowing cellphone data on unlimited plans [Reuters]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/2019-11-05-att-pay-60m-in-settlement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/2019-11-05-att-pay-60m-in-settlement/</guid>
      <description>AT&amp;amp;T to pay $60m in settlement for slowing cellphone data on unlimited plans. Reuters. https://www.reuters.com/article/us-at-t-settlement/att-will-pay-60-million-over-u-s-allegations-it-lied-in-unlimited-data-pledge-government-idUSKBN1XF26Q.    Complaint filed in 2014 by the FTC: AT&amp;amp;T charged smartphone users for &amp;lsquo;unlimited&amp;rsquo; data plans, but throttled them after ~2GB within a month.
  AT&amp;amp;T: None of these allegations were ever proved in court. We were fully prepared to defend ourselves, but decided settling was in the best interests of consumers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The New York Times Sells Premium Ads Based on How an Article Makes You Feel [Poynter]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2019-04-10-nyt-sells-ads-based-on-how-an-article-makes-you-feel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2019-04-10-nyt-sells-ads-based-on-how-an-article-makes-you-feel/</guid>
      <description>The New York Times Sells Premium Ads Based on How an Article Makes You Feel. Rick Edmonds. Poynter. https://www.poynter.org/business-work/2019/the-new-york-times-sells-premium-ads-based-on-how-an-article-makes-you-feel/. 2019-04-10.  The NYT piloted ad placements based on the emotions certain articles evoke.
The average lift to an ad is 40% NYT can charge more for those ads.
Will the newsroom be tasked with producing lots of emotional stories? NYT&#39;s claims:
 The newsroom turned out plenty of emotionally charged stories, anyhow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standing Against Hate [Facebook]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2019-03-27-fb-standing-against-hate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2019-03-27-fb-standing-against-hate/</guid>
      <description>Standing Against Hate. https://about.fb.com/news/2019/03/standing-against-hate/. https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19503094. 2019-03-27.  Main Article We now ban praise, support and representation of white nationalism and separatism on FB and Instagram
We didn&#39;t ban them before because their broader concepts, e.g. American pride and Basque separatism, are an important part of people&#39;s identity.
Experts in race relations have confirmed that white nationalism and separatism cannot be meaningfully separated from white supremacy and organized hate groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Doesn’t Make Money Because It Isn’t Designed To Make Money [Ian Bicking]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/miscellaneous/2019-03-18-open-source-doesnt-make-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/miscellaneous/2019-03-18-open-source-doesnt-make-money/</guid>
      <description>Open Source Doesn’t Make Money Because It Isn’t Designed To Make Money. Ian Bicking. http://www.ianbicking.org/blog/2019/03/open-source-doesnt-make-money-by-design.html. 2019-03-18.  A [fallacious] Just World hypothesis: if something has utility, if it helps people, if it’s something the world needs, if it empowers other people, then there should be a revenue opportunity.
Classical scratch-your-own-itch open source software is built by programmers for programmers. And it is wildly successful, but it’s selling to people who aren’t willing to pay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Counterintuitive Competitive Advantages [Morgan Housel]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/on-starting-a-business/2019-03-13-counterintuitive-competitive-advantages/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/on-starting-a-business/2019-03-13-counterintuitive-competitive-advantages/</guid>
      <description>Counterintuitive Competitive Advantages. Morgan Housel. Collaborative Fund. https://www.collaborativefund.com/blog/counterintuitive-competitive-advantages/. 2019-03-13.  Growing big antlers requires lots of Ca and Ph, which are rare. Small antlers were required to survive low-food winters, but big antlers were required to impress females to mate. The Irish elk spiraled to extinction.
I get the analogy that Housel is trying to paint, but this seems like an oversimplification. Sure, big antlers are sexy, but if small antlers are all that&#39;s left on the menu, I doubt female antlers will think &amp;ldquo;pass&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Trauma Floor: The Secret Lives of FB Moderators in America [The Verge]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2019-02-25-the-secret-lives-of-fb-mods-in-america/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2019-02-25-the-secret-lives-of-fb-mods-in-america/</guid>
      <description>The Trauma Floor: The Secret Lives of FB Moderators in America. Casey Newton. The Verge. https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/25/18229714/cognizant-facebook-content-moderator-interviews-trauma-working-conditions-arizona. 2019-02-25.  Moderators in Phoenix will make just $28,800 per year — while the average FB employee has a total compensation of $240,000.
Team leaders micro-manage content moderators&amp;rsquo; every bathroom break. Two Muslim employees were ordered to stop praying during their 9min/day of allotted &amp;ldquo;wellness time&amp;rdquo;.
Employees can be fired after making just a handful of errors a week, and those who remain live in fear of former colleagues returning to seek vengeance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Shady Economics of Buy-One-Get-One Free Deals [The Hustle]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/2019-02-17-shady-economics-of-buy-one-get-one-free-deals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/2019-02-17-shady-economics-of-buy-one-get-one-free-deals/</guid>
      <description>The Shady Economics of Buy-One-Get-One Free Deals. Zachary Crockett. The Hustle. https://thehustle.co/are-buy-one-get-one-free-deals-worth-it/. 2019-02-17.  BOGO goods are usually low-demand, non-efficient, lacking in quality and/or close to the expiration date. The BOGO deal is usually a 50% discount off of the manufacturer’s suggested retail price (MSRP). And oftentimes, this price is artificially marked up to begin with.
 MyPillow offered BOGO deal on their pillows, but really just doubled the price of the first pillow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FB Under Pressure to Halt Rise of Anti-Vaccination Groups [The Guardian]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2019-02-12-fb-versus-antivaxx-groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2019-02-12-fb-versus-antivaxx-groups/</guid>
      <description>FB Under Pressure to Halt Rise of Anti-Vaccination Groups. Ed Pilkington, Jessica Glenza. The Guardian. https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2019/feb/12/facebook-anti-vaxxer-vaccination-groups-pressure-misinformation. 2019-02-12.  Vitamin C &amp;amp; Orthomolecular Medicine for Optimal Health. Closed Group. 49,000 approved members.
 Gironda, an admin, sells high-dose Vitamin C in bulk through Revitalize Wellness. The &amp;lsquo;shop now&amp;rsquo; button links to her firm. Revitalize Wellness carries a disclaimer saying that its products are “not intended to treat, diagnose, cure or prevent disease”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESG! The Meme [Epsilon Theory]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/2019-01-29-esg-the-meme/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/2019-01-29-esg-the-meme/</guid>
      <description>Kobayashi Maru. Epsilon Theory. https://www.epsilontheory.com/kobayashi-maru/. 2019-01-29.  Environmental, Social and Governance Investing. So general as to be meaningless: marketing BS (thinking &amp;lsquo;holistically&amp;rsquo; about ESG risk factors as part of the investment process) to impact investing (providing wholesale financing for community lending initiatives).
ESG! The meme is about selling portfolios as virtue signaling devices. It moves the conversation away from fees and performance to values. Don&#39;t you want to make a difference?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Monetizing Encrypted Messaging by Analyzing Metadata [Twitter]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/privacy/2019-01-25-fb-monetizing-encrypted-messages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/privacy/2019-01-25-fb-monetizing-encrypted-messages/</guid>
      <description>Facebook Monetizing Encrypted Messaging by Analyzing Metadata. @SarahJamieLewis. https://twitter.com/SarahJamieLewis/status/1088914192847917056. 2019-01-25.  Claim: FB will track relationships and social groups and make that information accessible to law enforcement. FB is a corporation that needs to make money; surveillance makes them money.
Contention: Actual privacy and security must protect metadata as well as content.
Cwtch by OpenPrivacy aims to minimize metadata exposed by apps used. It&#39;s built on Tor. Challenges: message latency, server reliability &amp;amp; discovery, (online) first contact problem for key exchange.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why are glasses so expensive? [LA Times]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/2019-01-22-why-are-glasses-so-expensive/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/2019-01-22-why-are-glasses-so-expensive/</guid>
      <description>Why are glasses so expensive? The eyewear industry prefers to keep that blurry. David Lazurus. LA Times. https://www.latimes.com/business/lazarus/la-fi-lazarus-why-are-eyeglasses-so-expensive-20190122-story.html. 2019-01-22.   Column: How badly are we being ripped off on eyewear? Former industry execs tell all. David Lazurus. LA Times. https://www.latimes.com/business/lazarus/la-fi-lazarus-glasses-lenscrafters-luxottica-monopoly-20190305-story.html. 2019-03-05.    Luxottica bought everyone. They set whatever prices they please.
 Luxottica owns and licenses Armani, Brooks Brothers, Burberry, Chanel, Coach, DKNY, Dolce &amp;amp; Gabbana, Michael Kors, Oakley, Oliver Peoples, Persol, Polo Ralph Lauren, Ray-Ban, Tiffany, Valentino, Vogue and Versace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Less Wrong) I Want It My Way</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/overly_convenient_excuses/2019-01-04-lw-i-want-it-my-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/overly_convenient_excuses/2019-01-04-lw-i-want-it-my-way/</guid>
      <description>I Want It My Way!. Nick Hayes. Less Wrong. https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/WiDh3ca3C7GgrNXAn/i-want-it-my-way. 4th Jan, 2019.  Letting go of how you think things should be lets you see how things are. Consequently, you&#39;ll be able to get better results.
Wanting it my way: I believe that failure is bad, and that if I fail, then I personally am I failure. So I have those two things conflated. Then anything I do risks failing, especially new things, so I&#39;d better not do the new things, then.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Probably Won&#39;t Make it to the Top [DHH]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/letting_go/2018-11-22-dhh-you-probably-wont-make-it-to-the-top/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/letting_go/2018-11-22-dhh-you-probably-wont-make-it-to-the-top/</guid>
      <description>You Probably Won&amp;#39;t Make it to the Top. David Heinemeier Hansson (DHH). Signal vs. Noise. https://m.signalvnoise.com/youre-probably-won-t-make-it-to-the-top-8d2146abb790. 22nd Nov, 2018.  Fallacy: If you really set your mind to it, you can do it&amp;hellip; That’s how I did it. I just wanted it more, worked hard, and eventually all my dreams came true. I won’t say it’s easy, but it’s up to you!
Odds are overwhelmingly that you will not make it to the top.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Humble Exits [Morgan Housel]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/letting_go/2018-10-24-housel-humble-exits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/letting_go/2018-10-24-housel-humble-exits/</guid>
      <description>Humble Exits. Morgan Housel. The Collaborative Fund. https://www.collaborativefund.com/blog/humble-exits/. 24th Oct, 2018.  Jack Welch declined $110m for a 10th season of Seinfeld because he was done with the show. He wanted to end the show on the same kind of peak.
The show was based on recreating real events from his and Larry David&#39;s normal life. They were running out of material because it had been so long since they experienced a normal life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Sivan) Innovation Africa &amp; Water Availability</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/innovation_in_africa/2018-10-01-innovation-africa-and-water-availability/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/innovation_in_africa/2018-10-01-innovation-africa-and-water-availability/</guid>
      <description>Innovation Africa &amp;amp; Water Availability. Sivan (InnoAfrica). Talks at The Keller Center. 2018.  Bring in Israeli solar panels and drip irrigation. Pump water from the large reservoirs below. Cost $7,000.
Adapting to community: 6-8 weeks on committees, bank accounts; mobile charging stations and barbershops using solar panels for sustainability. Can&#39;t sell the water, but you can subsidize it with complementary products.
Set up remote monitoring with real time stats in order to schedule maintenance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Does a Market Work? [CS Colloquia]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/2018-10-01-how-does-a-market-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/2018-10-01-how-does-a-market-work/</guid>
      <description>Objectives: low latency, high throughput &amp;amp; high reliability.
The messages are quite brief, e.g. the ITCH protocol uses 32 bytes per message.
Trading firm listens to broadcasts on buys, sells, deletes on ITCH broadcasts. Online sorting to identify profitable trades.
Matching engine operates on a first-come-first-served basis. Earlier orders with better price get traded first.
Markets run at 50 microsecond scales.
Single market peaks at 10Gbps. Peaks are correlated, e.g. &amp;ldquo;Shit!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Chinese Govt Controls the Media [SoECS]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2018-10-01-chinese-media-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2018-10-01-chinese-media-control/</guid>
      <description>Seeing government influence through coordination of sensitive coverage, localization of negative news &amp;amp; crowding out other stories on the front page.
Structural topic models (LDA + context, e.g. topic prevalence, choice of words) analyze fundamental aspect of the news that can&#39;t be changed.
Instead of assuming news follows events, investigate!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kernighan&#39;s Remarks on the Digital Humanities</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/miscellaneous/2018-10-01-digital-humanities-with-kernighan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/miscellaneous/2018-10-01-digital-humanities-with-kernighan/</guid>
      <description>OCR tends to miss (sometimes) really important context.
Make use of derived data, e.g. age at marriage, gender differences, mortality rates, mapping migrations, last names
Don&#39;t spend all your time cleaning data.
Try a sequence of things, not one big idea.
Don&#39;t expect existing tools to do the whole job. All the while, building new tools is not as straightforward.
Sample Digital Humanities Projects ORBIS by Stanford. A kayak for the Roman Era.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons Learned in Tech Policy [SoECS]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2018-10-01-lessons-learned-in-tech-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2018-10-01-lessons-learned-in-tech-policy/</guid>
      <description>Local governments face severe constraints. Liaising with big tech for employees on sabbaticals could alleviate this.
State legislators may have unfounded opinions, but they have the sway, so work with them.
Rural-urban differences. Rural folk were more active. Urban folks wrote angry blogs and that was it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wolf that Tried to Play Nice [SoECS]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2018-10-01-the-wolf-that-tried-to-play-nice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2018-10-01-the-wolf-that-tried-to-play-nice/</guid>
      <description>AT&amp;amp;T restricted FaceTime from running on some data plans. Justifications?
 FaceTime is preloaded, therefore 100% of users have it FaceTime wasn&#39;t efficient in network usage. The capacity was asymmetrical, but video chat is symmetrical  Interestingly enough, AT&amp;amp;T required Apple to greenlight it, which they did. AT&amp;amp;T worked with top developers to teach network etiquette.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computers Can Solve Your Problem. You May Not Like the Answer. [Boston Globe]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2018-09-21-boston-public-school-equity-algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2018-09-21-boston-public-school-equity-algorithm/</guid>
      <description>Computers Can Solve Your Problem. You May Not Like the Answer. What happened when Boston Public Schools tried for equity with an algorithm. David Scharfenberg. The Boston Globe. https://apps.bostonglobe.com/ideas/graphics/2018/09/equity-machine/. 2018-09-21.  Teens need their sleep: sleep-deprived teens are at increased risk for poor academic performance, binge drinking, and suicide.
BPS laid out the algorithm’s four guiding principles:
 Increase the number of high school students starting school after 8am Decrease the number of elementary school students dismissed after 4pm Accommodate the needs of special education students wherever possible Generate transportation savings that could be reinvested in the schools  Officials picked a solution that attempted to balance several goals — student health, cost savings, and parental happiness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Mathematicians Can&#39;t Find the Hay in a Haystack [Quanta Magazine]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/mathematics/2018-09-17-cant-find-hay-in-a-hay-stack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/mathematics/2018-09-17-cant-find-hay-in-a-hay-stack/</guid>
      <description>Why Mathematicians Can’t Find the Hay in a Haystack. Kevin Hartnett. https://www.quantamagazine.org/why-mathematicians-cant-find-the-hay-in-a-haystack-20180917/. 2018-09-17.  Irrational numbers occupy most of the number line. If you were to pick a number on the number line at random, there is literally a 100% chance that it will be irrational (probabilities with inifinities are spooky). Yet, we almost never encounter irrational numbers for we can&#39;t write them down.
The shapes we know best - lines, parabolas, circles, spheres - are the needles, for they can be expressed by simple equations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Theory, Evolution &amp; Games) Separating Theory from Nonsense via Communication Norms, not Truth</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/knowing/2018-09-08-teg-separating-theory-from-nonsense/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/knowing/2018-09-08-teg-separating-theory-from-nonsense/</guid>
      <description>Separating Theory from Nonsense via Communication Norms, not Truth. Artem Kaznatcheev. Theory, Evolution &amp;amp; Games. https://egtheory.wordpress.com/2018/09/08/theory-norms/. 8th Sept, 2018.  Brian Skinner - how to distinguish good theory from crackpottery  Both theorists and crackpots share an irrational self-confidence A crackpot relies primarily on positive evidence  Thinks hard about a problem, arrives at a theory that feels right, and then publicizes the result.   A theorist incorporates negative evidence:  Ponders hard about a problem, arrives at a theory that feels right and then proceeds to try to disprove that theory Takes time to understand competing theories and compare them against her own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is the Lean Startup Dead? [Steve Blank]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/on-starting-a-business/2018-09-05-is-the-lean-startup-dead/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/on-starting-a-business/2018-09-05-is-the-lean-startup-dead/</guid>
      <description>Is the Lean Startup Dead?. Steve Blank. https://steveblank.com/2018/09/05/is-the-lean-startup-dead/. 2018-09-05.  Katzenberg (Paramount, Disney Studios &amp;amp; DreamWorks) has raised $1.75b for NewTV, a startup banking on consumers wanting a subscription for 10-minute programs on mobile.
They renamed to quibi.com/. At least that makes them more searchable on Google. &amp;ldquo;NewTV&amp;rdquo; searches lead to newtv.org, a community media center for the residents of Newton, Massachusetts.
  After the rubble of the dotcom crash, startups and investors needed a lean approach to survive long enough to generate revenue and profits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Trajectory of Great Ideas [Morgan Housel]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/on-starting-a-business/2018-08-14-trajectory-of-great-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/on-starting-a-business/2018-08-14-trajectory-of-great-ideas/</guid>
      <description>The Trajectory of Great Ideas. Morgan Housel. Collaborative Fund. https://www.collaborativefund.com/blog/ideas/. 2018-08-14.  Sears. Blockbuster. Nokia. AOL. You had a great idea. You discovered a beautiful beach to lay on, but other people didn&#39;t just follow you and lay down themselves; they built condos and restaurants while you were watching the sunset. Soon your great idea loses its appeal.
But you put so much work into the great idea that it&#39;s become an inseparable part of your identity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google&#39;s Project Dragonfly [The Intercept]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/privacy/2018-08-01-google-project-dragonfly/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/privacy/2018-08-01-google-project-dragonfly/</guid>
      <description>Google Plans to Launch Censored Search Engine in China, Leaked Documents Reveal [The Intercept]. Ryan Gallagher. The Intercept. https://theintercept.com/2018/08/01/google-china-search-engine-censorship/. 2018-08-01.  Project Dragonfly A censored version of Google search that blacklists websites and search terms about human rights, democracy, religion and peaceful protests.
China has 750m people; 80% of its internet access is on Android. There&#39;s $$$ to be made.
Between 2006 and 2010, Google had maintained a censored Google Search, but was heavily criticized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Average Age of a Successful Startup Founder is 45 [Harvard Business]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/on-starting-a-business/2018-07-11-average-age-of-successful-founder-is-45/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/on-starting-a-business/2018-07-11-average-age-of-successful-founder-is-45/</guid>
      <description>The Average Age of a Successful Startup Founder is 45. Harvard Business Review. https://hbr.org/2018/07/research-the-average-age-of-a-successful-startup-founder-is-45. 2018-07-11.  There&#39;s a variation among industries: software tends to 40, while oil/gas/biotech tends to 47.
Even Gates, Jobs, Bezos, Brin &amp;amp; Page had their growth rates peak when they were middle aged.
Different definitions of success, e.g. employment growth, sales growth, IPO/acquisition, came to the same conclusion.
VCs may not be looking for growth potential.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Love B2B over B2C [Atrium]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/on-starting-a-business/2018-07-11-why-i-love-b2b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/on-starting-a-business/2018-07-11-why-i-love-b2b/</guid>
      <description>Why I Love B2B over B2C. Justin Kan. Atrium. https://www.atrium.co/blog/b2b-vs-b2c/. 2018-07-11.  B2B customers will actually pay for your product. You have a clear execution path - they&#39;ll tell you and pay for features. Companies don&#39;t quickly flip flop between products. Consumers are too price sensitive and finicky.
B2B customers are rational, and thus understandable. They care about whether a solution solves their problem and if the solution is important enough to pay for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Morgan Housel) Immeasurably Important</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/an_outlook_on_life/2018-07-01-housel-immeasurably-important/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/an_outlook_on_life/2018-07-01-housel-immeasurably-important/</guid>
      <description>Immeasurably Important. Morgan Housel. Collaborative Fund. http://www.collaborativefund.com/blog/immeasurably-important/. 5th July, 2018.  Filtering out information is an art, not a science, necessitated by the information overload that we live in.
 Watch out for the tendency to only preserve information that meshes with how we think the world should be. If you think the world is all art, you miss how much stuff is too complicated to think about intuitively.  If you think the world is all data, you&#39;ll miss how much is too complicated to summarize in a statistic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IBM Watson&#39;s Health Saga</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/2018-06-25-ibm-watsons-health-saga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/2018-06-25-ibm-watsons-health-saga/</guid>
      <description>Layoffs at Watson Health Reveal IBM’s Problem with AI. Eliza Strickland. IEEE. https://spectrum.ieee.org/the-human-os/robotics/artificial-intelligence/layoffs-at-watson-health-reveal-ibms-problem-with-ai. https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17393560. 2018-06-25.   Jefferies gives IBM Watson a Wall Street reality check. John Mannes. https://techcrunch.com/2017/07/13/jefferies-gives-ibm-watson-a-wall-street-reality-check/. https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=14766793. 2017-07-13.    IBM acquired Phytel, Explorys and Truven for their troves of healthcare data and proprietary analytics.
  From 2010 to 2015, IBM has spent +$15bn and Watson is still not profitable.
  Marketed abilities: scan literature &amp;amp; patient history to recommend cancer treatment plans, offer preventative medicine &amp;amp; medical imaging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>U.S. Files Criminal Charges Against Elizabeth Holmes and Ramesh Balwani [WSJ]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/2018-06-15-theranos-disaster/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/2018-06-15-theranos-disaster/</guid>
      <description>U.S. Files Criminal Charges Against Elizabeth Holmes and Ramesh Balwani. John Carreyrou. The Wall Street Journal. https://www.wsj.com/articles/u-s-files-criminal-charges-against-theranoss-elizabeth-holmes-ramesh-balwani-1529096005. https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17323485. 2018-06-15.   (Ask HN) Holmes has 200 Patents. If tech didn&amp;#39;t work, why not noticed?. Hacker News. https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17328664. 2018-06-18.   Theranos Lessons. Morgan Housel. Collaborative Fund&amp;#39;s Blog. https://www.collaborativefund.com/blog/theranos-lessons/. 2019-06-19.   This CEO is Out for Blood. Roger Parloff. https://www.fortune.com/2014/06/12/theranos-blood-holmes/. https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=7951019. 2014-06-12.  Holmes and COO charged with wire fraud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Psychology of Money [Morgan Housel]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/an_outlook_on_life/2018-06-01-housel-psychology-of-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/an_outlook_on_life/2018-06-01-housel-psychology-of-money/</guid>
      <description>The Psychology of Money. Morgan Housel. The Collaborative Fund. http://www.collaborativefund.com/blog/the-psychology-of-money/. 2018-06-01.  Luck and risk are different sides of the same coin. People underestimate the role of luck and risk. There are a billion investors. By sheer chance, we expect a couple of them to be billionaires predominantly off luck. But it&#39;s hard to point fingers after the fact.
 Some people are born into families that encourage education; others are against it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Azeria Labs) The Importance of Deep Work &amp; The 30-Hour Method for Learning a New Skill</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/a_guide_to_creativity/2018-05-26-azeria-labs-importance-of-deep-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/a_guide_to_creativity/2018-05-26-azeria-labs-importance-of-deep-work/</guid>
      <description>The Importance of Deep Work &amp;amp; The 30-Hour Method for Learning a New Skill. Azeria Labs. https://azeria-labs.com/the-importance-of-deep-work-the-30-hour-method-for-learning-a-new-skill/. https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17163251.  30 Hour Deep Work Tryout:
 Scan resources and pick the ones that seem most useful (5 hours) Set up the environment and define structured goals (3 hours) Work towards increasingly difficult goals set in step 2 (22 hours)  Each session should be about 4 hours. It takes about 20min to get into the flow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Apology for the Internet - How It Went Wrong [Intelligencer]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/privacy/2018-04-16-an-apology-for-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/privacy/2018-04-16-an-apology-for-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>An Apology for the Internet - How It Went Wrong. Noah Kulwin. NY Mag. http://nymag.com/intelligencer/2018/04/an-apology-for-the-internet-from-the-people-who-built-it.html. 2018-04-16.  Start with hippie good intentions. A generation embracing new technology as a tool to transform the world for good.
 Can Duruk: You were going to Facebook not to work but to make the world more open and connected.  Mix in capitalism on steroids. To save the world, you first need to take it over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cambridge Analytica Uncovered: Secret filming reveals election tricks [Channel 4]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2018-03-19-cambridge-analytica-uncovered/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2018-03-19-cambridge-analytica-uncovered/</guid>
      <description>Cambridge Analytica Uncovered: Secret filming reveals election tricks. Channel 4 News. https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mpbeOCKZFfQ. 2018-03-19.  Pay people to take surveys but through an app. Mine their profile data, and also crawl their friends.
Identify swayable voters and their sensitivities. Craft targeted ads. Play on (unconscious) fears and hopes.
Elections are about emotions, not facts. Data science and social media can help us make sense of and manipulate the chaos.
An alternative argument: political misinformation is&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Competitive Edges Die [Morgan Housel]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/on-starting-a-business/2018-02-08-why-competitive-edges-die/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/on-starting-a-business/2018-02-08-why-competitive-edges-die/</guid>
      <description>Why Competitive Edges Die. Morgan Housel. Collaborative Fund. https://www.collaborativefund.com/blog/why-competitive-advantages-die/. 2018-02-08.  The Beginner&#39;s Mind Being right is the enemy of staying right because it leads you to forget the way the world works.
Knowing you have a competitive advantage reduces the incentive to explore other ideas, especially when those ideas conflict with your chosen strategy.
The Burden of Being Profitable Nothing to lose is a wonderful thing to have. Having a quarterly dividend to maintain is what happens after you build something great.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Betting on Things That Never Change [Morgan Housel]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/2017-07-20-betting-on-things-that-never-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/2017-07-20-betting-on-things-that-never-change/</guid>
      <description>Betting on Things That Never Change. Morgan Housel. Collaborative Fund. https://www.collaborativefund.com/blog/betting-on-things-that-never-change/. 2017-07-20.  Change by itself is hard. Investors have to spot it before it&#39;s obvious. Consumers have to change their behaviors to make it viable. These two points repel each other.
Sears bet the Internet changed nothing. Beenz bet the Internet changed everything - creating a points-based currency valid only at online merchants. Amazon bet the Internet changed distribution, but rooted its strategy in selection and low prices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Syll) What is Ergodicity?</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/knowing/2016-11-23-syll-what-is-ergodicity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/knowing/2016-11-23-syll-what-is-ergodicity/</guid>
      <description>What is Ergodicity?. Lars P. Syll. https://larspsyll.wordpress.com/2016/11/23/what-is-ergodicity-2/. 23rd Nov, 2016.  A random process is ergodic if all of its statistics can be determined from a sample function of the process. That is, the ensemble averages equal the corresponding time averages with probability one.
Role of Ergodicity in Human Inference  A newspaper has previously printed some inaccurate information, therefore, the newspaper is going to publish inaccurate information in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Trade of the Century: When George Soros Broke the British Pound [Priceonomics]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/2016-06-17-when-soros-broke-the-british-pound/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/trading-and-investing/2016-06-17-when-soros-broke-the-british-pound/</guid>
      <description>The Trade of the Century: When George Soros Broke the British Pound. Rohin Dhar. Priceonomics. https://priceonomics.com/the-trade-of-the-century-when-george-soros-broke/. 2016-06-17.  Before the EU, Europe had the ERM to fix their exchange rates with the Deutschmark within 6% of the agreed upon rate.
Keeping the exchange rate fixed requires governments to nudge the rate, e.g.
 Use reserves of foreign currency to buy up their own currency Set high interest rates to entice lenders to buy their currency  Margaret Thatcher (PM) opposed the fixed exchange rates but lost the vote to Major, an ERM proponent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Paul Graham) Life is Short</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/an_outlook_on_life/2016-01-01-pg-bullshit-minimizing-path/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/an_outlook_on_life/2016-01-01-pg-bullshit-minimizing-path/</guid>
      <description>Life is Short. Paul Graham. http://www.paulgraham.com/vb.html. Jan 2016.  Some of it is our own fault (e.g. arguing online). Some of it is forced by circumstances that we choose to endure (e.g. unnecessary meetings at work)
Choosing a bullshit minimizing path is error-prone. Your priorities change over time. Periodically evaluate where you are. It helps to have measurable aspects of your life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So You Want to Reform Democracy [Medium]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2015-11-22-so-you-want-to-reform-democracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2015-11-22-so-you-want-to-reform-democracy/</guid>
      <description>So You Want to Reform Democracy. Joshua Tauberer. https://medium.com/civic-tech-thoughts-from-joshdata/so-you-want-to-reform-democracy-7f3b1ef10597. 2015-11-22.  If there was an idea that could &amp;lsquo;fix&amp;rsquo; democracy, it would have been thought-up already. If you don&#39;t see your idea out there, it’s because it didn’t work the hundreds of other times someone tried it.
Let’s tell representatives what their constituents think. Then they HAVE to vote with us!
 They don’t necessarily want to know what their constituents are thinking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Slate Star Codex) No Clarity Around Growth Mindset</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/letting_go/2015-04-08-ssc-no-clarity-around-the-growth-mindset/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/letting_go/2015-04-08-ssc-no-clarity-around-the-growth-mindset/</guid>
      <description>No Clarity Around Growth Mindset. Scott Alexander. Slate Star Codex. https://slatestarcodex.com/2015/04/08/no-clarity-around-growth-mindset-yet/. 8th April, 2015.  Growth mindset: people who believe effort - and not ability - determines success are more resilient, skillful, hard-working, perseverant in the face of failure.
Most of the growth mindset experiments prime their subjects, but recent priming experiments have famously failed to replicate. Dweck&#39;s experiment:
 Group A: easy test (success) -&amp;gt; final bound-to-fail test Group B: hard test (told they&#39;re not working hard enough) -&amp;gt; final bound-to-fail test Group B outperformed Group A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Eliezer Yudkowsy) Against Rationalization</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/knowing/2015-02-01-yudkowsky-against-rationalization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/knowing/2015-02-01-yudkowsky-against-rationalization/</guid>
      <description>Against Rationalization. Eliezer Yudkowsky. Rationality: From AI to Zombies. Feb 2015.  In real life, you have to gather evidence, which may be costly. At some point you have to decide that you have enough evidence to stop and choose. A motivated skeptic asks if the evidence compels them to accept the conclusion; a motivated credulist asks if the evidence allows them to accept the conclusion.
Suspect motivated stopping when you close off the search, after coming to a comfortable conclusion, and yet there is a lot of fast cheap evidence you haven&#39;t gathered yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Yudkowsky) 0 and 1 Are Not Probabilities</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/overly_convenient_excuses/2015-02-01-yudkowsky-0-and-1-are-not-probabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/overly_convenient_excuses/2015-02-01-yudkowsky-0-and-1-are-not-probabilities/</guid>
      <description>0 And 1 Are Not Probabilities. Eliezer Yudkowsky. Rationality: From AI to Zombies. Feb 2015.  $$ O = \frac{P}{1 - P},\ \ \ P = \frac{O}{1 + O} $$
When you transform probabilities to odds, 0 goes to 0, but 1 goes to infinity. Now the absolute truth doesn&#39;t look like it should be easy to reach.
When you transform probabilities to odds, 0.502 and 0.503 goes to 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Yudkowsky) Letting Go</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/letting_go/2015-12-01-yudkowsky-letting-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/letting_go/2015-12-01-yudkowsky-letting-go/</guid>
      <description>Letting Go. Eliezer Yudkowsky. Rationality: From AI to Zombies. Feb 2015.  Learn when to admit failure It&#39;s important to have a watershed moment and acknowledge a fundamental problem, instead of dividing it into palatable bite-size mistakes.
LTCM were exploiting market inefficiencies. Other people learned of the tricks. LTCM didn&#39;t lose hope. They borrowed more and more leverage to exploit tinier and tinier margins.
And their math probably said the leverage was okay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Yudkowsky) Lotteries</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/overly_convenient_excuses/2015-02-01-yudkowsky-lotteries-a-waste-of-hope/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/overly_convenient_excuses/2015-02-01-yudkowsky-lotteries-a-waste-of-hope/</guid>
      <description>Lotteries: A Waste of Hope. Eliezer Yudkowsky. Rationality: From AI to Zombies. Feb 2015.   New Improved Lottery. Eliezer Yudkowsky. Rationality: From AI to Zombies. Feb 2015.  The lottery is a sink of emotional energy. It encourages people to invest in their dreams, their hopes for a better future, into an infinitesimal probability.
People can&#39;t devalue the emotional force of pleasant anticipation by a factor of .0000001 without dropping the line of reasoning entirely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Yudkowsky) The Proper Use of Humility</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/overly_convenient_excuses/2015-02-01-yudkowsky-the-proper-use-of-humility/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/overly_convenient_excuses/2015-02-01-yudkowsky-the-proper-use-of-humility/</guid>
      <description>The Proper Use of Humility. Eliezer Yudkowsky. Rationality: From AI to Zombies. Feb 2015.  To be humble is to take specific actions in anticipation of your own errors. To confess your fallibility and then do nothing about it is not humble; it is boasting of your modesty.
Good humility: Engineer humbly designs fail-safe mechanisms into machinery, even though they are damn sure the machinery won&#39;t fail.
Bad humility: But who can really know whether evolution is correct?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Yudkowsky) The Third Alternative</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/overly_convenient_excuses/2015-02-01-yudkowsky-the-third-alternative/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/overly_convenient_excuses/2015-02-01-yudkowsky-the-third-alternative/</guid>
      <description>The Third Alternative. Eliezer Yudkowsky. Rationality: From AI to Zombies. Feb 2015.  If Santa-belief is destroyed by truth, the children will lose their sense of wonder and stop behaving nicely. It does not follow that Santa-ism is the best of all possible alternatives.
People justify questionable policy by pointing to a supposed benefit over the null action. The search for alternatives can go on forever, so one needs a stopping criterion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Yudkowsky) There&#39;s Still a Chance, Right?</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/overly_convenient_excuses/2015-02-01-yudkowsky-overly-convenient-theres-still-a-chance-right/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/overly_convenient_excuses/2015-02-01-yudkowsky-overly-convenient-theres-still-a-chance-right/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;#39;s Still a Chance, Right?. Eliezer Yudkowsky. Rationality: From AI to Zombies. Feb 2015.  &amp;ldquo;Humans and chimps have 98% shared DNA.&amp;rdquo; Maybe the DNA is just similar by coincidence. You say the odds are tiny, but there&#39;s still a chance, right?
The problem is that probability theory sometimes lets us calculate a chance which is, indeed, too tiny to be worth the mental space to keep track of it - but by that time, you&#39;ve already calculated it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (SSC) The Parable of the Talents</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/an_outlook_on_life/2015-01-31-ssc-the-principle-of-the-talents/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/an_outlook_on_life/2015-01-31-ssc-the-principle-of-the-talents/</guid>
      <description>The Parable of the Talents. Scott Alexander. Slate Star Codex. https://slatestarcodex.com/2015/01/31/the-parable-of-the-talents/. 31st Jan, 2015.  Overweight people, depressed people, and poor people aren’t fully to blame for their situation – and neither are unintelligent people. It’s accidents of birth all the way down.
Srinivasa Ramanujan:
 Grew up in poverty in a one-room house in small-town India. But a lot of poor people in the US had better conditions/opportunities  Either, a lot of intelligence is innate Or, those poor people are just not trying hard enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Read and Know [Paul Graham, Robert Heaton]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/a_guide_to_creativity/2014-12-01-reading-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/a_guide_to_creativity/2014-12-01-reading-to-know/</guid>
      <description>How to Read. Robert Heaton. https://robertheaton.com/2018/06/25/how-to-read/. https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17424652. 2018-06-25.   Know. Paul Graham. http://www.paulgraham.com/know.html. 2014-12-01.  Choose your content. Some books [and articles] are not worth the effort.
Information overload is one of my major obstacles to reading to know. There are so many pieces out there. I&#39;m biased towards highly upvoted HN submissions. My RSS feeds ran out of control a while back - my queue has +400 pending articles :-/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do Things That Don&#39;t Scale [Paul Graham]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/on-starting-a-business/2013-07-01-do-things-that-dont-scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/on-starting-a-business/2013-07-01-do-things-that-dont-scale/</guid>
      <description>Do Things That Don&amp;#39;t Scale. Paul Graham. http://www.paulgraham.com/ds.html. 2013-07-01.  Recruit manually. Don&#39;t send links. Set them up on the spot.
Ask how big the startup would be if you did the right things, not whether you&#39;re currently changing the world.
Delight your initial customers. Tim Cook can&#39;t send handwritten notes, but you can.
If you can solve the problem manually, do so while gradually automating the most pressing bottlenecks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Get Startup Ideas [Paul Graham]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/on-starting-a-business/2012-11-01-how-to-get-startup-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/on-starting-a-business/2012-11-01-how-to-get-startup-ideas/</guid>
      <description>How to Get Startup Ideas. Paul Graham. http://www.paulgraham.com/startupideas.html. 2012-11-01.  Err on the side of having competitors, but make sure that you have a thesis that everyone else is overlooking, e.g. Google wasn&#39;t averse to users leaving google.com ASAP
The Startup Idea Matrix, (B2B Edition, B2C Edition) is a good start for knowing who to google.
  In college, take classes in different areas in lieu of taking entrepreneurship classes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Doctors Die [Zocalo]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/2011-11-30-how-doctors-die/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/2011-11-30-how-doctors-die/</guid>
      <description>How Doctors Die. Zocalo Public Square. https://www.zocalopublicsquare.org/2011/11/30/how-doctors-die/ideas/nexus/.  Doctors tend to be fairly serene when faced with death themselves. They know enough about modern medicine to know its limits. They go gently into that good night - no heroics; no CPR.
Sometimes, a family really means &amp;lsquo;do everything&amp;rsquo;, but often they mean &amp;lsquo;do everything that’s reasonable.&amp;rsquo; But they may not know what’s reasonable.
People have unrealistic expectations of what doctors can accomplish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Submarine [Paul Graham]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/2005-04-01-the-submarine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/optimism_and_deception/2005-04-01-the-submarine/</guid>
      <description>The Submarine. Paul Graham. http://www.paulgraham.com/submarine.html. 2005-04.  Many people rely on social proof to form opinions; therein lies the power of PR.
PR firms are not dishonest for they need good reputation with news outlets. But PR firms serve overworked reporters with selective truths.
The firms feed the same story to different publications at once. Readers see similar stories in multiple places and assume a new trend has come.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Paul Graham) The Age of the Essay</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/a_guide_to_creativity/2004-09-01-pg-the-age-of-the-essay/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/a_guide_to_creativity/2004-09-01-pg-the-age-of-the-essay/</guid>
      <description>The Age of the Essay. Paul Graham. http://www.paulgraham.com/essay.html. Sept 2004.  An essay is something that you write to try and figure out something. By definition, you can&#39;t begin with a statement.
Expressing ideas helps you form them. Writing something that others might read forces you to think well.
Think of the essay as an idea graph. At each node, contrary to Geoffrey&#39;s Principle of Least Astonishment for UIs, branch out to the most interesting related idea.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>