<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on c13u&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.c13u.com/categories/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on c13u&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.c13u.com/categories/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New grad vs senior dev [Eric Lipppert]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/2020-03-27-new-grad-vs-senior-dev/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/2020-03-27-new-grad-vs-senior-dev/</guid>
      <description>New grad vs senior dev.  Eric Lipppert. Fabulous adventures in coding. https://ericlippert.com/2020/03/27/new-grad-vs-senior-dev/  . https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=22352674  . Mar 27, 2020.  Substring Search in Visual Basic In CS, substring search is a foundational problem for which there are \(O(m + n)\) algorithms. But VB&amp;rsquo;s implementation was \(O(mn)\). Suppose we have InStr(&amp;quot;apple banana orange&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;banana&amp;quot;):
 Skip to the first b. Check if banana is a substring starting from that b.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Signal Is Finally Bringing Its Secure Messaging To the Masses [Andy Greenberg]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/2020-02-14-signal-secure-messaging-to-the-masses/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/2020-02-14-signal-secure-messaging-to-the-masses/</guid>
      <description>Signal Is Finally Bringing Its Secure Messaging To the Masses.  Andy Greenberg. https://www.wired.com/story/signal-encrypted-messaging-features-mainstream/  . https://it.slashdot.org/story/20/02/14/2216214/signal-is-finally-bringing-its-secure-messaging-to-the-masses#comments  . https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=22326731  . Feb 14, 2020.  Attracting the Masses Brian Acton (WhatsApp cofounder) injected $50m into the Signal Foundation, allowing them to grow from 3 to 50 full-timers.
You&amp;rsquo;d think that at Signal&amp;rsquo;s dominance, getting $$$ shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a problem. But VCs expect a multiple return and Signal doesn&amp;rsquo;t look like it will monetize soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Against &#39;Smart&#39; Clipboard Adjustments</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/2020-02-17-dont-touch-my-clipboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/2020-02-17-dont-touch-my-clipboard/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t touch my clipboard [Alex Ellis]  Complaint: Alex selected &amp;amp; copied an em dash ( - ) character from https://www.thepunctuationguide.com/em-dash.html, but here&amp;rsquo;s what the site put into the clipboard:
1 2 3 4  — From https://www.thepunctuationguide.com/em-dash.html © 2020 thepunctuationguide.com   There&amp;rsquo;s a tradeoff between attribution and changing things outside a site&amp;rsquo;s scope.
Apple&amp;rsquo;s iBooks does this too. It may be due to contractual agreements with publishers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lean Startups vs. VC Money</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/business/on-starting-a-business/2020-12-18-lean-vs-vc-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/business/on-starting-a-business/2020-12-18-lean-vs-vc-money/</guid>
      <description>20 years later, JetBrains is valued at $7b without taking VC money. HN users praise JetBrains for being user-focused, and the prevailing argument is that VC money comes with growth-hacking attached. 
Is the Lean Startup Dead? Katzenberg (Paramount, Disney Studios &amp;amp; DreamWorks) has raised $1.75b for NewTV, a startup banking on consumers wanting a subscription for 10-minute programs on mobile.
They renamed to quibi.com/  . At least that makes them more searchable on Google.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Startup Ideas</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/business/on-starting-a-business/2020-07-05-startup-ideation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/business/on-starting-a-business/2020-07-05-startup-ideation/</guid>
      <description>How to Get Startup Ideas  Err on the side of having competitors, but make sure that you have a thesis that everyone else is overlooking, e.g. Google wasn&amp;rsquo;t averse to users leaving google.com ASAP.
The Startup Idea Matrix, ( B2B Edition  , B2C Edition  ) is a good start for knowing who to google.
  Big companies tend to be slow at changing their approach. You&amp;rsquo;d think that Yahoo!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Distributed Systems</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/2020-05-17-distributed-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/2020-05-17-distributed-systems/</guid>
      <description>Mergeable Replicated Data Types  On a distributed system, each replica should [eventually] converge to the same state. Commutative Replicated Data Types (CRDTs) can accept updates and achieve consistent without remote synchronization.
The Need for Commutativity Say we have a queue \( 1 \to 2 \). Suppose two replicas, \(r_1\) and \(r_2\), independently call pop(). Each replica will have \(2\) on their queue.
However, on receiving an update that the other replica popped, each replica will call pop() to be consistent, thereby deleting \(2\).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Tracing for COVID-19</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/health-and-medicine/2020-05-06-contact-tracing-for-covid-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/health-and-medicine/2020-05-06-contact-tracing-for-covid-19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Apps&amp;rdquo; in this context means contact tracing apps released by public health authorities to do contact tracing. The APIs are limited to them.
  Big Picture  Release APIs to enable apps to interoperate between Android and iOS devices.  Bluetooth-based contact tracing baked into Android and iOS, such that no app is needed for broadcasting/listening.  This ensures broad adoption, but will be on an opt-in basis.   Interesting debate for privacy, ethics and public health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading and Writing to Know</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/knowing/2020-05-02-reading-and-writing-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/knowing/2020-05-02-reading-and-writing-to-know/</guid>
      <description>Reading to Know Choose your content. Some books [and articles] are not worth the effort. Sometimes you just don&amp;rsquo;t care whether you&amp;rsquo;ll remember what you&amp;rsquo;ve read. 
But even if you don&amp;rsquo;t remember the specifics, the effect on your model of the world persists. As your mental model evolves, re-reading books is beneficial because the material compiles differently. 
When reading, annotate connections from previous knowledge, unanswered questions and unjustified assumptions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wall Street University: USD 101</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/trading-and-investing/2020-05-02-wall-street-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/trading-and-investing/2020-05-02-wall-street-101/</guid>
      <description>Short Selling  Say $A shares are selling at $100, but I think they&amp;rsquo;re overpriced. So I borrow 10 shares, pay my brokerage interest and post some collateral. I then sell the shares for $1,000.
Whoever buys my shares has no idea that I do not own them. In a naked short, I do not actually borrow or ensure that the security can be borrowed within the standard 3-day settlement period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Politics of Free Speech</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/politics-and-governance/2020-04-29-politics-of-free-speech/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/politics-and-governance/2020-04-29-politics-of-free-speech/</guid>
      <description>Should Platforms Be Neutral? Facebook banned praise, support and representation of white nationalism and separatism, because the two concepts cannot be meaningfully separated from white supremacy and organized hate groups. Furthermore, people that search for related terms will have &amp;ldquo;Life After Hate&amp;rdquo; suggested to them. 
Part of me is uncomfortable. Sure, Facebook is trying to do the right thing here. What if Facebook was replaced by some tyrannical government that censors opposition?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philanthropy</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/socioeconomics/2020-04-26-on-philanthropy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/socioeconomics/2020-04-26-on-philanthropy/</guid>
      <description>Criticism/Defense Of Billionaire Philanthropy  Taxes will probably not go to the same causes, e.g. reforming the bail system, grassroot efforts for migrants, etc.
Foundations are more effective than governments as they do their due diligence, e.g. Bill Gates. Reforming the government is a long battle.
Jack Dorsey (Twitter), set up $1B of his Square stock (28% of net worth) in an LLC to fund efforts for Covid-19, Girl&amp;rsquo;s Health and Education, and Universal Basic Income.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tech Startups Are Flooding Kenya With Apps Offering High-Interest Loans [Bloomberg]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/business/optimism_and_deception/2020-02-12-high-interest-digital-loans-kenya/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/business/optimism_and_deception/2020-02-12-high-interest-digital-loans-kenya/</guid>
      <description>Tech Startups Are Flooding Kenya With Apps Offering High-Interest Loans.  Zeke Faux. Bloomberg New Economy. https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2020-02-12/tech-startups-are-flooding-kenya-with-apps-offering-high-interest-loans  . https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=22307002  .  Tala&amp;rsquo;s Version of Events Empowering female entrepreneurs around the world - Mexico, Philippines, India &amp;amp; Kenya.
69% of global adult population is not covered by credit bureaus. Using non-traditional data, more people can get scored.
Credit brings opportunity and choice. We help people be in control of their finances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook to Pay $550 Million to Settle Facial Recognition Suit</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/www/the-battle-for-the-web/2020-01-29-fb-550m-fine-for-facial-recognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/www/the-battle-for-the-web/2020-01-29-fb-550m-fine-for-facial-recognition/</guid>
      <description>Facebook to Pay $550 Million to Settle Facial Recognition Suit.  Natasha Singer; Mike Isaac. The New York Times. https://www.nytimes.com/2020/01/29/technology/facebook-privacy-lawsuit-earnings.html  . Jan 29, 2020.  Illinois&#39; biometric privacy law requires companies to obtain written permission before collecting a person’s biometrics. Residents have the right to sue for up to $5,000 per violation.
Facebook&amp;rsquo;s Tag Suggestions harvested facial data without getting written consent nor telling Illinois users for how long the data would be kept.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theory About Theories</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/knowing/2020-01-08-theory-about-theories/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/knowing/2020-01-08-theory-about-theories/</guid>
      <description>On Coming Up With New Theories A crackpot publicizes a theory that feels right. A theorist goes further to try and disprove a theory that feels right, before publishing it. 
There is still value in an earnest well-thought out theory, even if it turns out wrong, e.g. saving others the trouble. Juniors spend far more time making sure they know everything, while seniors release more half-baked ideas - yet the senior&amp;rsquo;s half-baked ideas will probably be more widely read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Third Base [Scott Galloway]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/socioeconomics/2019-12-13-galloway-third-base/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/socioeconomics/2019-12-13-galloway-third-base/</guid>
      <description>Third Base  Not recognizing your blessings feeds into the dark side of capitalism and meritocracy: success is a choice, and that those who haven’t achieved success are not unlucky, but unworthy.
I&amp;rsquo;m relatively lucky. I don&amp;rsquo;t know how much of the techie hubris that I bear. I have unresolved feelings about meritocracy and fairness. Race is usually used as a proxy for bridging the gap, e.g. affirmative action at colleges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We ran the numbers, and there really is a pipeline problem in eng hiring. [interviewing.io]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/www/the-battle-for-the-web/2019-12-03-there-is-a-pipeline-problem-in-eng-hiring/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/www/the-battle-for-the-web/2019-12-03-there-is-a-pipeline-problem-in-eng-hiring/</guid>
      <description>We ran the numbers, and there really is a pipeline problem in eng hiring.  Aline Lerner. http://blog.interviewing.io/we-ran-the-numbers-and-there-really-is-a-pipeline-problem-in-eng-hiring/  . https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21694348  . Dec 3, 2019.  Wait, but research shows:
 STEM in early education is unfriendly to children from underrepresented backgrounds Lack of a level playing field and unequal access to quality STEM education Hostile university culture in male-dominated CS programs Biased hiring practices Non-inclusive work environments cause higher churn of underrepresented folk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: All Therapy Books [Scott Alexander]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/social-science/psychology/2019-11-20-ssc-all-therapy-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/social-science/psychology/2019-11-20-ssc-all-therapy-books/</guid>
      <description>Book Review: All Therapy Books.  Scott Alexander. Slate Star Codex. https://slatestarcodex.com/2019/11/20/book-review-all-therapy-books/  .  Scott&amp;rsquo;s thesis: Each of the therapy books on their own can be convincing. But they should be taken in the context of All Therapy Books, which as a category are pretty worrying.
 Dodo Bird Verdict  : All psychotherapies are about equally good, and the only things that matters are &amp;ldquo;nonspecific factors&amp;rdquo; like how much patients like their therapist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The New Dot Com Bubble is Here: It’s Called Online Advertising [The Correspondent]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/business/optimism_and_deception/2019-11-06-the-new-dotcom-bubble-is-online-advertising/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/business/optimism_and_deception/2019-11-06-the-new-dotcom-bubble-is-online-advertising/</guid>
      <description>The New Dot Com Bubble is Here: It’s Called Online Advertising.  Jesse Frederick; Maurits Martijn. https://thecorrespondent.com/100/the-new-dot-com-bubble-is-here-its-called-online-advertising/13228924500-22d5fd24  . Nov 6, 2019.  In 2018, $273b was spent on digital ads. But are ad platforms any good at manipulating us?
Tadelis, Econ Prof at UCB stint @ eBay: Consultants: paying for sponsored links for people that searched for &amp;lsquo;eBay&amp;rsquo; was a $245.6m return, not a $20m expense.
Selection Effect: What if the ad clickers were going to use eBay anyway?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AT&amp;T to pay $60m in settlement for slowing cellphone data on unlimited plans</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/business/optimism_and_deception/2019-11-05-att-pay-60m-in-settlement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/business/optimism_and_deception/2019-11-05-att-pay-60m-in-settlement/</guid>
      <description>AT&amp;amp;T to pay $60m in settlement for slowing cellphone data on unlimited plans.  Reuters. https://www.reuters.com/article/us-at-t-settlement/att-will-pay-60-million-over-u-s-allegations-it-lied-in-unlimited-data-pledge-government-idUSKBN1XF26Q  .    Complaint filed in 2014 by the FTC: AT&amp;amp;T charged smartphone users for &amp;lsquo;unlimited&amp;rsquo; data plans, but throttled them after ~2GB within a month.
  AT&amp;amp;T: None of these allegations were ever proved in court. We were fully prepared to defend ourselves, but decided settling was in the best interests of consumers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The New York Times Sells Premium Ads Based on How an Article Makes You Feel</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/www/the-battle-for-the-web/2019-04-10-nyt-sells-ads-based-on-how-an-article-makes-you-feel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/www/the-battle-for-the-web/2019-04-10-nyt-sells-ads-based-on-how-an-article-makes-you-feel/</guid>
      <description>The New York Times Sells Premium Ads Based on How an Article Makes You Feel.  Rick Edmonds. Poynter. https://www.poynter.org/business-work/2019/the-new-york-times-sells-premium-ads-based-on-how-an-article-makes-you-feel/  . Apr 10, 2019.  The NYT piloted ad placements based on the emotions certain articles evoke.
The average lift to an ad is 40% NYT can charge more for those ads.
Will the newsroom be tasked with producing lots of emotional stories? NYT&amp;rsquo;s claims:
 The newsroom turned out plenty of emotionally charged stories, anyhow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Shady Economics of Buy-One-Get-One Free Deals [The Hustle]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/business/optimism_and_deception/2019-02-17-shady-economics-of-buy-one-get-one-free-deals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/business/optimism_and_deception/2019-02-17-shady-economics-of-buy-one-get-one-free-deals/</guid>
      <description>The Shady Economics of Buy-One-Get-One Free Deals.  Zachary Crockett. The Hustle. https://thehustle.co/are-buy-one-get-one-free-deals-worth-it/  . Feb 17, 2019.  BOGO goods are usually low-demand, non-efficient, lacking in quality and/or close to the expiration date. The BOGO deal is usually a 50% discount off of the manufacturer’s suggested retail price (MSRP). And oftentimes, this price is artificially marked up to begin with.
 MyPillow offered BOGO deal on their pillows, but really just doubled the price of the first pillow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Monetizing Encrypted Messaging by Analyzing Metadata [Twitter]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/www/the-battle-for-the-web/2019-01-25-fb-monetizing-encrypted-messages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/www/the-battle-for-the-web/2019-01-25-fb-monetizing-encrypted-messages/</guid>
      <description>Facebook Monetizing Encrypted Messaging by Analyzing Metadata.  @SarahJamieLewis. https://twitter.com/SarahJamieLewis/status/1088914192847917056  . Jan 25, 2019.  Claim: FB will track relationships and social groups and make that information accessible to law enforcement. FB is a corporation that needs to make money; surveillance makes them money.
Contention: Actual privacy and security must protect metadata as well as content.
 Cwtch by OpenPrivacy   aims to minimize metadata exposed by apps used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monopolistic Tendencies in the Prescription Glasses Industry</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/health-and-medicine/2019-01-22-why-are-glasses-so-expensive/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/health-and-medicine/2019-01-22-why-are-glasses-so-expensive/</guid>
      <description>Luxottica - Queen of the Seven Kingdoms  Luxottica owns and licenses Armani, Brooks Brothers, Burberry, Chanel, Coach, DKNY, Dolce &amp;amp; Gabbana, Michael Kors, Oakley, Oliver Peoples, Persol, Polo Ralph Lauren, Ray-Ban, Tiffany, Valentino, Vogue and Versace.
Italy&amp;rsquo;s Luxottica also runs EyeMed Vision Care, LensCrafters, Pearle Vision, Sears Optical, Sunglass Hut and Target Optical. It also merged with the world&amp;rsquo;s leading maker of prescription eyeglass lenses and contact lenses, to form EssilorLuxottica.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Probably Won&#39;t Make it to the Top [DHH]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/personal_growth/letting_go/2018-11-22-dhh-you-probably-wont-make-it-to-the-top/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/personal_growth/letting_go/2018-11-22-dhh-you-probably-wont-make-it-to-the-top/</guid>
      <description>You Probably Won&amp;#39;t Make it to the Top.  David Heinemeier Hansson (DHH). Signal vs. Noise. https://m.signalvnoise.com/youre-probably-won-t-make-it-to-the-top-8d2146abb790  . Nov 22, 2018.  Fallacy: If you really set your mind to it, you can do it&amp;hellip; That’s how I did it. I just wanted it more, worked hard, and eventually all my dreams came true. I won’t say it’s easy, but it’s up to you!
Odds are overwhelmingly that you will not make it to the top.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Humble Exits [Morgan Housel]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/personal_growth/letting_go/2018-10-24-housel-humble-exits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/personal_growth/letting_go/2018-10-24-housel-humble-exits/</guid>
      <description>Humble Exits.  Morgan Housel. The Collaborative Fund. https://www.collaborativefund.com/blog/humble-exits/  . Oct 24, 2018.  Jack Welch declined $110m for a 10th season of Seinfeld because he was done with the show. He wanted to end the show on the same kind of peak.
The show was based on recreating real events from his and Larry David&amp;rsquo;s normal life. They were running out of material because it had been so long since they experienced a normal life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Does a Market Work? [CS Colloquia]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/trading-and-investing/2018-10-01-how-does-a-market-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/trading-and-investing/2018-10-01-how-does-a-market-work/</guid>
      <description>Objectives: low latency, high throughput &amp;amp; high reliability.
The messages are quite brief, e.g. the ITCH protocol uses 32 bytes per message.
Trading firm listens to broadcasts on buys, sells, deletes on ITCH broadcasts. Online sorting to identify profitable trades.
Matching engine operates on a first-come-first-served basis. Earlier orders with better price get traded first.
Markets run at 50 microsecond scales.
Single market peaks at 10Gbps. Peaks are correlated, e.g. &amp;ldquo;Shit!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Chinese Govt Controls the Media [SoECS]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/politics-and-governance/2018-10-01-chinese-media-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/politics-and-governance/2018-10-01-chinese-media-control/</guid>
      <description>Seeing government influence through coordination of sensitive coverage, localization of negative news &amp;amp; crowding out other stories on the front page.
Structural topic models (LDA + context, e.g. topic prevalence, choice of words) analyze fundamental aspect of the news that can&amp;rsquo;t be changed.
Instead of assuming news follows events, investigate!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kernighan&#39;s Remarks on the Digital Humanities</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/miscellaneous/2018-10-01-digital-humanities-with-kernighan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/miscellaneous/2018-10-01-digital-humanities-with-kernighan/</guid>
      <description>OCR tends to miss (sometimes) really important context.
Make use of derived data, e.g. age at marriage, gender differences, mortality rates, mapping migrations, last names
Don&amp;rsquo;t spend all your time cleaning data.
Try a sequence of things, not one big idea.
Don&amp;rsquo;t expect existing tools to do the whole job. All the while, building new tools is not as straightforward.
Sample Digital Humanities Projects  ORBIS by Stanford  . A kayak for the Roman Era.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons Learned in Tech Policy [SoECS]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/politics-and-governance/2018-10-01-lessons-learned-in-tech-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/politics-and-governance/2018-10-01-lessons-learned-in-tech-policy/</guid>
      <description>Local governments face severe constraints. Liaising with big tech for employees on sabbaticals could alleviate this.
State legislators may have unfounded opinions, but they have the sway, so work with them.
Rural-urban differences. Rural folk were more active. Urban folks wrote angry blogs and that was it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wolf that Tried to Play Nice [SoECS]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/business/optimism_and_deception/2018-10-01-the-wolf-that-tried-to-play-nice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/business/optimism_and_deception/2018-10-01-the-wolf-that-tried-to-play-nice/</guid>
      <description>AT&amp;amp;T restricted FaceTime from running on some data plans. Justifications?
 FaceTime is preloaded, therefore 100% of users have it FaceTime wasn&amp;rsquo;t efficient in network usage. The capacity was asymmetrical, but video chat is symmetrical  Interestingly enough, AT&amp;amp;T required Apple to greenlight it, which they did. AT&amp;amp;T worked with top developers to teach network etiquette.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computers Can Solve Your Problem. You May Not Like the Answer. [Boston Globe]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/miscellaneous/2018-09-21-boston-public-school-equity-algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/miscellaneous/2018-09-21-boston-public-school-equity-algorithm/</guid>
      <description>Computers Can Solve Your Problem. You May Not Like the Answer. : The algorithm had four guiding principles:
 Increase # of high school students starting after 8am Decrease # of elementary school students dismissed after 4pm Accommodate the needs of special education students Generate transportation savings  Unprecedented opposition to the algorithm&amp;rsquo;s solution. Angry parents signed petitions and stormed the school committee. BPS dropped the solution.
Complications:
 Younger students were being forced into earlier start hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On DNA Testing</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/health-and-medicine/2018-09-18-on-dna-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/health-and-medicine/2018-09-18-on-dna-testing/</guid>
      <description>The human genome has sequences of nucleotide base pairs that are repeated over and over again. At each locus of interest, a person has two sets of repeats inherited from each parent. Each possible difference at a locus is an allele. The combinations of the possible differences at multiple loci form a DNA profile that can be used to tie suspects to a crime scene. 
The Accuracy of DNA Testing is Wanting  74/108 crime labs erroneously incriminated a suspect during a mock study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Mathematicians Can&#39;t Find the Hay in a Haystack [Quanta Magazine]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/mathematics/2018-09-17-cant-find-hay-in-a-hay-stack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/mathematics/2018-09-17-cant-find-hay-in-a-hay-stack/</guid>
      <description>Why Mathematicians Can’t Find the Hay in a Haystack.  Kevin Hartnett. https://www.quantamagazine.org/why-mathematicians-cant-find-the-hay-in-a-haystack-20180917/  . Sep 17, 2018.  Irrational numbers occupy most of the number line. If you were to pick a number on the number line at random, there is literally a 100% chance that it will be irrational (probabilities with inifinities are spooky). Yet, we almost never encounter irrational numbers for we can&amp;rsquo;t write them down.
The shapes we know best - lines, parabolas, circles, spheres - are the needles, for they can be expressed by simple equations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google&#39;s Project Dragonfly [The Intercept]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/politics-and-governance/2018-08-01-google-project-dragonfly/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/politics-and-governance/2018-08-01-google-project-dragonfly/</guid>
      <description>Google Plans to Launch Censored Search Engine in China, Leaked Documents Reveal [The Intercept].  Ryan Gallagher. The Intercept. https://theintercept.com/2018/08/01/google-china-search-engine-censorship/  . Aug 1, 2018.  Project Dragonfly A censored version of Google search that blacklists websites and search terms about human rights, democracy, religion and peaceful protests.
China has 750m people; 80% of its internet access is on Android. There&amp;rsquo;s $$$ to be made.
Between 2006 and 2010, Google had maintained a censored Google Search, but was heavily criticized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Average Age of a Successful Startup Founder is 45 [Harvard Business]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/business/on-starting-a-business/2018-07-11-average-age-of-successful-founder-is-45/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/business/on-starting-a-business/2018-07-11-average-age-of-successful-founder-is-45/</guid>
      <description>The Average Age of a Successful Startup Founder is 45.  Harvard Business Review. https://hbr.org/2018/07/research-the-average-age-of-a-successful-startup-founder-is-45  . Jul 11, 2018.  There&amp;rsquo;s a variation among industries: software tends to 40, while oil/gas/biotech tends to 47.
Even Gates, Jobs, Bezos, Brin &amp;amp; Page had their growth rates peak when they were middle aged.
Different definitions of success, e.g. employment growth, sales growth, IPO/acquisition, came to the same conclusion.
VCs may not be looking for growth potential.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Love B2B over B2C [Atrium]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/business/on-starting-a-business/2018-07-11-why-i-love-b2b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/business/on-starting-a-business/2018-07-11-why-i-love-b2b/</guid>
      <description>Why I Love B2B over B2C.  Justin Kan. Atrium. https://www.atrium.co/blog/b2b-vs-b2c/  . Jul 11, 2018.  B2B customers will actually pay for your product. You have a clear execution path - they&amp;rsquo;ll tell you and pay for features. Companies don&amp;rsquo;t quickly flip flop between products. Consumers are too price sensitive and finicky.
B2B customers are rational, and thus understandable. They care about whether a solution solves their problem and if the solution is important enough to pay for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Morgan Housel) Immeasurably Important</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/personal_growth/an_outlook_on_life/2018-07-01-housel-immeasurably-important/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/personal_growth/an_outlook_on_life/2018-07-01-housel-immeasurably-important/</guid>
      <description>Immeasurably Important.  Morgan Housel. Collaborative Fund. http://www.collaborativefund.com/blog/immeasurably-important/  . Jul 5, 2018.  Filtering out information is an art, not a science, necessitated by the information overload that we live in.
 Watch out for the tendency to only preserve information that meshes with how we think the world should be. If you think the world is all art, you miss how much stuff is too complicated to think about intuitively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IBM Watson&#39;s Health Saga</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/health-and-medicine/2018-06-25-ibm-watsons-health-saga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/health-and-medicine/2018-06-25-ibm-watsons-health-saga/</guid>
      <description>Layoffs at Watson Health Reveal IBM’s Problem with AI.  Eliza Strickland. IEEE. https://spectrum.ieee.org/the-human-os/robotics/artificial-intelligence/layoffs-at-watson-health-reveal-ibms-problem-with-ai  . https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17393560  . Jun 25, 2018.  Jefferies gives IBM Watson a Wall Street reality check.  John Mannes. https://techcrunch.com/2017/07/13/jefferies-gives-ibm-watson-a-wall-street-reality-check/  . https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=14766793  . Jul 13, 2017.    IBM acquired Phytel, Explorys and Truven for their troves of healthcare data and proprietary analytics.
  From 2010 to 2015, IBM has spent +$15bn and Watson is still not profitable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>U.S. Files Criminal Charges Against Elizabeth Holmes and Ramesh Balwani [WSJ]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/health-and-medicine/2018-06-15-theranos-disaster/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/health-and-medicine/2018-06-15-theranos-disaster/</guid>
      <description>U.S. Files Criminal Charges Against Elizabeth Holmes and Ramesh Balwani.  John Carreyrou. The Wall Street Journal. https://www.wsj.com/articles/u-s-files-criminal-charges-against-theranoss-elizabeth-holmes-ramesh-balwani-1529096005  . https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17323485  . Jun 15, 2018.  (Ask HN) Holmes has 200 Patents. If tech didn&amp;#39;t work, why not noticed?  Hacker News. https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17328664  . Jun 18, 2018.  Theranos Lessons.  Morgan Housel. Collaborative Fund&amp;#39;s Blog. https://www.collaborativefund.com/blog/theranos-lessons/  . Jun 19, 2019.  This CEO is Out for Blood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Psychology of Money [Morgan Housel]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/personal_growth/an_outlook_on_life/2018-06-01-housel-psychology-of-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/personal_growth/an_outlook_on_life/2018-06-01-housel-psychology-of-money/</guid>
      <description>The Psychology of Money.  Morgan Housel. The Collaborative Fund. http://www.collaborativefund.com/blog/the-psychology-of-money/  . Jun 1, 2018.  People underestimate the role played by luck. Given \(N\) investors, if \(N\) is large enough, a couple of them will luck their way into billions.
But every investor seems to be doing due diligence. The successful ones will be more convinced that their methods really work.
Considering the amount of investing books out there, we should be seeing a lot more Warren Buffets in the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Deep Work &amp; The 30-Hour Method for Learning a New Skill</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/knowing/2018-05-26-azeria-labs-importance-of-deep-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/knowing/2018-05-26-azeria-labs-importance-of-deep-work/</guid>
      <description>The Importance of Deep Work &amp;amp; The 30-Hour Method for Learning a New Skill.  Azeria Labs. https://azeria-labs.com/the-importance-of-deep-work-the-30-hour-method-for-learning-a-new-skill/  . https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17163251  .  30 Hour Deep Work Tryout:
 Scan resources and pick the ones that seem most useful (5 hours) Set up the environment and define structured goals (3 hours) Work towards increasingly difficult goals set in step 2 (22 hours)  Each session should be about 4 hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Apology for the Internet - How It Went Wrong [Intelligencer]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/www/the-battle-for-the-web/2018-04-16-an-apology-for-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/www/the-battle-for-the-web/2018-04-16-an-apology-for-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>An Apology for the Internet - How It Went Wrong.  Noah Kulwin. NY Mag. http://nymag.com/intelligencer/2018/04/an-apology-for-the-internet-from-the-people-who-built-it.html  . Apr 16, 2018.  Start with hippie good intentions. A generation embracing new technology as a tool to transform the world for good.
 Can Duruk: You were going to Facebook not to work but to make the world more open and connected.  Mix in capitalism on steroids. To save the world, you first need to take it over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cambridge Analytica Uncovered</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/politics-and-governance/2018-03-19-cambridge-analytica-uncovered/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/politics-and-governance/2018-03-19-cambridge-analytica-uncovered/</guid>
      <description>Cambridge Analytica Uncovered  Pay people to take surveys but through an app. Mine their profile data, and also crawl their friends.
Identify swayable voters and their sensitivities. Craft targeted ads. Play on (unconscious) fears and hopes.
Elections are about emotions, not facts. Data science and social media can help us make sense of and manipulate the chaos.
An alternative argument: political misinformation is&amp;hellip;
 Weak in high profile partisan races because pre-existing beliefs hardly change Strong when people don&amp;rsquo;t have string pre-existing opinions, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Betting on Things That Never Change [Morgan Housel]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/trading-and-investing/2017-07-20-betting-on-things-that-never-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/trading-and-investing/2017-07-20-betting-on-things-that-never-change/</guid>
      <description>Betting on Things That Never Change.  Morgan Housel. Collaborative Fund. https://www.collaborativefund.com/blog/betting-on-things-that-never-change/  . Jul 20, 2017.  Change by itself is hard. Investors have to spot it before it&amp;rsquo;s obvious. Consumers have to change their behaviors to make it viable. These two points repel each other.
Sears bet the Internet changed nothing. Beenz bet the Internet changed everything - creating a points-based currency valid only at online merchants. Amazon bet the Internet changed distribution, but rooted its strategy in selection and low prices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Syll) What is Ergodicity?</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/knowing/2016-11-23-syll-what-is-ergodicity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/knowing/2016-11-23-syll-what-is-ergodicity/</guid>
      <description>What is Ergodicity?  Lars P. Syll. https://larspsyll.wordpress.com/2016/11/23/what-is-ergodicity-2/  . Nov 23, 2016.  A random process is ergodic if all of its statistics can be determined from a sample function of the process. That is, the ensemble averages equal the corresponding time averages with probability one.
Role of Ergodicity in Human Inference  A newspaper has previously printed some inaccurate information, therefore, the newspaper is going to publish inaccurate information in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Trade of the Century: When George Soros Broke the British Pound [Priceonomics]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/trading-and-investing/2016-06-17-when-soros-broke-the-british-pound/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/trading-and-investing/2016-06-17-when-soros-broke-the-british-pound/</guid>
      <description>The Trade of the Century: When George Soros Broke the British Pound.  Rohin Dhar. Priceonomics. https://priceonomics.com/the-trade-of-the-century-when-george-soros-broke/  . Jun 17, 2016.  Before the EU, Europe had the ERM to fix their exchange rates with the Deutschmark within 6% of the agreed upon rate.
Keeping the exchange rate fixed requires governments to nudge the rate, e.g.
 Use reserves of foreign currency to buy up their own currency Set high interest rates to entice lenders to buy their currency  Margaret Thatcher (PM) opposed the fixed exchange rates but lost the vote to Major, an ERM proponent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Paul Graham) Life is Short</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/personal_growth/an_outlook_on_life/2016-01-01-pg-bullshit-minimizing-path/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/personal_growth/an_outlook_on_life/2016-01-01-pg-bullshit-minimizing-path/</guid>
      <description>Life is Short.  Paul Graham. http://www.paulgraham.com/vb.html  . Jan 1, 2016.  Some of it is our own fault (e.g. arguing online). Some of it is forced by circumstances that we choose to endure (e.g. unnecessary meetings at work)
Choosing a bullshit minimizing path is error-prone. Your priorities change over time. Periodically evaluate where you are. It helps to have measurable aspects of your life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So You Want to Reform Democracy [Medium]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/politics-and-governance/2015-11-22-so-you-want-to-reform-democracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/politics-and-governance/2015-11-22-so-you-want-to-reform-democracy/</guid>
      <description>So You Want to Reform Democracy.  Joshua Tauberer. https://medium.com/civic-tech-thoughts-from-joshdata/so-you-want-to-reform-democracy-7f3b1ef10597  . Nov 22, 2015.  If there was an idea that could &amp;lsquo;fix&amp;rsquo; democracy, it would have been thought-up already. If you don&amp;rsquo;t see your idea out there, it’s because it didn’t work the hundreds of other times someone tried it.
Let’s tell representatives what their constituents think. Then they HAVE to vote with us!
 They don’t necessarily want to know what their constituents are thinking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Slate Star Codex) No Clarity Around Growth Mindset</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/personal_growth/letting_go/2015-04-08-ssc-no-clarity-around-the-growth-mindset/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/personal_growth/letting_go/2015-04-08-ssc-no-clarity-around-the-growth-mindset/</guid>
      <description>No Clarity Around Growth Mindset.  Scott Alexander. Slate Star Codex. https://slatestarcodex.com/2015/04/08/no-clarity-around-growth-mindset-yet/  . Apr 8, 2015.  Growth mindset: people who believe effort - and not ability - determines success are more resilient, skillful, hard-working, perseverant in the face of failure.
Most of the growth mindset experiments prime their subjects, but recent priming experiments have famously failed to replicate. Dweck&amp;rsquo;s experiment:
 Group A: easy test (success) -&amp;gt; final bound-to-fail test Group B: hard test (told they&amp;rsquo;re not working hard enough) -&amp;gt; final bound-to-fail test Group B outperformed Group A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Yudkowsky) Letting Go</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/personal_growth/letting_go/2015-12-01-yudkowsky-letting-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/personal_growth/letting_go/2015-12-01-yudkowsky-letting-go/</guid>
      <description>Letting Go.  Eliezer Yudkowsky. Rationality: From AI to Zombies. Feb 1, 2015.  Learn when to admit failure It&amp;rsquo;s important to have a watershed moment and acknowledge a fundamental problem, instead of dividing it into palatable bite-size mistakes.
LTCM were exploiting market inefficiencies. Other people learned of the tricks. LTCM didn&amp;rsquo;t lose hope. They borrowed more and more leverage to exploit tinier and tinier margins.
And their math probably said the leverage was okay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (SSC) The Parable of the Talents</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/personal_growth/an_outlook_on_life/2015-01-31-ssc-the-principle-of-the-talents/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/personal_growth/an_outlook_on_life/2015-01-31-ssc-the-principle-of-the-talents/</guid>
      <description>The Parable of the Talents.  Scott Alexander. Slate Star Codex. https://slatestarcodex.com/2015/01/31/the-parable-of-the-talents/  . Jan 31, 2015.  Overweight people, depressed people, and poor people aren’t fully to blame for their situation – and neither are unintelligent people. It’s accidents of birth all the way down.
Srinivasa Ramanujan:
 Grew up in poverty in a one-room house in small-town India. But a lot of poor people in the US had better conditions/opportunities  Either, a lot of intelligence is innate Or, those poor people are just not trying hard enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do Things That Don&#39;t Scale [Paul Graham]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/business/on-starting-a-business/2013-07-01-do-things-that-dont-scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/business/on-starting-a-business/2013-07-01-do-things-that-dont-scale/</guid>
      <description>Do Things That Don&amp;#39;t Scale.  Paul Graham. http://www.paulgraham.com/ds.html  . Jul 1, 2013.  Recruit manually. Don&amp;rsquo;t send links. Set them up on the spot.
Ask how big the startup would be if you did the right things, not whether you&amp;rsquo;re currently changing the world.
Delight your initial customers. Tim Cook can&amp;rsquo;t send handwritten notes, but you can.
If you can solve the problem manually, do so while gradually automating the most pressing bottlenecks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Doctors Die [Zocalo]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/personal_growth/letting_go/2011-11-30-how-doctors-die/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/personal_growth/letting_go/2011-11-30-how-doctors-die/</guid>
      <description>How Doctors Die.  Zocalo Public Square. https://www.zocalopublicsquare.org/2011/11/30/how-doctors-die/ideas/nexus/  .  Doctors tend to be fairly serene when faced with death themselves. They know enough about modern medicine to know its limits. They go gently into that good night - no heroics; no CPR.
Sometimes, a family really means &amp;lsquo;do everything&amp;rsquo;, but often they mean &amp;lsquo;do everything that’s reasonable.&amp;rsquo; But they may not know what’s reasonable.
People have unrealistic expectations of what doctors can accomplish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Submarine [Paul Graham]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/business/optimism_and_deception/2005-04-01-the-submarine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/business/optimism_and_deception/2005-04-01-the-submarine/</guid>
      <description>The Submarine.  Paul Graham. http://www.paulgraham.com/submarine.html  . Apr 1, 2005.  Many people rely on social proof to form opinions; therein lies the power of PR.
PR firms are not dishonest for they need good reputation with news outlets. But PR firms serve overworked reporters with selective truths.
The firms feed the same story to different publications at once. Readers see similar stories in multiple places and assume a new trend has come.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
