<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Health Care on Chege&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/tags/health-care/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Health Care on Chege&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.curiosities.dev/tags/health-care/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Is Dentistry a Science? [The Atlantic]</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/2019-05-01-is-dentistry-a-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/2019-05-01-is-dentistry-a-science/</guid>
      <description>Is Dentistry a Science?  Ferris Jabr. www.theatlantic.com  . May 1, 2019.    Cochrane Oral Health   reviews dental procedures in a systematic manner. Unfortunately, most of the reviews don&amp;rsquo;t find substantive support for dental interventions.
There is currently no substantive evidence for: binannual cleanings, fluoridation reducing tooth decay in adults; regular flossing combating plaque (gum disease? probably); preventative wisdom teeth removal; tooth-colored resin instead of metal amalgam fillings; crown vs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monopolistic Tendencies in the Prescription Glasses Industry</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/2019-01-22-why-are-glasses-so-expensive/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/2019-01-22-why-are-glasses-so-expensive/</guid>
      <description>Luxottica - Queen of the Seven Kingdoms  Luxottica owns and licenses Armani, Brooks Brothers, Burberry, Chanel, Coach, DKNY, Dolce &amp;amp; Gabbana, Michael Kors, Oakley, Oliver Peoples, Persol, Polo Ralph Lauren, Ray-Ban, Tiffany, Valentino, Vogue and Versace.
Italy&amp;rsquo;s Luxottica also runs EyeMed Vision Care, LensCrafters, Pearle Vision, Sears Optical, Sunglass Hut and Target Optical. It also merged with the world&amp;rsquo;s leading maker of prescription eyeglass lenses and contact lenses, to form EssilorLuxottica.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Doctors Die [Zocalo]</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/personal_growth/letting_go/2011-11-30-how-doctors-die/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/personal_growth/letting_go/2011-11-30-how-doctors-die/</guid>
      <description>How Doctors Die.  Ken Murray. www.zocalopublicsquare.org  . Nov 30, 2011.   Doctors tend to be fairly serene when faced with death themselves. They know enough about modern medicine to know its limits. They go gently into that good night - no heroics; no CPR.
Sometimes, a family really means &amp;lsquo;do everything&amp;rsquo;, but often they mean &amp;lsquo;do everything that’s reasonable.&amp;rsquo; But they may not know what’s reasonable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Dentists Rip Us Off [William Ecenbarger]</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/1997-02-01-how-dentists-rip-us-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 1997 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/1997-02-01-how-dentists-rip-us-off/</guid>
      <description>How Dentists Rip Us Off.  William Ecenbarger. digitalsmiledesign.com  . Feb 1, 1997.   This piece was brought up in &amp;ldquo;Is Dentistry a Science?&amp;quot;   ( summary  ). Looks like this piece has done its rounds in dentist online spaces.
  Ecenbarger pitch: moving into the area; had done gum surgery; had a direct-reimbursement program to cover expenses; interested in good oral health; no desire for cosmetic improvements</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
