<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computer Science &amp; Software Engineering on Chege&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Computer Science &amp; Software Engineering on Chege&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Oct 1974 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Signal Is Finally Bringing Its Secure Messaging To the Masses [Andy Greenberg]</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/2020-02-14-signal-secure-messaging-to-the-masses/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/2020-02-14-signal-secure-messaging-to-the-masses/</guid>
      <description>Signal Is Finally Bringing Its Secure Messaging To the Masses.  Andy Greenberg. www.wired.com  . it.slashdot.org  . news.ycombinator.com  . Feb 14, 2020.   Attracting the Masses Brian Acton (WhatsApp cofounder) injected $50m into the Signal Foundation, allowing them to grow from 3 to 50 full-timers.
You&amp;rsquo;d think that at Signal&amp;rsquo;s dominance, getting $$$ shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a problem. But VCs expect a multiple return and Signal doesn&amp;rsquo;t look like it will monetize soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Engineering Journal Reviews</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/2022-01-16-swe-journal-reviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/2022-01-16-swe-journal-reviews/</guid>
      <description>Formal Software Design Alloy is an open-source language and analyzer for software modeling. An Alloy model is a collection of constraints that describe a set of structures, e.g. all possible security configurations of a web application. Alloy&amp;rsquo;s tool, the Alloy Analyzer is a solver that takes the constraints of a model and finds structures that satisfy them. 
📑    The Alloy Analyzer leverages a SAT solver, and this precludes Alloy from analyzing optimization problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Socio-Economic Equity in Tech</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/2021-10-28-socio-economic-equity-in-tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/2021-10-28-socio-economic-equity-in-tech/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to STEM diversity goals, Asian American and Pacific Islander (AAPI) tends to be excluded from the URMs under discussion, e.g. .
However, AAPI as a blanket term obscures the struggles of member groups, e.g. \(62\%\) of AAPI adults aged 24 and older have an associate&amp;rsquo;s degree or higher, compared to 28% of Native Hawaiians and Pacific Islanders of the same age. AA comprises \(\approx 50\) ethnic groups, while PI has \(\approx 20\).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Areas of Interest in Computer Science</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/2021-04-12-interest-areas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/2021-04-12-interest-areas/</guid>
      <description>Maybe a good approximation is where Google Research is spending $$$
  : Algorithms and Optimization; Augmented Reality and Virtual Reality; Geo; Human Computer Interaction; Health Research; Machine Learning and Data Mining; Mobile; Machine Perception; Networking; Natural Language Processing; Privacy; Quantum Computing; Structured Data, Extraction, Semantic Graph, and Database Management; Security; Software Engineering and Programming Languages; Systems; Misc.
  Research Scholar Program recipients.  research.google  . Apr 7, 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer Graphics Potpourri</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/computer-graphics/2021-01-03-potpourri/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/computer-graphics/2021-01-03-potpourri/</guid>
      <description>Retained Mode vs. Immediate Mode In retained mode, the graphics library exposes an API to the application for building/updating a scene. However, the graphics library is in charge of issuing drawing commands. In contrast, an immediate-mode API allows the application to issue the drawing commands. Retained-mode APIs abstract away initialization, state maintenance and cleanup, but uses more memory. Immediate-mode APIs allow for more targeted optimizations. 
https://reactjs.org/ is one of the more popular retained-mode web APIs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Information Retrieval Medley</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/2021-01-03-information-retrieval-medley/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/2021-01-03-information-retrieval-medley/</guid>
      <description>Pagination with Relative Cursors  Exposing pagination through URLs like example.com/items?page=25&amp;amp;limit=100 leads to SQL like SELECT * from &#39;items&#39; LIMIT 100 OFFSET 2400;, which inefficiently goes through 2,500 records and discards the first 2,400.
With relative cursors, we have URLs like example.com/items?limit=50&amp;amp;lastID=XXX, which leads to SQL like SELECT * from &#39;items&#39; WHERE &#39;id&#39; &amp;gt; XXX ORDER BY &#39;id&#39; ASC LIMIT 50, and this is more efficient, assuming there are indexes for id.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Systems Programming</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/2020-11-21-on-systems-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/2020-11-21-on-systems-programming/</guid>
      <description>Garbage Collection Garbage Collection is about simulating a computer with infinite memory. Consequently, if you have more RAM than your program will ever need, then a null garbage collector is a valid one.  
Traits of Beautiful Code   is the chief designer of Ruby, and thus the frequent illustrations and praises for Ruby.
How do other chief designers explain their rationale? For instance, what would Java&amp;rsquo;s designer say to &amp;rsquo;s criticism?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Dependencies</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/2020-11-14-software-dependencies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/2020-11-14-software-dependencies/</guid>
      <description>Dependency Management Golang introduced a new library referencing mode to overcome limitations of the old one. While the two library modes are supported by Golang, they are incompatible, e.g. dependency management (DM) issues, reference inconsistencies, build failures, etc.  did an empirical study that resulted in HERO, an automated technique to detect DM issues and suggest fixes. Applied to 19k Golang projects, HERO detected 98.5% on a DM issue benchmark, and found 2,422 new DM issues in 2,356 Golang projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Distributed Systems</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/2020-05-17-distributed-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/2020-05-17-distributed-systems/</guid>
      <description>Mergeable Replicated Data Types  On a distributed system, each replica should [eventually] converge to the same state. Commutative Replicated Data Types (CRDTs) can accept updates and achieve consistent without remote synchronization.
The Need for Commutativity Say we have a queue \( 1 \to 2 \). Suppose two replicas, \(r_1\) and \(r_2\), independently call pop(). Each replica will have \(2\) on their queue.
However, on receiving an update that the other replica popped, each replica will call pop() to be consistent, thereby deleting \(2\).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
