<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Free Speech on c13u&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.c13u.com/tags/free-speech/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Free Speech on c13u&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.c13u.com/tags/free-speech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Politics of Free Speech</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/www/the-battle-for-the-web/2020-04-29-politics-of-free-speech/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/www/the-battle-for-the-web/2020-04-29-politics-of-free-speech/</guid>
      <description>Should Platforms Be Neutral? Facebook banned praise, support and representation of white nationalism and separatism, because the two concepts cannot be meaningfully separated from white supremacy and organized hate groups. Furthermore, people that search for related terms will have &amp;ldquo;Life After Hate&amp;rdquo; suggested to them. []
Part of me is uncomfortable. Sure, Facebook is trying to do the right thing here. What if Facebook was replaced by some tyrannical government that censors opposition?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Chinese Govt Controls the Media [SoECS]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/politics-and-governance/2018-10-01-chinese-media-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/politics-and-governance/2018-10-01-chinese-media-control/</guid>
      <description>Seeing government influence through coordination of sensitive coverage, localization of negative news &amp;amp; crowding out other stories on the front page.
Structural topic models (LDA + context, e.g. topic prevalence, choice of words) analyze fundamental aspect of the news that can&amp;rsquo;t be changed.
Instead of assuming news follows events, investigate!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google&#39;s Project Dragonfly [The Intercept]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/politics-and-governance/2018-08-01-google-project-dragonfly/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/politics-and-governance/2018-08-01-google-project-dragonfly/</guid>
      <description>Google Plans to Launch Censored Search Engine in China, Leaked Documents Reveal [The Intercept].  Ryan Gallagher. The Intercept. https://theintercept.com/2018/08/01/google-china-search-engine-censorship/ . Aug 1, 2018.  Project Dragonfly A censored version of Google search that blacklists websites and search terms about human rights, democracy, religion and peaceful protests.
China has 750m people; 80% of its internet access is on Android. There&amp;rsquo;s $$$ to be made.
Between 2006 and 2010, Google had maintained a censored Google Search, but was heavily criticized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cambridge Analytica Uncovered</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/politics-and-governance/2018-03-19-cambridge-analytica-uncovered/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/politics-and-governance/2018-03-19-cambridge-analytica-uncovered/</guid>
      <description>Cambridge Analytica Uncovered [] Pay people to take surveys but through an app. Mine their profile data, and also crawl their friends.
Identify swayable voters and their sensitivities. Craft targeted ads. Play on (unconscious) fears and hopes.
Elections are about emotions, not facts. Data science and social media can help us make sense of and manipulate the chaos.
An alternative argument: political misinformation is&amp;hellip;
 Weak in high profile partisan races because pre-existing beliefs hardly change Strong when people don&amp;rsquo;t have string pre-existing opinions, e.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
