<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fairness on c13u&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.c13u.com/tags/fairness/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fairness on c13u&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.c13u.com/tags/fairness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rage Against the Algorithm</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/miscellaneous/2021-07-04-rage-against-the-algo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/miscellaneous/2021-07-04-rage-against-the-algo/</guid>
      <description>The lack of explanability is a common theme. Higher-ups claim the machine is unbiased, while the workers on the ground say, &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not me; it&amp;rsquo;s the computer&amp;rdquo;.
 Automating Inequality: How High-tech Tools Profile, Police, and Punish the Poor   should be an enlightening read.
  Computers Can Solve Your Problem. You May Not Like the Answer  The algorithm had four guiding principles:
 Increase # of high school students starting after 8am Decrease # of elementary school students dismissed after 4pm Accommodate the needs of special education students Generate transportation savings  Unprecedented opposition to the algorithm&amp;rsquo;s solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Dangers of Stochastic Parrots: Can Language Models Be Too Big? 🦜</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/machine-learning/perspectives-on-ml/2021-03-03-on-the-dangers-of-stochastic-parrots/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/machine-learning/perspectives-on-ml/2021-03-03-on-the-dangers-of-stochastic-parrots/</guid>
      <description>The paper is written in a period when NLP practitioners are producing bigger (# of parameters; size of training data) language models (LMs), and pushing the top scores on benchmarks.
  Environmental Risks Large LMs consume a lot of resources, e.g. training a single BERT base model on GPUs was estimated to use as much energy as a trans-American flight.
Marginalized communities are doubly punished. They are least likely to benefit from LMs, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On DNA Testing</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/health-and-medicine/2018-09-18-on-dna-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/health-and-medicine/2018-09-18-on-dna-testing/</guid>
      <description>The human genome has sequences of nucleotide base pairs that are repeated over and over again. At each locus of interest, a person has two sets of repeats inherited from each parent. Each possible difference at a locus is an allele. The combinations of the possible differences at multiple loci form a DNA profile that can be used to tie suspects to a crime scene. 
The Accuracy of DNA Testing is Wanting  74/108 crime labs erroneously incriminated a suspect during a mock study.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
