<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Fairness on Chege's Blog</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/tags/fairness/</link><description>Recent content in Fairness on Chege's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.curiosities.dev/tags/fairness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Computational Bias and Fairness</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/bias-and-fairness/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/bias-and-fairness/</guid><description> Check out CMSC 20370/30370: Inclusive Technology: Design For Underserved and Marginalized Communities , and other similar courses. CMSC 20370 references a lot of papers from ACM&amp;rsquo;s CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems .</description></item><item><title>LLMs: Stochastic Parrots 🦜 and How (Not) to Use Them</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/large-language-models/stochastic-parrots/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/large-language-models/stochastic-parrots/</guid><description>was written in a period when NLP practitioners are producing bigger (# of parameters; size of training data) language models (LMs), and pushing the top scores on benchmarks. The paper itself was controversial because it led to Gebru being fired from Google, following disagreements with her managers on conditions (withdraw, or remove Google-affiliated authors) for publishing the paper.
A lot changed since mid-2021, when I initially wrote this page.</description></item><item><title>On DNA Testing</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/2018-09-18-on-dna-testing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/2018-09-18-on-dna-testing/</guid><description>The human genome has sequences of nucleotide base pairs that are repeated over and over again. At each locus of interest, a person has two sets of repeats inherited from each parent. Each possible difference at a locus is an allele. The combinations of the possible differences at multiple loci form a DNA profile that can be used to tie suspects to a crime scene.
The Accuracy of DNA Testing is Wanting 74/108 crime labs erroneously incriminated a suspect during a mock study.</description></item></channel></rss>