<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fairness on c13u&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.c13u.com/tags/fairness/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fairness on c13u&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.c13u.com/tags/fairness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Software Picking Sides</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/miscellaneous/2020-07-04-software-picking-sides/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/miscellaneous/2020-07-04-software-picking-sides/</guid>
      <description>Examples The Markup found that 70% of political and racial justice emails to Gmail accounts are placed &amp;ldquo;promotions&amp;rdquo; tab, which isn&amp;rsquo;t as noticeable as the &amp;ldquo;inbox&amp;rdquo; tab. 
Sorting email looks like a hard software problem. If the sender isn&amp;rsquo;t in the phonebook, and Gmail noticed the same sender in thousands of emails to other Gmail accounts, how likely is it that the sender is sending a personal email?
It seems that the onus is on mail list maintainers to instruct users how to make sure that future emails get routed to the &amp;ldquo;primary&amp;rdquo; tab, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computers Can Solve Your Problem. You May Not Like the Answer. [Boston Globe]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/miscellaneous/2018-09-21-boston-public-school-equity-algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/miscellaneous/2018-09-21-boston-public-school-equity-algorithm/</guid>
      <description>Computers Can Solve Your Problem. You May Not Like the Answer. : The algorithm had four guiding principles:
 Increase # of high school students starting after 8am Decrease # of elementary school students dismissed after 4pm Accommodate the needs of special education students Generate transportation savings  Unprecedented opposition to the algorithm&amp;rsquo;s solution. Angry parents signed petitions and stormed the school committee. BPS dropped the solution.
Complications:
 Younger students were being forced into earlier start hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On DNA Testing</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/health-and-medicine/2018-09-18-on-dna-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/health-and-medicine/2018-09-18-on-dna-testing/</guid>
      <description>The human genome has sequences of nucleotide base pairs that are repeated over and over again. At each locus of interest, a person has two sets of repeats inherited from each parent. Each possible difference at a locus is an allele. The combinations of the possible differences at multiple loci form a DNA profile that can be used to tie suspects to a crime scene. 
The Accuracy of DNA Testing is Wanting  74/108 crime labs erroneously incriminated a suspect during a mock study.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
