<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>scholar.google.com on Chege&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/domains/scholar.google.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in scholar.google.com on Chege&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.curiosities.dev/domains/scholar.google.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01. The Case for the Scout Mindset</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/knowing/scout-mindset/01-the-case-for-the-scout-mindset/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/knowing/scout-mindset/01-the-case-for-the-scout-mindset/</guid>
      <description>Two Types of Thinking  Soldier Mindset Reasoning is like defensive combat. Finding out you’re wrong means suffering a defeat. Seeks out evidence to fortify and defend your beliefs.
Directionally motivated reasoning. When we want something to be true, we ask, &amp;ldquo;Can I believe this?&amp;rdquo; When we don&amp;rsquo;t want something to be true, we ask, &amp;ldquo;Must I believe this?&amp;rdquo; 
Scout Mindset Reasoning is like mapmaking. Finding out you’re wrong means revising your map.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02. Developing Self-Awareness</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/knowing/scout-mindset/02-developing-self-awareness/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/knowing/scout-mindset/02-developing-self-awareness/</guid>
      <description>Signs of a Scout  These Don&amp;rsquo;t Make You a Scout Feeling objective. The more objective you feel, the more you trust your own intuitions and opinions as accurate representations of reality, and the less inclined you are to question them.
Being smart and knowledgeable. It&amp;rsquo;s not a case of &amp;ldquo;if people were smarter and well-informed, they&amp;rsquo;d realize their errors&amp;rdquo;. For example,  found that polarization (on political fronts) on anthropogenic climate change increases as scientific intelligence increases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03. Thriving Without Illusions</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/knowing/scout-mindset/03-thriving-without-illusions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/knowing/scout-mindset/03-thriving-without-illusions/</guid>
      <description>Coping with Reality  This chapter felt a bit vacuous with its use of anecdotes to advance points.
  Criticism of studies that argue that self-deception makes us happier: conflation of positive illusions and positive beliefs; unfounded definitions of what counts as self-deception; results that can be equally well-explained by something else.
There are alternative coping strategies that don&amp;rsquo;t involve self-deception: making a hypothetical plan about some unpleasant and unavoidable thing; noticing silver linings but not to the point of sweet lemons; admitting that things could be worse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04. Changing Your Mind</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/knowing/scout-mindset/04-changing-your-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/knowing/scout-mindset/04-changing-your-mind/</guid>
      <description>How to Be Wrong   found that experts were barely able to forecast better than random chance. However, a small subset of people (coined &amp;ldquo;superforecasters&amp;rdquo; ) were better. In a competition, they beat teams of top professors and CIA professional analysts. These superforecasters were not smarter than everyone else nor did they have more knowledge/experience, they were great at being wrong.
Change your mind a little at a time. Seeing the world in shades of grey is less stressful, as the experience of encountering evidence against one of your beliefs is not high stakes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05. Rethinking Identity</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/knowing/scout-mindset/05-rethinking-identity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/knowing/scout-mindset/05-rethinking-identity/</guid>
      <description>How Beliefs Become Identities  Didn&amp;rsquo;t have priors on this. In retrospect, I could have asked: how can I differentiate between a belief and an identity? What are the consequences of a belief becoming an identity?
  Feeling under siege from a hostile world may crystallize a belief into an identity, e.g. formula-feeders feeling judged as bad mothers; evangelical christians feeling alienated by legal and cultural changes like legal abortion, gay marriage and sexualized content in the media.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AoC 2021 Day 08: Seven Segment Search</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/programming-challenges/advent-of-code/2021/src/AoC2021/SevenSegmentSearch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/programming-challenges/advent-of-code/2021/src/AoC2021/SevenSegmentSearch/</guid>
      <description>Day 8 - Advent of Code 2021.  adventofcode.com  .  Accessed Mar 7, 2022.  Part I Description You barely reach the safety of the cave when the whale smashes into the cave mouth, collapsing it. Sensors indicate another exit to this cave at a much greater depth, so you have no choice but to press on.
As your submarine slowly makes its way through the cave system, you notice that the four-digit seven-segment displays in your submarine are malfunctioning; they must have been damaged during the escape.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Engineering Journal Reviews</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/2022-01-16-swe-journal-reviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/2022-01-16-swe-journal-reviews/</guid>
      <description>Formal Software Design Alloy is an open-source language and analyzer for software modeling. An Alloy model is a collection of constraints that describe a set of structures, e.g. all possible security configurations of a web application. Alloy&amp;rsquo;s tool, the Alloy Analyzer is a solver that takes the constraints of a model and finds structures that satisfy them. 
📑    The Alloy Analyzer leverages a SAT solver, and this precludes Alloy from analyzing optimization problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journal Reviews</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/networks/journal-reviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/networks/journal-reviews/</guid>
      <description>Link Prediction Given network-structured data, predict whether a link exists between two nodes.
General types of prediction tasks on graphs: graph-level (e.g. will a molecule bind to a receptor implicated in a disease?), node-level (e.g. what is the identity of each node?), and edge-level (e.g. does this edge exist; what value does it have?). 
  Applications include: predicting drug-drug interactions (common in treating patients with complex/co-existing diseases) as they may cause changes in the drugs&#39; pharmacological activity .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journal Reviews on Fairness</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/bias-and-fairness/2021-10-04-journal-reviews-on-fairness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/bias-and-fairness/2021-10-04-journal-reviews-on-fairness/</guid>
      <description>Meta 📑    Instead of changing the data or learners in multiple ways and then see if fairness improves,  postulate that the root causes of bias are the prior decisions that generated the training data. These affect (a) what data was selected, and (b) the labels assigned to the examples. They propose the \(\text{Fair-SMOTE}\) (Fair Synthetic Minority Over Sampling Technique) algorithm which (1) removes biased labels (via situation testing: if the model&amp;rsquo;s prediction for a data point changes once all of the data points&#39; protected attributes  are flipped, then that label is biased and the data point is discarded), and (2) rebalances internal distributions such that based on a protected attribute, examples are equal in both positive and negative classes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Becoming a Better Point Guard</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/sports/2021-07-13-point-guard-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/sports/2021-07-13-point-guard-journey/</guid>
      <description>Objective: Learn to read the game and make smart predictions. Reaction times are overrated; perception and prediction rule  .
  Offensive Playmaking and Scoring  tracks the following play types: transition, isolation, pick &amp;amp; roll ball handler, pick &amp;amp; roll roll man, post up, spot up, handoff, cut, off screen and put-backs.
At least these categories provide a baseline for what search terms to use.  also has a miscellaneous play type section, so it&amp;rsquo;ll be interesting to see if a new play-type pops up in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rage Against the Algorithm</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/bias-and-fairness/2021-07-04-rage-against-the-algo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/bias-and-fairness/2021-07-04-rage-against-the-algo/</guid>
      <description>The lack of explanability is a common theme. Higher-ups claim the machine is unbiased, while the workers on the ground say, &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not me; it&amp;rsquo;s the computer&amp;rdquo;.
 Automating Inequality: How High-tech Tools Profile, Police, and Punish the Poor   should be an enlightening read.
  Computers Can Solve Your Problem. You May Not Like the Answer  The algorithm had four guiding principles:
 Increase # of high school students starting after 8am Decrease # of elementary school students dismissed after 4pm Accommodate the needs of special education students Generate transportation savings  Unprecedented opposition to the algorithm&amp;rsquo;s solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research on Privacy Enhancing Techniques</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/cos432-information-security/14-privacy/privacy-enhancing-tech/2022-01-23-lit-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/cos432-information-security/14-privacy/privacy-enhancing-tech/2022-01-23-lit-review/</guid>
      <description>Journals  note that prediction services can still make accurate predictions using a fraction of the data collected from a user device. They propose Cloak, which suppresses non-pertinent features (i.e. those features which can consistently tolerate addition of noise without degrading utility) to the prediction task. Cloak has a provable degree of privacy, and unlike cryptographic techniques, does not degrade prediction latency. Using the training data, labels, a pre-trained model and a privacy-utility knob, they (1) find the pertinent features through perturbation training, and (2) learn utility-preserving constant values for suppressing the non-pertinent data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Dependencies</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/2020-11-14-software-dependencies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/2020-11-14-software-dependencies/</guid>
      <description>Dependency Management Golang introduced a new library referencing mode to overcome limitations of the old one. While the two library modes are supported by Golang, they are incompatible, e.g. dependency management (DM) issues, reference inconsistencies, build failures, etc.  did an empirical study that resulted in HERO, an automated technique to detect DM issues and suggest fixes. Applied to 19k Golang projects, HERO detected 98.5% on a DM issue benchmark, and found 2,422 new DM issues in 2,356 Golang projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fables in Service of Capitalism</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/optimism_and_deception/not-a-story-the-capitalists-would-tell-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/optimism_and_deception/not-a-story-the-capitalists-would-tell-you/</guid>
      <description>Environmentalism Over the last 70 years, less than 10% of plastic waste has been recycled - it&amp;rsquo;s uneconomical. Recycling shifts attention from the environmental impact of plastics and their overproduction to the consumer&amp;rsquo;s willingness to recycle. Reducing and reusing is a much better environmental strategy. 
Betting (and Gambling) I&amp;rsquo;m seeing more prominent gambling sites and ads compared to when I was growing up. Based on my peers, SportPesa made lots of headway in Kenya (few companies can claim to sponsor English Premier League teams).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tech and Democracy</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/politics-and-governance/2020-01-27-tech-and-democracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/politics-and-governance/2020-01-27-tech-and-democracy/</guid>
      <description>Political Ads Cambridge Analytica (CA) paid people to take in-app survey; mined FB profile data including friends&#39; data; crafted tailored sensitive ads to sway-able voters. Elections are about emotions, not facts. Data science and social media can help us make sense of and manipulate the chaos. 
An alternative argument. Political misinformation is:
 Weak in high profile partisan races because pre-existing beliefs hardly change Strong when people don&amp;rsquo;t have string pre-existing opinions, e.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
