<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Overly Convenient Excuses on c13u&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/overly_convenient_excuses/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Overly Convenient Excuses on c13u&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/overly_convenient_excuses/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Less Wrong) I Want It My Way</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/overly_convenient_excuses/2019-01-04-lw-i-want-it-my-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/overly_convenient_excuses/2019-01-04-lw-i-want-it-my-way/</guid>
      <description>I Want It My Way!. Nick Hayes. Less Wrong. https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/WiDh3ca3C7GgrNXAn/i-want-it-my-way. 4th Jan, 2019.  Letting go of how you think things should be lets you see how things are. Consequently, you&#39;ll be able to get better results.
Wanting it my way: I believe that failure is bad, and that if I fail, then I personally am I failure. So I have those two things conflated. Then anything I do risks failing, especially new things, so I&#39;d better not do the new things, then.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Yudkowsky) 0 and 1 Are Not Probabilities</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/overly_convenient_excuses/2015-02-01-yudkowsky-0-and-1-are-not-probabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/overly_convenient_excuses/2015-02-01-yudkowsky-0-and-1-are-not-probabilities/</guid>
      <description>0 And 1 Are Not Probabilities. Eliezer Yudkowsky. Rationality: From AI to Zombies. Feb 2015.  $$ O = \frac{P}{1 - P},\ \ \ P = \frac{O}{1 + O} $$
When you transform probabilities to odds, 0 goes to 0, but 1 goes to infinity. Now the absolute truth doesn&#39;t look like it should be easy to reach.
When you transform probabilities to odds, 0.502 and 0.503 goes to 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Yudkowsky) Lotteries</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/overly_convenient_excuses/2015-02-01-yudkowsky-lotteries-a-waste-of-hope/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/overly_convenient_excuses/2015-02-01-yudkowsky-lotteries-a-waste-of-hope/</guid>
      <description>Lotteries: A Waste of Hope. Eliezer Yudkowsky. Rationality: From AI to Zombies. Feb 2015.   New Improved Lottery. Eliezer Yudkowsky. Rationality: From AI to Zombies. Feb 2015.  The lottery is a sink of emotional energy. It encourages people to invest in their dreams, their hopes for a better future, into an infinitesimal probability.
People can&#39;t devalue the emotional force of pleasant anticipation by a factor of .0000001 without dropping the line of reasoning entirely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Yudkowsky) The Proper Use of Humility</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/overly_convenient_excuses/2015-02-01-yudkowsky-the-proper-use-of-humility/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/overly_convenient_excuses/2015-02-01-yudkowsky-the-proper-use-of-humility/</guid>
      <description>The Proper Use of Humility. Eliezer Yudkowsky. Rationality: From AI to Zombies. Feb 2015.  To be humble is to take specific actions in anticipation of your own errors. To confess your fallibility and then do nothing about it is not humble; it is boasting of your modesty.
Good humility: Engineer humbly designs fail-safe mechanisms into machinery, even though they are damn sure the machinery won&#39;t fail.
Bad humility: But who can really know whether evolution is correct?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Yudkowsky) The Third Alternative</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/overly_convenient_excuses/2015-02-01-yudkowsky-the-third-alternative/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/overly_convenient_excuses/2015-02-01-yudkowsky-the-third-alternative/</guid>
      <description>The Third Alternative. Eliezer Yudkowsky. Rationality: From AI to Zombies. Feb 2015.  If Santa-belief is destroyed by truth, the children will lose their sense of wonder and stop behaving nicely. It does not follow that Santa-ism is the best of all possible alternatives.
People justify questionable policy by pointing to a supposed benefit over the null action. The search for alternatives can go on forever, so one needs a stopping criterion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Yudkowsky) There&#39;s Still a Chance, Right?</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/overly_convenient_excuses/2015-02-01-yudkowsky-overly-convenient-theres-still-a-chance-right/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/personal_growth/overly_convenient_excuses/2015-02-01-yudkowsky-overly-convenient-theres-still-a-chance-right/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;#39;s Still a Chance, Right?. Eliezer Yudkowsky. Rationality: From AI to Zombies. Feb 2015.  &amp;ldquo;Humans and chimps have 98% shared DNA.&amp;rdquo; Maybe the DNA is just similar by coincidence. You say the odds are tiny, but there&#39;s still a chance, right?
The problem is that probability theory sometimes lets us calculate a chance which is, indeed, too tiny to be worth the mental space to keep track of it - but by that time, you&#39;ve already calculated it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>