<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technology on c13u&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.c13u.com/tags/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technology on c13u&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.c13u.com/tags/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>APIs Are Not In the Efficiency Business</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/technology/miscellaneous/2020-04-11-apis-are-not-in-the-efficiency-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/technology/miscellaneous/2020-04-11-apis-are-not-in-the-efficiency-business/</guid>
      <description>CityFlo Reduces Google Maps API Bill by 94% [] Google Directions API limited their free tier. CityFlo uses this API to calculate ETAs. Initially, CityFlo queried the API every time a stop was registered.
This was the problem. The number of API calls should be dependent on the stops themselves, not the buses. For an MVP, sure - make that query - but if you&#39;re running a growing business, those calls add up!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook to Pay $550 Million to Settle Facial Recognition Suit [The New York Times]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/technology/the-battle-for-the-web/2020-01-29-fb-550m-fine-for-facial-recognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/technology/the-battle-for-the-web/2020-01-29-fb-550m-fine-for-facial-recognition/</guid>
      <description>Facebook to Pay $550 Million to Settle Facial Recognition Suit.  Natasha Singer; Mike Isaac. The New York Times. https://www.nytimes.com/2020/01/29/technology/facebook-privacy-lawsuit-earnings.html. Jan 29, 2020.  Illinois&amp;rsquo; biometric privacy law requires companies to obtain written permission before collecting a person’s biometrics. Residents have the right to sue for up to $5,000 per violation.
Facebook&#39;s Tag Suggestions harvested facial data without getting written consent nor telling Illinois users for how long the data would be kept.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We ran the numbers, and there really is a pipeline problem in eng hiring. [interviewing.io]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/technology/the-battle-for-the-web/2019-12-03-there-is-a-pipeline-problem-in-eng-hiring/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/technology/the-battle-for-the-web/2019-12-03-there-is-a-pipeline-problem-in-eng-hiring/</guid>
      <description>We ran the numbers, and there really is a pipeline problem in eng hiring.  Aline Lerner. http://blog.interviewing.io/we-ran-the-numbers-and-there-really-is-a-pipeline-problem-in-eng-hiring/. https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21694348. Dec 3, 2019.  Wait, but research shows:
 STEM in early education is unfriendly to children from underrepresented backgrounds Lack of a level playing field and unequal access to quality STEM education Hostile university culture in male-dominated CS programs Biased hiring practices Non-inclusive work environments cause higher churn of underrepresented folk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AT&amp;T to pay $60m in settlement for slowing cellphone data on unlimited plans [Reuters]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/business/optimism_and_deception/2019-11-05-att-pay-60m-in-settlement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/business/optimism_and_deception/2019-11-05-att-pay-60m-in-settlement/</guid>
      <description>AT&amp;amp;T to pay $60m in settlement for slowing cellphone data on unlimited plans.  Reuters. https://www.reuters.com/article/us-at-t-settlement/att-will-pay-60-million-over-u-s-allegations-it-lied-in-unlimited-data-pledge-government-idUSKBN1XF26Q.    Complaint filed in 2014 by the FTC: AT&amp;amp;T charged smartphone users for &amp;lsquo;unlimited&amp;rsquo; data plans, but throttled them after ~2GB within a month.
  AT&amp;amp;T: None of these allegations were ever proved in court. We were fully prepared to defend ourselves, but decided settling was in the best interests of consumers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The New York Times Sells Premium Ads Based on How an Article Makes You Feel [Poynter]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/technology/the-battle-for-the-web/2019-04-10-nyt-sells-ads-based-on-how-an-article-makes-you-feel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/technology/the-battle-for-the-web/2019-04-10-nyt-sells-ads-based-on-how-an-article-makes-you-feel/</guid>
      <description>The New York Times Sells Premium Ads Based on How an Article Makes You Feel.  Rick Edmonds. Poynter. https://www.poynter.org/business-work/2019/the-new-york-times-sells-premium-ads-based-on-how-an-article-makes-you-feel/. Apr 10, 2019.  The NYT piloted ad placements based on the emotions certain articles evoke.
The average lift to an ad is 40% NYT can charge more for those ads.
Will the newsroom be tasked with producing lots of emotional stories? NYT&#39;s claims:
 The newsroom turned out plenty of emotionally charged stories, anyhow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standing Against Hate [Facebook]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/technology/the-battle-for-the-web/2019-03-27-fb-standing-against-hate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/technology/the-battle-for-the-web/2019-03-27-fb-standing-against-hate/</guid>
      <description>Standing Against Hate.  https://about.fb.com/news/2019/03/standing-against-hate/. https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19503094. Mar 27, 2019.  Main Article We now ban praise, support and representation of white nationalism and separatism on FB and Instagram
We didn&#39;t ban them before because their broader concepts, e.g. American pride and Basque separatism, are an important part of people&#39;s identity.
Experts in race relations have confirmed that white nationalism and separatism cannot be meaningfully separated from white supremacy and organized hate groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Trauma Floor: The Secret Lives of FB Moderators in America [The Verge]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/technology/the-battle-for-the-web/2019-02-25-the-secret-lives-of-fb-mods-in-america/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/technology/the-battle-for-the-web/2019-02-25-the-secret-lives-of-fb-mods-in-america/</guid>
      <description>The Trauma Floor: The Secret Lives of FB Moderators in America.  Casey Newton. The Verge. https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/25/18229714/cognizant-facebook-content-moderator-interviews-trauma-working-conditions-arizona. Feb 25, 2019.  Moderators in Phoenix will make just $28,800 per year — while the average FB employee has a total compensation of $240,000.
Team leaders micro-manage content moderators&amp;rsquo; every bathroom break. Two Muslim employees were ordered to stop praying during their 9min/day of allotted &amp;ldquo;wellness time&amp;rdquo;.
Employees can be fired after making just a handful of errors a week, and those who remain live in fear of former colleagues returning to seek vengeance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FB Under Pressure to Halt Rise of Anti-Vaccination Groups [The Guardian]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/technology/the-battle-for-the-web/2019-02-12-fb-versus-antivaxx-groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/technology/the-battle-for-the-web/2019-02-12-fb-versus-antivaxx-groups/</guid>
      <description>FB Under Pressure to Halt Rise of Anti-Vaccination Groups.  Ed Pilkington, Jessica Glenza. The Guardian. https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2019/feb/12/facebook-anti-vaxxer-vaccination-groups-pressure-misinformation. Feb 12, 2019.  Vitamin C &amp;amp; Orthomolecular Medicine for Optimal Health. Closed Group. 49,000 approved members.
 Gironda, an admin, sells high-dose Vitamin C in bulk through Revitalize Wellness. The &amp;lsquo;shop now&amp;rsquo; button links to her firm. Revitalize Wellness carries a disclaimer saying that its products are “not intended to treat, diagnose, cure or prevent disease”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Monetizing Encrypted Messaging by Analyzing Metadata [Twitter]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/technology/the-battle-for-the-web/2019-01-25-fb-monetizing-encrypted-messages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/technology/the-battle-for-the-web/2019-01-25-fb-monetizing-encrypted-messages/</guid>
      <description>Facebook Monetizing Encrypted Messaging by Analyzing Metadata.  @SarahJamieLewis. https://twitter.com/SarahJamieLewis/status/1088914192847917056. Jan 25, 2019.  Claim: FB will track relationships and social groups and make that information accessible to law enforcement. FB is a corporation that needs to make money; surveillance makes them money.
Contention: Actual privacy and security must protect metadata as well as content.
Cwtch by OpenPrivacy aims to minimize metadata exposed by apps used. It&#39;s built on Tor. Challenges: message latency, server reliability &amp;amp; discovery, (online) first contact problem for key exchange.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Sivan) Innovation Africa &amp; Water Availability</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/business/on-starting-a-business/2018-10-01-innovation-africa-and-water-availability/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/business/on-starting-a-business/2018-10-01-innovation-africa-and-water-availability/</guid>
      <description>Innovation Africa &amp;amp; Water Availability.  Sivan (InnoAfrica). Talks at The Keller Center. Oct 1, 2018.  Bring in Israeli solar panels and drip irrigation. Pump water from the large reservoirs below. Cost $7,000.
Adapting to community: 6-8 weeks on committees, bank accounts; mobile charging stations and barbershops using solar panels for sustainability. Can&#39;t sell the water, but you can subsidize it with complementary products.
Set up remote monitoring with real time stats in order to schedule maintenance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Chinese Govt Controls the Media [SoECS]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/politics-and-governance/2018-10-01-chinese-media-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/politics-and-governance/2018-10-01-chinese-media-control/</guid>
      <description>Seeing government influence through coordination of sensitive coverage, localization of negative news &amp;amp; crowding out other stories on the front page.
Structural topic models (LDA + context, e.g. topic prevalence, choice of words) analyze fundamental aspect of the news that can&#39;t be changed.
Instead of assuming news follows events, investigate!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons Learned in Tech Policy [SoECS]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/politics-and-governance/2018-10-01-lessons-learned-in-tech-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/politics-and-governance/2018-10-01-lessons-learned-in-tech-policy/</guid>
      <description>Local governments face severe constraints. Liaising with big tech for employees on sabbaticals could alleviate this.
State legislators may have unfounded opinions, but they have the sway, so work with them.
Rural-urban differences. Rural folk were more active. Urban folks wrote angry blogs and that was it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wolf that Tried to Play Nice [SoECS]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/business/optimism_and_deception/2018-10-01-the-wolf-that-tried-to-play-nice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/business/optimism_and_deception/2018-10-01-the-wolf-that-tried-to-play-nice/</guid>
      <description>AT&amp;amp;T restricted FaceTime from running on some data plans. Justifications?
 FaceTime is preloaded, therefore 100% of users have it FaceTime wasn&#39;t efficient in network usage. The capacity was asymmetrical, but video chat is symmetrical  Interestingly enough, AT&amp;amp;T required Apple to greenlight it, which they did. AT&amp;amp;T worked with top developers to teach network etiquette.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computers Can Solve Your Problem. You May Not Like the Answer. [Boston Globe]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/technology/miscellaneous/2018-09-21-boston-public-school-equity-algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/technology/miscellaneous/2018-09-21-boston-public-school-equity-algorithm/</guid>
      <description>Computers Can Solve Your Problem. You May Not Like the Answer. Adapted from []:
The algorithm had four guiding principles:
 Increase # of high school students starting after 8am Decrease # of elementary school students dismissed after 4pm Accommodate the needs of special education students Generate transportation savings  Unprecedented opposition to the algorithm&#39;s solution. Angry parents signed petitions and stormed the school committee. BPS dropped the solution.
Complications:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google&#39;s Project Dragonfly [The Intercept]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/politics-and-governance/2018-08-01-google-project-dragonfly/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/politics-and-governance/2018-08-01-google-project-dragonfly/</guid>
      <description>Google Plans to Launch Censored Search Engine in China, Leaked Documents Reveal [The Intercept].  Ryan Gallagher. The Intercept. https://theintercept.com/2018/08/01/google-china-search-engine-censorship/. Aug 1, 2018.  Project Dragonfly A censored version of Google search that blacklists websites and search terms about human rights, democracy, religion and peaceful protests.
China has 750m people; 80% of its internet access is on Android. There&#39;s $$$ to be made.
Between 2006 and 2010, Google had maintained a censored Google Search, but was heavily criticized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Apology for the Internet - How It Went Wrong [Intelligencer]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/technology/the-battle-for-the-web/2018-04-16-an-apology-for-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/technology/the-battle-for-the-web/2018-04-16-an-apology-for-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>An Apology for the Internet - How It Went Wrong.  Noah Kulwin. NY Mag. http://nymag.com/intelligencer/2018/04/an-apology-for-the-internet-from-the-people-who-built-it.html. Apr 16, 2018.  Start with hippie good intentions. A generation embracing new technology as a tool to transform the world for good.
 Can Duruk: You were going to Facebook not to work but to make the world more open and connected.  Mix in capitalism on steroids. To save the world, you first need to take it over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cambridge Analytica Uncovered: Secret filming reveals election tricks [Channel 4]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/politics-and-governance/2018-03-19-cambridge-analytica-uncovered/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/politics-and-governance/2018-03-19-cambridge-analytica-uncovered/</guid>
      <description>Cambridge Analytica Uncovered: Secret filming reveals election tricks.  Channel 4 News. https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mpbeOCKZFfQ. Mar 19, 2018.  Pay people to take surveys but through an app. Mine their profile data, and also crawl their friends.
Identify swayable voters and their sensitivities. Craft targeted ads. Play on (unconscious) fears and hopes.
Elections are about emotions, not facts. Data science and social media can help us make sense of and manipulate the chaos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So You Want to Reform Democracy [Medium]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/politics-and-governance/2015-11-22-so-you-want-to-reform-democracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/politics-and-governance/2015-11-22-so-you-want-to-reform-democracy/</guid>
      <description>So You Want to Reform Democracy.  Joshua Tauberer. https://medium.com/civic-tech-thoughts-from-joshdata/so-you-want-to-reform-democracy-7f3b1ef10597. Nov 22, 2015.  If there was an idea that could &amp;lsquo;fix&amp;rsquo; democracy, it would have been thought-up already. If you don&#39;t see your idea out there, it’s because it didn’t work the hundreds of other times someone tried it.
Let’s tell representatives what their constituents think. Then they HAVE to vote with us!
 They don’t necessarily want to know what their constituents are thinking.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>