<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>twitter.com on Chege&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/domains/twitter.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in twitter.com on Chege&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.curiosities.dev/domains/twitter.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Brandolini&#39;s Bullshit Asymmetry Principle</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/knowing/calling-bullshit/01-intro-to-bullshit/01-brandolinis-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/knowing/calling-bullshit/01-intro-to-bullshit/01-brandolinis-law/</guid>
      <description>The Principle Brandolini&amp;rsquo;s Bullshit Asymmetry Principle: The amount of energy needed to refute bullshit is an order of magnitude bigger than to produce it. 
In Essence of Bullshit  , Frankfurt posits that the essence of bullshit is lack of concern for the truth, which may explain why bullshit is easier to produce.
  Jonathan Swift: Falsehood flies, and the Truth comes limping after it; so that when Men come to be undeceiv&amp;rsquo;d, it is too late; the Jest is over, and the Tale has had its Effect&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Myths and Fallacies of &#39;Personally Identifiable Information&#39;</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/politics-and-governance/wws351-it-policy/07-privacy/differential-privacy/2010-narayanan-myths-and-fallacies-of-pii/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/politics-and-governance/wws351-it-policy/07-privacy/differential-privacy/2010-narayanan-myths-and-fallacies-of-pii/</guid>
      <description>Myths and Fallacies of &amp;#39;Personally Identifiable Information&amp;#39;.  Narayanan, Arvind; Shmatikov, Vitaly. dl.acm.org  . Jun 1, 2010.    What is PII? From Breach Notification Laws: For example, California Senate Bill 1386: SSNs, driver’s license numbers, financial accounts.
The list can never be exhaustive, e.g. email addresses and telephone numbers are not mentioned in Bill 1386.
Focuses on data that are commonly used for authenticating an individual. Ignores data that reveals some sensitive information about an individual</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fiction Potpourri</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/potpourri/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/potpourri/</guid>
      <description>Unknown Number  tells the story of a person who has gender dysphoria. In an alternate universe, they never transitioned but went on to become an established physicist who could communicate across parallel universes.
The use of text message screenshots (and corresponding alternative text) brings a modern feel to the piece.
  The Sin of America There&amp;rsquo;s a woman outside of a town called Sheridan, where the sky is there to only witness, not to intervene&amp;hellip; They all swarm hungrily over her, caring nothing for who she is or where she has been or where they will go when this is over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Becoming a Better Point Guard</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/sports/2021-07-13-point-guard-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/sports/2021-07-13-point-guard-journey/</guid>
      <description>Objective: Learn to read the game and make smart predictions. Reaction times are overrated; perception and prediction rule  .
  Offensive Playmaking and Scoring  tracks the following play types: transition, isolation, pick &amp;amp; roll ball handler, pick &amp;amp; roll roll man, post up, spot up, handoff, cut, off screen and put-backs.
At least these categories provide a baseline for what search terms to use.  also has a miscellaneous play type section, so it&amp;rsquo;ll be interesting to see if a new play-type pops up in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Academic Research</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/knowing/2021-06-15-on-academic-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/knowing/2021-06-15-on-academic-research/</guid>
      <description>Going to a talk is difficult for everyone because nobody understands the whole thing, but it&amp;rsquo;s especially difficult for undergraduates because they still expect to. 
   is a rich resource for understanding scholarly literature. Browse it. Some of the listed items are familiar, e.g. Google Scholar, SCImago, Sci-Hub, but it&amp;rsquo;d be informative to zoom out to the larger picture, e.g. good alternatives to Google Scholar.
  Why Even Read Papers?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philanthropy</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/socioeconomics/2020-04-26-on-philanthropy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/socioeconomics/2020-04-26-on-philanthropy/</guid>
      <description>Criticism/Defense Of Billionaire Philanthropy  Taxes will probably not go to the same causes, e.g. reforming the bail system, grassroot efforts for migrants, etc.
Admittedly, these are things that the government should be doing, but it seems that the government doesn&amp;rsquo;t do enough. Furthermore, some of these issues so politicized, e.g. immigrants, that government support can be fickle.
  Foundations are more effective than governments as they do their due diligence, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Monetizing Encrypted Messaging by Analyzing Metadata [Twitter]</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/www/the-battle-for-the-web/2019-01-25-fb-monetizing-encrypted-messages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/www/the-battle-for-the-web/2019-01-25-fb-monetizing-encrypted-messages/</guid>
      <description>Facebook Monetizing Encrypted Messaging by Analyzing Metadata.  @SarahJamieLewis. twitter.com  . Jan 25, 2019.   Claim: FB will track relationships and social groups and make that information accessible to law enforcement. FB is a corporation that needs to make money; surveillance makes them money.
Contention: Actual privacy and security must protect metadata as well as content.
 Cwtch by OpenPrivacy   aims to minimize metadata exposed by apps used.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
