<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>www.connectedpapers.com on Chege's Blog</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/domains/www.connectedpapers.com/</link><description>Recent content in www.connectedpapers.com on Chege's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.curiosities.dev/domains/www.connectedpapers.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>On Societal Oppressions</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/socioeconomics/2022-09-18-societal-oppressions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/socioeconomics/2022-09-18-societal-oppressions/</guid><description>Looking for parallels should be done cautiously. For example, the advantaging associated with race may be different from the one associated with heterosexism. It&amp;rsquo;s also hard to disentangle [dis]advantaging where social class, economic class, race, religion, sexuality, ethnic identity, and other factors interact.
Isn&amp;rsquo;t this the crux of intersectionality studies?
Intersectionality identifies multiple factors of advantage and disadvantage. Factors include gender, caste, sex, race, ethnicity, class, sexuality, religion, disability, weight, and physical appearance.</description></item><item><title>On Becoming a Better Point Guard</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/sports/2021-07-13-point-guard-journey/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/sports/2021-07-13-point-guard-journey/</guid><description>Objective: Learn to read the game and make smart predictions. Reaction times are overrated; perception and prediction rule .
Offensive Playmaking and Scoring tracks the following play types: transition, isolation, pick &amp;amp; roll ball handler, pick &amp;amp; roll roll man, post up, spot up, handoff, cut, off screen and put-backs.
At least these categories provide a baseline for what search terms to use. also has a miscellaneous play type section, so it&amp;rsquo;ll be interesting to see if a new play-type pops up in the future.</description></item><item><title>A Zooming Web Browser</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/www/1996-11-05-a-zooming-browser/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 1996 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/www/1996-11-05-a-zooming-browser/</guid><description>A Zooming Web Browser. Bederson, Benjamin B.; Hollan, James D.; Stewart, Jason; Rogers, David; Vick, David; Ring, Laura; Grose, Eric; Forsythe, Chris. Multimedia Computing and Networking, 1996. Vol. 2667. www.osti.gov . www.connectedpapers.com . Interesting because these were the early days of the web, back when Netscape was king. The web could have evolved in different ways. Why didn&amp;rsquo;t the zooming browser catch on?
Problem Context Navigating the web presents a struggle between focus and context.</description></item></channel></rss>