<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Competition on c13u&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.c13u.com/tags/competition/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Competition on c13u&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.c13u.com/tags/competition/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Counterintuitive Competitive Advantages [Morgan Housel]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/on-starting-a-business/2019-03-13-counterintuitive-competitive-advantages/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/on-starting-a-business/2019-03-13-counterintuitive-competitive-advantages/</guid>
      <description>Counterintuitive Competitive Advantages. Morgan Housel. Collaborative Fund. https://www.collaborativefund.com/blog/counterintuitive-competitive-advantages/. 2019-03-13.  Growing big antlers requires lots of Ca and Ph, which are rare. Small antlers were required to survive low-food winters, but big antlers were required to impress females to mate. The Irish elk spiraled to extinction.
I get the analogy that Housel is trying to paint, but this seems like an oversimplification. Sure, big antlers are sexy, but if small antlers are all that&#39;s left on the menu, I doubt female antlers will think &amp;ldquo;pass&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wolf that Tried to Play Nice [SoECS]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2018-10-01-the-wolf-that-tried-to-play-nice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2018-10-01-the-wolf-that-tried-to-play-nice/</guid>
      <description>AT&amp;amp;T restricted FaceTime from running on some data plans. Justifications?
 FaceTime is preloaded, therefore 100% of users have it FaceTime wasn&#39;t efficient in network usage. The capacity was asymmetrical, but video chat is symmetrical  Interestingly enough, AT&amp;amp;T required Apple to greenlight it, which they did. AT&amp;amp;T worked with top developers to teach network etiquette.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Trajectory of Great Ideas [Morgan Housel]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/on-starting-a-business/2018-08-14-trajectory-of-great-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/on-starting-a-business/2018-08-14-trajectory-of-great-ideas/</guid>
      <description>The Trajectory of Great Ideas. Morgan Housel. Collaborative Fund. https://www.collaborativefund.com/blog/ideas/. 2018-08-14.  Sears. Blockbuster. Nokia. AOL. You had a great idea. You discovered a beautiful beach to lay on, but other people didn&#39;t just follow you and lay down themselves; they built condos and restaurants while you were watching the sunset. Soon your great idea loses its appeal.
But you put so much work into the great idea that it&#39;s become an inseparable part of your identity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Competitive Edges Die [Morgan Housel]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/on-starting-a-business/2018-02-08-why-competitive-edges-die/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/business/on-starting-a-business/2018-02-08-why-competitive-edges-die/</guid>
      <description>Why Competitive Edges Die. Morgan Housel. Collaborative Fund. https://www.collaborativefund.com/blog/why-competitive-advantages-die/. 2018-02-08.  The Beginner&#39;s Mind Being right is the enemy of staying right because it leads you to forget the way the world works.
Knowing you have a competitive advantage reduces the incentive to explore other ideas, especially when those ideas conflict with your chosen strategy.
The Burden of Being Profitable Nothing to lose is a wonderful thing to have. Having a quarterly dividend to maintain is what happens after you build something great.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>