<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>utilitarianism on Chege's Blog</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/tags/utilitarianism/</link><description>Recent content in utilitarianism on Chege's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.curiosities.dev/tags/utilitarianism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>House of El (2021 - 2023)</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/house-of-el-2021-2023/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/house-of-el-2021-2023/</guid><description>House of El Book One: The Shadow Threat. Image Credits: dc.com
House of El. Claudia Gray; Eric Zawardski. www.dc.com . www.hoopladigital.com . 2021. Snapshots [Tribune Member] Krypton is the most advanced civilization known to exist in the galaxy. For generations, its citizens have been genetically engineered to make them the greatest examples of their kind. We have the best soldiers that can possibly exist.</description></item><item><title>The Mighty</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/tomasi-mighty/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/tomasi-mighty/</guid><description>&amp;#34;The Mighty&amp;#34;. Credits: imagecomics.com The Mighty. Peter J. Tomasi; Champagne Keith; Chris Samnee; Peter Snejbjerg. imagecomics.com . www.hoopladigital.com . 2022. Review Similar back story to Invincible , also published by Image Comics. Like Omni-Man, Alpha One comes from a distant civilization of advanced humans. However, his ambitions weren&amp;rsquo;t shared by his people, and crashed into Earth by mistake while being transported to a prison in Venus.</description></item><item><title>Swamp Thing</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/swamp-thing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/swamp-thing/</guid><description>The Swamp Thing. Image from dccomics.com Motifs Love and Loyalty Their master gone, the un-men pause, uncertain of what to do&amp;hellip; They must among themselves for a moment &amp;ndash; and, at least, a decision is reached. For all their existence, they have followed their master blindly &amp;ndash; wherever he might lead&amp;hellip; And there seems no good reason to change that situation now.
[Liz] He&amp;rsquo;s kept her safely shut away for years.</description></item><item><title>TV and Film</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/tv-and-film/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/tv-and-film/</guid><description>Crime Drama Ozark&amp;rsquo;s highlights are Ruth Langmore&amp;rsquo;s 90s' hip hop playlist, Wendy Byrde&amp;rsquo;s sociopathic ambition, and Del Rio&amp;rsquo;s suave. The show follows the Byrde family that has to launder money for the Navarro Cartel. The writers use shortcuts as the show proceeds, and grant excessive plot armor for the Byrde family in subsequent seasons.
&amp;rsquo;s Bill Dubuque also wrote The Accountant (2016 Film) , which follows a CPA with high-functioning autism who makes his living by uncooking the books of criminal organizations experiencing internal embezzlement.</description></item><item><title>As the Last I May Know</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/huang-as-the-last-i-may-know/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/huang-as-the-last-i-may-know/</guid><description>As the Last I May Know. Shi Lian Huang. www.tor.com . Accessed Dec 4, 2021. won the &amp;ldquo;Best Short Story&amp;rdquo; Hugo Award in 2020.
Memorable Points Background: Sere missiles can wipe out a city completely. Nyma&amp;rsquo;s nation has been the only recipient of a seres strike. They&amp;rsquo;ve since acquired their own seres stockpile. They&amp;rsquo;re engaged in war with an state that lacks seres weapons.</description></item><item><title>Stories of Your Life and Others</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/chiang-stories-of-your-life-and-others/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/chiang-stories-of-your-life-and-others/</guid><description>Stories of Your Life and Others. Ted Chiang. 2010. ISBN: 9781931520898 . Tower of Babylon Story focused on Hillalum, who lived during the construction of the Tower of Babel .
notes that the Hebrew school version was more elaborate than the Old Testament account, e.g. the tower is so tall that it takes a year to climb, and when a man falls to his death, no one mourns, but when a brick is dropped, the brick-layers weep because it will take a year to replace.</description></item><item><title>Eternals</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/eternals/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/fiction/eternals/</guid><description>Eternals (2006) by Neil Gaiman. Image from marvel.com Eternals Vol. 3 (2006). Neil Gaiman; John Romita Jr.. www.marvel.com . www.hoopladigital.com . 2006. Eternals Vol. 5 (2021). Kieron Gillen; Esad Ribić. www.marvel.com . www.hoopladigital.com . marvel.fandom.com . Snapshots Origin of Life Mark Evanier: Can you prove that ancient civilizations weren&amp;rsquo;t visited by space travellers and heralded as gods?</description></item><item><title>Health Ethics</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/2020-05-02-health-ethics/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/2020-05-02-health-ethics/</guid><description>Harden, a liberal behavior geneticist, is publishing a book, &amp;ldquo;The Genetic Lottery: Why DNA Matters for Social Equality&amp;rdquo;. Watch this space as it casts doubt on prevailing social justice thesis that environmental factors, and not genetics, influence behavior or social outcomes.
Check back in Sept 2022 (one year from now).
Faster Human Trials In 1986, AZT (AIDS treatment) showed 1/145 deaths compared to the placebo&amp;rsquo;s 16/137. 6,000 AIDS patients were offered AZT, helping it get to the public much faster.</description></item></channel></rss>