<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HN Users on c13u&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.c13u.com/authors/hn-users/</link>
    <description>Recent content in HN Users on c13u&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.c13u.com/authors/hn-users/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Against &#39;Smart&#39; Clipboard Adjustments</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/2020-02-17-dont-touch-my-clipboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/2020-02-17-dont-touch-my-clipboard/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t touch my clipboard [Alex Ellis] [] Complaint: Alex selected &amp;amp; copied an em dash ( - ) character from https://www.thepunctuationguide.com/em-dash.html, but here&amp;rsquo;s what the site put into the clipboard:
1 2 3 4  — From https://www.thepunctuationguide.com/em-dash.html © 2020 thepunctuationguide.com   There&amp;rsquo;s a tradeoff between attribution and changing things outside a site&amp;rsquo;s scope.
Apple&amp;rsquo;s iBooks does this too. It may be due to contractual agreements with publishers. []</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Politics of Free Speech</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/www/the-battle-for-the-web/2020-04-29-politics-of-free-speech/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/www/the-battle-for-the-web/2020-04-29-politics-of-free-speech/</guid>
      <description>Should Platforms Be Neutral? Facebook banned praise, support and representation of white nationalism and separatism, because the two concepts cannot be meaningfully separated from white supremacy and organized hate groups. Furthermore, people that search for related terms will have &amp;ldquo;Life After Hate&amp;rdquo; suggested to them. []
Part of me is uncomfortable. Sure, Facebook is trying to do the right thing here. What if Facebook was replaced by some tyrannical government that censors opposition?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>APIs Are Not In the Efficiency Business</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/miscellaneous/2020-04-11-apis-are-not-in-the-efficiency-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/miscellaneous/2020-04-11-apis-are-not-in-the-efficiency-business/</guid>
      <description>CityFlo Reduces Google Maps API Bill by 94% [] Google Directions API limited their free tier  . CityFlo uses this API to calculate ETAs. Initially, CityFlo queried the API every time a stop was registered.
This was the problem. The number of API calls should be dependent on the stops themselves, not the buses. For an MVP, sure - make that query - but if you&amp;rsquo;re running a growing business, those calls add up!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theory About Theories</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/knowing/2020-01-08-theory-about-theories/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/knowing/2020-01-08-theory-about-theories/</guid>
      <description>On Coming Up With New Theories A crackpot publicizes a theory that feels right. A theorist goes further to try and disprove a theory that feels right, before publishing it. []
There is still value in an earnest well-thought out theory, even if it turns out wrong, e.g. saving others the trouble. Juniors spend far more time making sure they know everything, while seniors release more half-baked ideas - yet the senior&amp;rsquo;s half-baked ideas will probably be more widely read.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
