<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences on Chege's Blog</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/publications/Proceedings-of-the-National-Academy-of-Sciences/</link><description>Recent content in Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences on Chege's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.curiosities.dev/publications/Proceedings-of-the-National-Academy-of-Sciences/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>02. Developing Self-Awareness</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/knowing/scout-mindset/02-developing-self-awareness/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/knowing/scout-mindset/02-developing-self-awareness/</guid><description>Signs of a Scout These Don&amp;rsquo;t Make You a Scout Feeling objective. The more objective you feel, the more you trust your own intuitions and opinions as accurate representations of reality, and the less inclined you are to question them.
Being smart and knowledgeable. It&amp;rsquo;s not a case of &amp;ldquo;if people were smarter and well-informed, they&amp;rsquo;d realize their errors&amp;rdquo;. For example, found that polarization (on political fronts) on anthropogenic climate change increases as scientific intelligence increases.</description></item><item><title>04. Changing Your Mind</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/knowing/scout-mindset/04-changing-your-mind/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/knowing/scout-mindset/04-changing-your-mind/</guid><description>How to Be Wrong found that experts were barely able to forecast better than random chance. However, a small subset of people (coined &amp;ldquo;superforecasters&amp;rdquo; ) were better. In a competition, they beat teams of top professors and CIA professional analysts. These superforecasters were not smarter than everyone else nor did they have more knowledge/experience, they were great at being wrong.
Change your mind a little at a time. Seeing the world in shades of grey is less stressful, as the experience of encountering evidence against one of your beliefs is not high stakes.</description></item></channel></rss>