<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>On Starting a Business on c13u&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.c13u.com/business/on-starting-a-business/</link>
    <description>Recent content in On Starting a Business on c13u&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.c13u.com/business/on-starting-a-business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Counterintuitive Competitive Advantages [Morgan Housel]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/business/on-starting-a-business/2019-03-13-counterintuitive-competitive-advantages/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/business/on-starting-a-business/2019-03-13-counterintuitive-competitive-advantages/</guid>
      <description>Counterintuitive Competitive Advantages.  Morgan Housel. Collaborative Fund. https://www.collaborativefund.com/blog/counterintuitive-competitive-advantages/. Mar 13, 2019.  Growing big antlers requires lots of Ca and Ph, which are rare. Small antlers were required to survive low-food winters, but big antlers were required to impress females to mate. The Irish elk spiraled to extinction.
I get the analogy that Housel is trying to paint, but this seems like an oversimplification. Sure, big antlers are sexy, but if small antlers are all that&#39;s left on the menu, I doubt female antlers will think &amp;ldquo;pass&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Sivan) Innovation Africa &amp; Water Availability</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/business/on-starting-a-business/2018-10-01-innovation-africa-and-water-availability/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/business/on-starting-a-business/2018-10-01-innovation-africa-and-water-availability/</guid>
      <description>Innovation Africa &amp;amp; Water Availability.  Sivan (InnoAfrica). Talks at The Keller Center. Oct 1, 2018.  Bring in Israeli solar panels and drip irrigation. Pump water from the large reservoirs below. Cost $7,000.
Adapting to community: 6-8 weeks on committees, bank accounts; mobile charging stations and barbershops using solar panels for sustainability. Can&#39;t sell the water, but you can subsidize it with complementary products.
Set up remote monitoring with real time stats in order to schedule maintenance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is the Lean Startup Dead? [Steve Blank]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/business/on-starting-a-business/2018-09-05-is-the-lean-startup-dead/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/business/on-starting-a-business/2018-09-05-is-the-lean-startup-dead/</guid>
      <description>Is the Lean Startup Dead?  Steve Blank. https://steveblank.com/2018/09/05/is-the-lean-startup-dead/. Sep 5, 2018.  Katzenberg (Paramount, Disney Studios &amp;amp; DreamWorks) has raised $1.75b for NewTV, a startup banking on consumers wanting a subscription for 10-minute programs on mobile.
They renamed to quibi.com/. At least that makes them more searchable on Google. &amp;ldquo;NewTV&amp;rdquo; searches lead to newtv.org, a community media center for the residents of Newton, Massachusetts.
  After the rubble of the dotcom crash, startups and investors needed a lean approach to survive long enough to generate revenue and profits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Trajectory of Great Ideas [Morgan Housel]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/business/on-starting-a-business/2018-08-14-trajectory-of-great-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/business/on-starting-a-business/2018-08-14-trajectory-of-great-ideas/</guid>
      <description>The Trajectory of Great Ideas.  Morgan Housel. Collaborative Fund. https://www.collaborativefund.com/blog/ideas/. Aug 14, 2018.  Sears. Blockbuster. Nokia. AOL. You had a great idea. You discovered a beautiful beach to lay on, but other people didn&#39;t just follow you and lay down themselves; they built condos and restaurants while you were watching the sunset. Soon your great idea loses its appeal.
But you put so much work into the great idea that it&#39;s become an inseparable part of your identity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Average Age of a Successful Startup Founder is 45 [Harvard Business]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/business/on-starting-a-business/2018-07-11-average-age-of-successful-founder-is-45/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/business/on-starting-a-business/2018-07-11-average-age-of-successful-founder-is-45/</guid>
      <description>The Average Age of a Successful Startup Founder is 45.  Harvard Business Review. https://hbr.org/2018/07/research-the-average-age-of-a-successful-startup-founder-is-45. Jul 11, 2018.  There&#39;s a variation among industries: software tends to 40, while oil/gas/biotech tends to 47.
Even Gates, Jobs, Bezos, Brin &amp;amp; Page had their growth rates peak when they were middle aged.
Different definitions of success, e.g. employment growth, sales growth, IPO/acquisition, came to the same conclusion.
VCs may not be looking for growth potential.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Love B2B over B2C [Atrium]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/business/on-starting-a-business/2018-07-11-why-i-love-b2b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/business/on-starting-a-business/2018-07-11-why-i-love-b2b/</guid>
      <description>Why I Love B2B over B2C.  Justin Kan. Atrium. https://www.atrium.co/blog/b2b-vs-b2c/. Jul 11, 2018.  B2B customers will actually pay for your product. You have a clear execution path - they&#39;ll tell you and pay for features. Companies don&#39;t quickly flip flop between products. Consumers are too price sensitive and finicky.
B2B customers are rational, and thus understandable. They care about whether a solution solves their problem and if the solution is important enough to pay for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Competitive Edges Die [Morgan Housel]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/business/on-starting-a-business/2018-02-08-why-competitive-edges-die/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/business/on-starting-a-business/2018-02-08-why-competitive-edges-die/</guid>
      <description>Why Competitive Edges Die.  Morgan Housel. Collaborative Fund. https://www.collaborativefund.com/blog/why-competitive-advantages-die/. Feb 8, 2018.  The Beginner&#39;s Mind Being right is the enemy of staying right because it leads you to forget the way the world works.
Knowing you have a competitive advantage reduces the incentive to explore other ideas, especially when those ideas conflict with your chosen strategy.
The Burden of Being Profitable Nothing to lose is a wonderful thing to have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do Things That Don&#39;t Scale [Paul Graham]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/business/on-starting-a-business/2013-07-01-do-things-that-dont-scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/business/on-starting-a-business/2013-07-01-do-things-that-dont-scale/</guid>
      <description>Do Things That Don&amp;#39;t Scale.  Paul Graham. http://www.paulgraham.com/ds.html. Jul 1, 2013.  Recruit manually. Don&#39;t send links. Set them up on the spot.
Ask how big the startup would be if you did the right things, not whether you&#39;re currently changing the world.
Delight your initial customers. Tim Cook can&#39;t send handwritten notes, but you can.
If you can solve the problem manually, do so while gradually automating the most pressing bottlenecks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Get Startup Ideas [Paul Graham]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/business/on-starting-a-business/2012-11-01-how-to-get-startup-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/business/on-starting-a-business/2012-11-01-how-to-get-startup-ideas/</guid>
      <description>How to Get Startup Ideas.  Paul Graham. http://www.paulgraham.com/startupideas.html. Nov 1, 2012.  Err on the side of having competitors, but make sure that you have a thesis that everyone else is overlooking, e.g. Google wasn&#39;t averse to users leaving google.com ASAP
The Startup Idea Matrix, (B2B Edition, B2C Edition) is a good start for knowing who to google.
  In college, take classes in different areas in lieu of taking entrepreneurship classes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>