<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Meritocracy on Chege&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/tags/meritocracy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Meritocracy on Chege&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.curiosities.dev/tags/meritocracy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>06. Sunny</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/06-sunny/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/06-sunny/</guid>
      <description>Elizabeth met Sunny in Stanford&amp;rsquo;s Mandarin program. She was 18, he was 19 years older and married. Elizabeth had struggled and gotten bullied and Sunny helped her out.
Sunny was arrogant and demeaning to employees. Sunny was a sucker for #hours clocked in. 8 hours a day showed a lack of dedication. But Elizabeth had utmost confidence in him.
That Sunny (COO) and Elizabeth (CEO) were dating wasn&amp;rsquo;t disclosed to the board.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philanthropy</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/socioeconomics/2020-04-26-on-philanthropy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/socioeconomics/2020-04-26-on-philanthropy/</guid>
      <description>Criticism/Defense Of Billionaire Philanthropy  Taxes will probably not go to the same causes, e.g. reforming the bail system, grassroot efforts for migrants, etc.
Admittedly, these are things that the government should be doing, but it seems that the government doesn&amp;rsquo;t do enough. Furthermore, some of these issues so politicized, e.g. immigrants, that government support can be fickle.
  Foundations are more effective than governments as they do their due diligence, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Third Base [Scott Galloway]</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/socioeconomics/2019-12-13-galloway-third-base/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/socioeconomics/2019-12-13-galloway-third-base/</guid>
      <description>Third Base  Not recognizing your blessings feeds into the dark side of capitalism and meritocracy: success is a choice, and that those who haven’t achieved success are not unlucky, but unworthy.
I&amp;rsquo;m relatively lucky. I don&amp;rsquo;t know how much of the techie hubris that I bear. I have unresolved feelings about meritocracy and fairness. Race is usually used as a proxy for bridging the gap, e.g. affirmative action at colleges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We ran the numbers, and there really is a pipeline problem in eng hiring. [interviewing.io]</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/www/the-battle-for-the-web/2019-12-03-there-is-a-pipeline-problem-in-eng-hiring/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/www/the-battle-for-the-web/2019-12-03-there-is-a-pipeline-problem-in-eng-hiring/</guid>
      <description>We ran the numbers, and there really is a pipeline problem in eng hiring.  Aline Lerner. http://blog.interviewing.io/we-ran-the-numbers-and-there-really-is-a-pipeline-problem-in-eng-hiring/  . https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21694348  . Dec 3, 2019.  Wait, but research shows:
 STEM in early education is unfriendly to children from underrepresented backgrounds Lack of a level playing field and unequal access to quality STEM education Hostile university culture in male-dominated CS programs Biased hiring practices Non-inclusive work environments cause higher churn of underrepresented folk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Probably Won&#39;t Make it to the Top [DHH]</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/personal_growth/letting_go/2018-11-22-dhh-you-probably-wont-make-it-to-the-top/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/personal_growth/letting_go/2018-11-22-dhh-you-probably-wont-make-it-to-the-top/</guid>
      <description>You Probably Won&amp;#39;t Make it to the Top.  David Heinemeier Hansson (DHH). Signal vs. Noise. https://m.signalvnoise.com/youre-probably-won-t-make-it-to-the-top-8d2146abb790  . Nov 22, 2018.  Fallacy: If you really set your mind to it, you can do it&amp;hellip; That’s how I did it. I just wanted it more, worked hard, and eventually all my dreams came true. I won’t say it’s easy, but it’s up to you!
Odds are overwhelmingly that you will not make it to the top.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Psychology of Money [Morgan Housel]</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/personal_growth/an_outlook_on_life/2018-06-01-housel-psychology-of-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/personal_growth/an_outlook_on_life/2018-06-01-housel-psychology-of-money/</guid>
      <description>The Psychology of Money.  Morgan Housel. The Collaborative Fund. http://www.collaborativefund.com/blog/the-psychology-of-money/  . Jun 1, 2018.  People underestimate the role played by luck. Given \(N\) investors, if \(N\) is large enough, a couple of them will luck their way into billions.
But every investor seems to be doing due diligence. The successful ones will be more convinced that their methods really work.
Considering the amount of investing books out there, we should be seeing a lot more Warren Buffets in the world.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
