<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>www.youtube.com on Chege&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/domains/www.youtube.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in www.youtube.com on Chege&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.curiosities.dev/domains/www.youtube.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On Becoming a Better Point Guard</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/sports/2021-07-13-point-guard-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/sports/2021-07-13-point-guard-journey/</guid>
      <description>Objective: Learn to read the game and make smart predictions. Reaction times are overrated; perception and prediction rule  .
Watching film is a good way of training my mental basketball model.  has a couple.
  Offensive Playmaking and Scoring  tracks the following play types: transition, isolation, pick &amp;amp; roll ball handler, pick &amp;amp; roll roll man, post up, spot up, handoff, cut, off screen and putbacks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GME ✋ ... 🚀🚀🚀 ... 💎 ✋</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/trading-and-investing/crowds-and-rationalism/2021-01-30-gme-to-the-moon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/trading-and-investing/crowds-and-rationalism/2021-01-30-gme-to-the-moon/</guid>
      <description>$GME price in Jan-Feb 2021. Image Credits: https://finance.yahoo.com/chart/GME
  Folks like Melvin Capital and Citron Research think that GameStop is a dying business. The general public is optimistic though, be it for fundamental reasons   (e.g. Ryan Cohen (chewy.com) will help GameStop can re-invent itself in the online space ), or for personal amusement, or FOMO. In particular, /r/wallstreetbets members are buying lots of call options   .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tech and Democracy</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/politics-and-governance/2020-01-27-tech-and-democracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/politics-and-governance/2020-01-27-tech-and-democracy/</guid>
      <description>So You Want to Reform Democracy If there was an idea that could &amp;lsquo;fix&amp;rsquo; democracy, it would have been thought-up already. If you don&amp;rsquo;t see your idea out there, it’s because it didn’t work the hundreds of other times someone tried it.
Let’s tell representatives what their constituents think. Then they HAVE to vote with us!
 They don’t necessarily want to know what their constituents are thinking. When they do, they have no trouble finding out  Only a small fraction of citizens will ever participate in a poll, and that causes selection biases.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
