<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>www.youtube.com on Chege&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/domains/www.youtube.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in www.youtube.com on Chege&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.curiosities.dev/domains/www.youtube.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On Becoming a Better Point Guard</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/sports/2021-07-13-point-guard-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/sports/2021-07-13-point-guard-journey/</guid>
      <description>Objective: Learn to read the game and make smart predictions. Reaction times are overrated; perception and prediction rule  .
  Offensive Playmaking and Scoring  tracks the following play types: transition, isolation, pick &amp;amp; roll ball handler, pick &amp;amp; roll roll man, post up, spot up, handoff, cut, off screen and put-backs.
At least these categories provide a baseline for what search terms to use.  also has a miscellaneous play type section, so it&amp;rsquo;ll be interesting to see if a new play-type pops up in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GME ✋ ... 🚀🚀🚀 ... 💎 ✋</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/trading-and-investing/crowds-and-rationalism/2021-01-30-gme-to-the-moon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/trading-and-investing/crowds-and-rationalism/2021-01-30-gme-to-the-moon/</guid>
      <description>$GME price in Jan-Feb 2021. Image Credits: https://finance.yahoo.com/chart/GME
  Folks like Melvin Capital and Citron Research think that GameStop is a dying business. The general public is optimistic though, be it for fundamental reasons   (e.g. Ryan Cohen (chewy.com) will help GameStop can re-invent itself in the online space ), or for personal amusement, or FOMO. In particular, /r/wallstreetbets members are buying lots of call options   .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tech and Democracy</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/politics-and-governance/2020-01-27-tech-and-democracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/politics-and-governance/2020-01-27-tech-and-democracy/</guid>
      <description>Political Ads Cambridge Analytica (CA) paid people to take in-app survey; mined FB profile data including friends&#39; data; crafted tailored sensitive ads to sway-able voters. Elections are about emotions, not facts. Data science and social media can help us make sense of and manipulate the chaos. 
An alternative argument. Political misinformation is:
 Weak in high profile partisan races because pre-existing beliefs hardly change Strong when people don&amp;rsquo;t have string pre-existing opinions, e.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
