<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bad Blood [Book] on Chege&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bad Blood [Book] on Chege&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00. Prologue</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/00-prologue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/00-prologue/</guid>
      <description>Holmes had an all-star team: Larry Ellison&amp;rsquo;s mentor as Chair, Associate Dean of Stanford&amp;rsquo;s School of Engineering, 30 years IBM experience, 25 years pharma and biotech experience, Panasonic&amp;rsquo;s chip-making subsidiary head&amp;hellip;
Fraud or not, this is a sick lineup! How could she mess this up?
  Big Pharma spends tens of $B on clinical trials each year. Theranos would enable them to adjust dosage and save 30%. Holmes insisted on revising financial projections upward - assuming all (15+) deals came through - to $1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>01. A Purposeful Life</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/01-a-purposeful-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/01-a-purposeful-life/</guid>
      <description>Holmes wanted to be a billionaire since childhood. Her parents were from wealth, with medical and military folk. Holmes attended Houston&amp;rsquo;s most prestigious private school. She spoke her way into Stanford&amp;rsquo;s Mandarin program, while still in high school. Parents insisted on living a purposeful life.
Worked in lab during school year. Freshman internship at Genome Institute of Singapore: nasal swabs and syringes. There had to be a better way.
Ah, the transformative experience abroad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bad Blood [John Carreyrou]</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/_meta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/_meta/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02. The Gluebot</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/02-the-gluebot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/02-the-gluebot/</guid>
      <description>Holmes insisted on using just a prick of blood. Problem: unreproducible results. A miniaturized catridge made storing and using the reagents hard.
You can&amp;rsquo;t Steve Jobs your way through medical devices. But you can&amp;rsquo;t change the world by being cynical.
  Costs. Each cartridge cost +$200 to make and was single use. Holmes even purchased a $2m automated packaging line.
Control of Information. The biochemists and the engineers reported up to Holmes and weren&amp;rsquo;t encouraged to communicate with each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03. Apple Envy</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/03-apple-envy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/03-apple-envy/</guid>
      <description>Holmes&amp;rsquo;s Grand Plans. The iPod of health care. Build a personal disease map; reverse engineer cancer and predict evolution of tumors.
Again, if she&amp;rsquo;s faking this belief, then its sociopathic. But maybe she thought she could do it. Inventors go where no one else dares. They&amp;rsquo;re ridiculed by society. Here&amp;rsquo;s to the crazy ones. The misfits. The rebels. The troublemakers.     Chat ports were blocked to protect proprietary information and trade secrets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04. Goodbye East Paly</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/04-goodbye-east-paly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/04-goodbye-east-paly/</guid>
      <description>For some terminated employees, Holmes requested a dossier on them for leverage. Mosley (finance guy) had stored porn on his work laptop. Holmes (retroactively) used that as the cause for his termination and lack of stock options.
Matt (IT) wanted to leave to start IT consulting firm. Holmes asking him to use ununionized (mob controlled) movers for a last minute move from East Paly was one of the final straws. Holmes tried asking Matt&amp;rsquo;s peer to build dossier in exchange for Matt&amp;rsquo;s position, but they declined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05. The Childhood Neighbor</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/05-the-childhood-neighbor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/05-the-childhood-neighbor/</guid>
      <description>Money was a sore point in the Holmes household. Holmes&amp;rsquo;s grandparents had squandered away their share of the Fleischmann fortune. Richard Fuisz, a family friend, was a flashy successful businessman.
So in a way, Elizabeth didn&amp;rsquo;t grow up in wealth? This puts a spin on Chapter 01: A Purposeful Life  .
  Fuisz was offended that Elizabeth never consulted him. Fuisz made his money patenting medical inventions that he anticipated other companies would someday want.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06. Sunny</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/06-sunny/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/06-sunny/</guid>
      <description>Elizabeth met Sunny in Stanford&amp;rsquo;s Mandarin program. She was 18, he was 19 years older and married. Elizabeth had struggled and gotten bullied and Sunny helped her out.
Sunny was arrogant and demeaning to employees. Sunny was a sucker for #hours clocked in. 8 hours a day showed a lack of dedication. But Elizabeth had utmost confidence in him.
That Sunny (COO) and Elizabeth (CEO) were dating wasn&amp;rsquo;t disclosed to the board.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>07. Dr. J</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/07-dr-j/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/07-dr-j/</guid>
      <description>FB&amp;rsquo;s private valuation had doubled to $50b in 6 months. &amp;lsquo;Angry Birds&amp;rsquo; showed an app could be a business. Low interest rates made hedge funds consider private startups.
Walgreens Dr. J - Walgreens Innovation. Theranos tests could boost revenues. Walgreens agrees to prepurchase $50m of cartridges and loan Theranos $25m.
Walgreens: we can&amp;rsquo;t risk a scenario where CVS has a deal with them in 6 months and it ends up being real.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>08. The miniLab</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/08-minilab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/08-minilab/</guid>
      <description>The miniLab, 4S for short, stemmed from the need for a device that could perform more than just one class of tests. Theranos value prop was now minituarization, as opposed to invention. Current blood analyzers used too much blood and did too few tests.
Kent, de-facto Chief Architect of the miniLab, had raised $215k on Kickstarter for his bike lights side project. Elizabeth and Sunny wanted the patent to be transferred to Theranos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>09. The Wellness Play</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/09-the-wellness-play/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/09-the-wellness-play/</guid>
      <description>Safeway was doing poorly. Burd teased with a &amp;lsquo;wellness play&amp;rsquo;. He expected the clinics&#39; to recoup the $350m renovation costs. Testing and rewarding employees would reduce Safeway&amp;rsquo;s health care costs.
Theranos would courier samples to Palo Alto for testing. Theranos used a lancet on the index finger AND the good old hypodermic needle to the arm. The results could take 2 weeks as opposed to near-instantaneous. Theranos&amp;rsquo;s results tended to be way off, unless they had been outsourced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10. Who Is LTC Shoemaker?</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/10-who-is-ltc-shoemaker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/10-who-is-ltc-shoemaker/</guid>
      <description>Elizabeth had successfully pitched to James Mattis, 4-star General, about deploying Theranos in Afghanistan. General Mattis was known to look out for his troops.
Elizabeth&amp;rsquo;s plan around regulation - the real blood analysis would be beamed to California to be done by professionals; only the CLIA compliance for the Palo Alto lab was needed - no FDA.
Lt. Col. Shoemaker, responsible for the army&amp;rsquo;s compliance with medical regulations, was openly critical of the Theranos&#39; workaround.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11. Lighting a Fuisz</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/11-lighting-a-fuisz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/11-lighting-a-fuisz/</guid>
      <description>Elizabeth sued Richard Fuisz claiming he used Joe &amp;amp; John Fuisz to steal confidential information at McDermott Will &amp;amp; Emery, in order to build the rival patent. Note that John thought his father, Richard, was overbearing.
David Boies was legendary: antitrust against MSFT, Al Gore on contested 2000 election, overturning ban on gay marriage in CA. He also intimidated opponents with private investigators.
There was paranoia that Quest Diagnostics and Laboratory Corporation of America were thirsty for Theranos&amp;rsquo;s blood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12. Ian Gibbons</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/12-ian-gibbons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/12-ian-gibbons/</guid>
      <description>Ian&amp;rsquo;s specialty was immunoassays. His contentions: the devices fell short of the lab bench&amp;rsquo;s accuracy; there was little communication between groups; Elizabeth&amp;rsquo;s dishonesty about Theranos&#39; capbilities.
Ian confided in Channing Robertson, who parroted to Elizabeth, who fired Ian.
But his colleagues lobbied him back in. He was in a demoted position though. Paul, previous mentee turned manager, was more compromising with the engineers.
Ian was dismayed that Elizabeth&amp;rsquo;s name was usually in 1st place on patents despite negligible scientific contribution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13. Chiat\Day</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/13-chiat-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/13-chiat-day/</guid>
      <description>Chiat\Day was the agency that Apple had used. Therefore, Theranos would too.
Patrick (Chiat\Day) was enamored by Elizabeth&amp;rsquo;s mission. The website models featured all demographics. Elizabeth scheduled Wednesday meetings because that&amp;rsquo;s how Apple did it.
Stan Fiorito (Chiat\Day) was more circumspect. Sunny&amp;rsquo;s sales targets had measly research. How were they affording $6m/year retainer?
Elizabeth claimed Theranos was saving soldiers&#39; lives in Afghanistan. She wanted bold claims:
 800 tests on a drop of blood More accurate than traditional lab testing Tests ready in &amp;lt; 30min Tests approved by the FDA and endorsed by key medical centers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>14. Going Live</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/14-going-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/14-going-live/</guid>
      <description>Theranos&amp;rsquo;s Lab was divided into two. The upstairs one, CLIA-certified, was full of commercial diagnostic equipment. The downstairs one had Theranos&amp;rsquo;s tech.
2.5 years of the miniLab&amp;rsquo;s development. But it was still a work in progress. In medical device standards, 3 years is a short time.
Sycophants were promoted. Many employees were on H1-B, so they needed Theranos&amp;rsquo;s employment.
After LTC Shoemaker, Elizabeth scrapped the remote diagnostics. The samples were to be couriered to Palo Alto.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>15. Unicorn</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/15-unicorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/15-unicorn/</guid>
      <description>Elizabeth used Shultz&amp;rsquo;s connections to get a WSJ Weekend Interview to coincide with the launch. The interview was a friendly setting, with a pro-business &amp;amp; anti-regulation ethos.
Theranos was about to launch. Its devices were being used by the military too. Elizabeth offered Don Lucas a discount investment opportunity - $15m at a $6b valuation; 7 years ago, Theranos was valued at $40m.
Uber had raised $361m at $3.5b. Spotify raised $250m at $4b.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>16. The Grandson</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/16-the-grandson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/16-the-grandson/</guid>
      <description>The Edison&amp;rsquo;s innards were mostly a pipette fastened to a robotic arm. But it had a [buggy] touchscreen interface, so&amp;hellip;
A test is considered precise if its coefficient of variation (CV) is below 10%. Data runs that failed to meet the threshold were discarded. Of six values, Theranos only reported the median to the patient.
Theranos also argued that proficiency testing results were assessed by comparing them to its peers&#39; results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>17. Fame</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/17-the-fame/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/17-the-fame/</guid>
      <description>Richard and Joe Fuisz were tired and battered. They had already spent $2m+ on their defense. What if they lost and were made to cover Theranos&amp;rsquo;s legal expenses?
Richard agreed to withdraw patent in exchange for Theranos withdrawing its suit. The Fuiszes had lost. But Joe demanded a public apology from Theranos.
Roger Parloff, Fortune Magazine&amp;rsquo;s legal correspondent saw the settlement in Litigation Daily. After speaking to Shultz, Perry, Kissinger, Nunn, Mattis and the 2 new directors: Kovacevich (former Wells Fargo CEO) and Frist (former Senate majority leader), came the June 2014 cover story that catapulted Elizabeth to fame: This CEO Is Out for Blood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>18. The Hippocratic Oath</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/18-the-hippocratic-oath/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/18-the-hippocratic-oath/</guid>
      <description>Alan talked Elizabeth and Sunny out of running HIV tests on diluted finger-stick samples - unreliable potassium and cholesterol results were bad enough.
Alan was tired of convincing physicians that blood test results were sound and accurate. He chose to resign and asked his name be taken off the lab&amp;rsquo;s CLIA license. Alan got served with an affidavit.
How could Alan go against the most fabled SV unicorn? The litigation would bankrupt him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>19. The Tip</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/19-the-tip/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/19-the-tip/</guid>
      <description>Alan retrieved the proficiency testing email chain through a whistleblower law firm. He forwarded the thread to Carreyrou. The thread showed Sunny admonishing Alan &amp;amp; Mark for running proficiency tests on the Edison and admitting that the device had &amp;ldquo;failed&amp;rdquo; the test. Elizabeth was copied on most of the emails.
Carreyrou tracked Carmen Washington, who had complained about Theranos&amp;rsquo;s blood tests in Walgreens. 3 of her patients had received questionable test results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20. The Ambush</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/20-the-ambush/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/20-the-ambush/</guid>
      <description>Charlotte: I doubt if Theranos&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;box&amp;rsquo; is real. Henry [Kissinger] doubts too and he&amp;rsquo;s been saying he wants out.
Tyler got served with an affidavit stating that he&amp;rsquo;d never spoken to any third parties about Theranos and that he&amp;rsquo;d give names of [ex]employees who he knew had talked to WSJ.
George: Tyler isn&amp;rsquo;t a snitch. Finding out who spoke to WSJ is Theranos&amp;rsquo;s problem.
Tyler declined to name WSJ&amp;rsquo;s other sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>21. Trade Secrets</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/21-trade-secrets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/21-trade-secrets/</guid>
      <description>Carreyrou &amp;amp; WSJ vs. Boies Schiller The Boies Schiller delegation was led by David Boies himself!
Admissions: Ownership of commercial blood analyzers; problematic potassium test was a known issue, and no faulty results had been released to patients.
Siemens ADVIA? Special dilution on ADVIA? Number of tests done by the Edison? Trade secret!
Boies Schiller and witnesses Tyler was young and unqualified; disgruntled ex-employees are unreliable.
BS summoned Erika to an interview, lest she be litigated against.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>22. La Mattanza</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/22-la-mattanza/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/22-la-mattanza/</guid>
      <description>La Mattanza: An ancient Silician ritual in which fisherman waded into the Mediterranean Sea up to their waist with clubs and spears and then stood still for hours on end until the [bluefin tuna] no longer noticed their presence. Eventually, when enough [tuna] had gathered around them, someone gave and imperceptible signal and in a split second the scene went from preternatural quiet to gory bloodbath as the fishermen struck viciously at their unsuspecting quarry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>23. Damage Control</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/23-damage-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/23-damage-control/</guid>
      <description>Rupert Murdoch led the most recent $430m funding round with $125m. He followed his gut: he&amp;rsquo;d invested $150k in Uber for it to become $50m.
The investment packket forecasted (profit revenue) of ($330m, $1b) in 2015 and ($505m, $2b) in 2016. Furthermore, Theranos had lined up Cox Enterprises, The Waltons, New England Patriots owner, Carlos Slim, controller of Fiat Chrysler.
Elizabeth brought up Carreyrou&amp;rsquo;s story to Murdoch, but Murdoch declined to intervene - saying he trusted the paper&amp;rsquo;s editors to handle the matter fairly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>24. The Empress Has No Clothes</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/24-the-empress-has-no-clothes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/24-the-empress-has-no-clothes/</guid>
      <description>[3 weeks before first article] Erika Cheung&amp;rsquo;s email to Gary Yamamoto (CMS) spurred the surprise inspection on Theranos&amp;rsquo;s labs in less than 3 days. They found so many problems and missing documentation that they planned to return. When they returned, WSJ&amp;rsquo;s article was out and there was pressure. CMS released a letter calling Theranos an &amp;ldquo;immediate jeopardy to patient health and safety&amp;rdquo;.
Theranos claimed to have fixed many of the deficiencies, and that the problems had no bearing on the soundness of its proprietary tech.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epilogue</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/25-epilogue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/25-epilogue/</guid>
      <description>March 14, 2018: SEC charges Theranos, Homes and Balwani with conducting &amp;ldquo;an elaborate, years-long fraud&amp;rdquo;. To resolve SEC&amp;rsquo;s civil charges, Elizabeth was forced to relinquish her voting control, give back a big chunk of stock, pay a $500k penalty and not be an officer/director in a public company for 10 years.
Sunny didn&amp;rsquo;t join Theranos until late 2009. Elizabeth had already been misleading pharmaceutical companies for years about the readiness of her tech.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
