<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on c13u&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.c13u.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on c13u&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.c13u.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>On Graduation</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/blog/2019-11-28-on-graduation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/blog/2019-11-28-on-graduation/</guid>
      <description>In 8 hours, family and friends will gather at our home to celebrate my graduation. It&#39;s a big deal - I left Kenya for Princeton, graduated and now work at Microsoft. I&#39;ll probably need to say something at some point. Here&#39;s that thing.
I&#39;m humbled, not because I&#39;m striving to be virtuous, but from realizing that my current state is a series of non-deterministic yet compounding luck [TRoL], [Housel]. In my time counselling Kenyan students applying to US universities, I haven&#39;t been able to reliably help them gain admission [KAtUS].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Search of Influential Academic Publications</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/blog/2019-06-16-most-important-papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/blog/2019-06-16-most-important-papers/</guid>
      <description>I recently downloaded citations data from  Aminer  . I seek interesting papers to read during my free time [note]. The database has the following structure:   Table Columns Remarks   papers paper_id, title, venue, year, number of citations, abstract 3,079,007 papers from 1936 to 2018   authors name, appearance order, paper_id 1,766,547 distinct names (out of 9,476,165 names)   paper_references paper_id, cited_paper_id 25,166,994 references     Approach 1: Citation Count  For one, we can answer that with a SQL query: SELECT papers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Stuff On the Internet (#1)</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/blog/2018-08-30-random-walk-on-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/blog/2018-08-30-random-walk-on-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>(April 2018) An Apology for the Internet 
Remember &amp;lsquo;Seasons in the Sun&amp;rsquo;? I thought it was Westlife&#39;s but turns out Terry Jacks is the real owner. Combine that melody and some witty criticism of current technological trends and you get Joy of Tech&#39;s comic. Cheers to more cat memes in the sun. Also, relevant XKCD!
Burrito Time by Dos Toros As much as I advocate for not being glued to the phone, it&#39;s hard to hate the brilliant marketing: one notification sent every day at a random time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>