<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on Chege's Blog</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on Chege's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.curiosities.dev/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Self-Learning: The Road So Far</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/blog/2021-06-25-on-self-learning/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/blog/2021-06-25-on-self-learning/</guid><description>On graduating, I pictured myself blossoming into a voracious autodidact. Unlike those pesky pre-requisites scattered through college, the topics I&amp;rsquo;d dive into will be 100% my choice! Two years after graduation, I&amp;rsquo;m underwhelmed by my progress so far. This post examines my current predicament.
OneNote Notebooks Fortunately, OneNote is not part of M365 else I would need to pay for continued access.
Useful for annotating primary sources. Handwritten annotations make me feel as if I&amp;rsquo;m actually learning something.</description></item><item><title>On Graduation</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/blog/2019-11-28-on-graduation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/blog/2019-11-28-on-graduation/</guid><description>In 8 hours, family and friends will gather at our home to celebrate my graduation. It&amp;rsquo;s a big deal - I left Kenya for Princeton, graduated and now work at Microsoft. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably need to say something at some point. Here&amp;rsquo;s that thing.
I&amp;rsquo;m humbled, not because I&amp;rsquo;m striving to be virtuous, but from realizing that my current state is a series of non-deterministic yet compounding luck [TRoL] , [Housel] .</description></item><item><title>In Search of Influential Academic Publications</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/blog/2019-06-16-most-important-papers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/blog/2019-06-16-most-important-papers/</guid><description>I recently downloaded citations data from Aminer . I seek interesting papers to read during my free time [note]. The database has the following structure: Table Columns Remarks papers paper_id, title, venue, year, number of citations, abstract 3,079,007 papers from 1936 to 2018 authors name, appearance order, paper_id 1,766,547 distinct names (out of 9,476,165 names) paper_references paper_id, cited_paper_id 25,166,994 references Approach 1: Citation Count For one, we can answer that with a SQL query: SELECT papers.</description></item><item><title>Home</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/blog/2015-04-26-home/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/blog/2015-04-26-home/</guid><description>Today the sun is so angry that it has descended a few feet to prove its power. Point noted. I adjust my baseball cap in self-defense.
Similar metaphor in Catheryne Valente&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The Sin of America&amp;rdquo; : There&amp;rsquo;s a woman outside of a town called Sheridan, where the sky comes so near to earth it has to use the crosswalk just like everyone else.
Two people on a farm.</description></item></channel></rss>