<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>[ToDo] Mathematics on Chege's Blog</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/todo/mathematics/</link><description>Recent content in [ToDo] Mathematics on Chege's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.curiosities.dev/todo/mathematics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>[ToDo] Discrete Mathematics</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/todo/mathematics/discrete-mathematics/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/todo/mathematics/discrete-mathematics/</guid><description>Logic walks through pretty common syntax. Sets and Sequences defines sets and sequences, and various notations. Sums and Products introduces syntax, and declares a few closed forms without proofs. Graphs defines various terms like vertices, edges, paths, walks, trails, trees, connectedness, edge-directionality, edge-weights, etc. recommends:
Calculus by Michael Spivak. Logic in Computer Science by Michael Huth. Discrete and Combinatorial Mathematics: An Applied Introduction by Ralph Grimaldi.</description></item><item><title>[ToDo] Linear Algebra</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/todo/mathematics/hefferon-linear-algebra/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/todo/mathematics/hefferon-linear-algebra/</guid><description>Linear Systems
Solving Linear Systems Linear Geometry Reduced Echelon Form Topic: Computer Algebra Systems Topic: Input-Output Analysis Topic: Accuracy of Computations Topic: Analyzing Networks Vector Spaces
Definition of Vector Space Linear Independence Basis and Dimension Topic: Fields Topic: Crystals Topic: Voting Paradoxes Topic: Dimensional Analysis Maps Between Spaces
Isomorphisms Homomorphisms Computing Linear Maps Matrix Operations Change of Basis Projection Topic: Line of Best Fit Topic: Geometry of Linear Maps Topic: Magic Squares Topic: Markov Chains Topic: Orthonormal Matrices Determinants</description></item><item><title>[ToDo] Linear Algebra: An Inquiry-Based Approach</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/todo/mathematics/linear-algebra-an-inquiry-based-approach/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/todo/mathematics/linear-algebra-an-inquiry-based-approach/</guid><description>Objective: Get better at linear algebra for the sake of it.
✅ Ch 01. Introduction to Systems of Linear Equations
✅ Ch 02. The Matrix Representation of a Linear System
Ch 03. Row Echelon Forms
Ch 04. Vector Representation
Ch 05. The Matrix-Vector Form of a Linear System
Ch 06. Linear Dependence and Independence
Ch 07. Matrix Transformations
Ch 08. Matrix Operations
Ch 09. Introduction to Eigenvalues and Eigenvectors
Ch 10.</description></item><item><title>[ToDo] Introduction to Applied Linear Algebra: Vectors, Matrices, and Least squares</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/todo/mathematics/intro-to-applied-linear-algebra/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/todo/mathematics/intro-to-applied-linear-algebra/</guid><description>Vectors Linear Functions Norm and Distance Clustering Linear Independence Matrices Matrix Examples Linear Equations Linear Dynamical Systems Matrix Multiplication Matrix Inverses Least Squares Least Squares Data Fitting Least Squares Classification Multi-Objective Least Squares Constrained Least Squares Constrained Least Squares Applications Non-linear Least Squares Constrained Non-linear Least Squares Introduction to Applied Linear Algebra: Vectors, Matrices, and Least squares. Stephen Boyd; Lieven Vandenberghe. Stanford University; University of California, Los Angeles.</description></item><item><title>[ToDo] Think Bayes</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/todo/mathematics/think-bayes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/todo/mathematics/think-bayes/</guid><description> Bayes&amp;rsquo;s Theorem Computational Statistics Estimation More Estimation Odds and Addends Decision Analysis Prediction Observer Bias Two Dimensions Approximate Bayesian Computation Hypothesis Testing Evidence Simulation A Hierarchical Model Dealing with Dimensions Think Bayes. Downey, Allen. proquest.safaribooksonline.com .</description></item><item><title>[ToDo] The Princeton Companion to Mathematics</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/todo/mathematics/princeton-companion-to-mathematics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/todo/mathematics/princeton-companion-to-mathematics/</guid><description>Notes Part I Introduction:
✅ What Is Mathematics About? ✅ The Language and Grammar of Mathematics Some Fundamental Mathematical Definitions The General Goals of Mathematical Research Part II The Origins of Modern Mathematics:
From Numbers to Number Systems Geometry The Development of Abstract Algebra Algorithms The Development of Rigor in Mathematical Analysis The Development of the Idea of Proof The Crisis in the Foundations of Mathematics Part III Mathematical Concepts:</description></item></channel></rss>