<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Learning Resources on c13u&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.c13u.com/learning-resources/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Learning Resources on c13u&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.c13u.com/learning-resources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>CPSC 465: Theory of Distributed Systems</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/learning-resources/theory-of-distributed-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/learning-resources/theory-of-distributed-systems/</guid>
      <description>Introduction
Message Passing
 Model Broadcast and Convergecast Distributed Breadth-First Search Leader Election Logical Clocks Synchronizers Coordinated Attack Synchronous Agreement Byzantine Agreement Impossibility of Asynchronous Agreement Paxos Failure Detectors Quorum Systems  Shared Memory
 Model Distributed Shared Memory Mutual Exclusion The Wait-Free Hierarchy Atomic Snapshots Lower Bounds on Perturbable Objects Restricted-Use Objects Common2 Randomized Consensus and Test-and-Set Renaming Software Transactional Memory Obstruction-Freedom BG Simulation Topological Methods Approximate Agreement  Other Communication Models</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linear Algebra</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/learning-resources/hefferon-linear-algebra/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/learning-resources/hefferon-linear-algebra/</guid>
      <description>Linear Systems
 Solving Linear Systems Linear Geometry Reduced Echelon Form Topic: Computer Algebra Systems Topic: Input-Output Analysis Topic: Accuracy of Computations Topic: Analyzing Networks  Vector Spaces
 Definition of Vector Space Linear Independence Basis and Dimension Topic: Fields Topic: Crystals Topic: Voting Paradoxes Topic: Dimensional Analysis  Maps Between Spaces
 Isomorphisms Homomorphisms Computing Linear Maps Matrix Operations Change of Basis Projection Topic: Line of Best Fit Topic: Geometry of Linear Maps Topic: Magic Squares Topic: Markov Chains Topic: Orthonormal Matrices  Determinants</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CPSC 469: Randomized Algorithms</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/learning-resources/randomized-algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/learning-resources/randomized-algorithms/</guid>
      <description>Randomized Algorithms Probability Theory Random Variables Basic Probabilistic Inequalities Concentration Bounds Randomized Search Trees Hashing Martingales and Stopping Times Markov Chains Approximate Counting The Probabilistic Method De-randomization Quantum Computing Randomized Distributed Algorithms Sample Assignments from Fall 2019 Sample Assignments from Fall 2016 Sample Assignments from Spring 2014 Sample Assignments from Spring 2013 Sample Assignments from Spring 2011 Sample Assignments from Spring 2009 Probabilistic Recurrences  CPSC 469: Randomized Algorithms.  James Aspnes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CS231n: Convolutional Neural Networks for Visual Recognition</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/learning-resources/cs231n-cnn-for-visual-recognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/learning-resources/cs231n-cnn-for-visual-recognition/</guid>
      <description>Image Classification; Linear Classification; Optimization; Backpropagation; Neural Networks; Convolutional Neural Networks; Understanding and Visualizing Convolutional Neural Networks; Transfer Learning and Fine-tuning Convolutional Neural Networks.
 CS231n: Convolutional Neural Networks for Visual Recognition.  Fei-Fei Li; Ranjay Krishna; Danfei Xu. http://cs231n.stanford.edu/ . 2020.    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>INFO 270: Calling Bullshit: Data Reasoning in a Digital World</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/learning-resources/calling-bullshit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/learning-resources/calling-bullshit/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to bullshit    Spotting bullshit    The natural ecology of bullshit    Causality    Statistical traps    Visualization    Big data    Publication bias    Predatory publishing and scientific misconduct    The ethics of calling bullshit.    Fake news    Refuting bullshit    INFO 270: Calling Bullshit: Data Reasoning in a Digital World.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Algorithms by Jeff Erickson</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/learning-resources/erickson-algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/learning-resources/erickson-algorithms/</guid>
      <description>Introduction; Recursion; Backtracking; Dynamic Programming; Greedy Algorithms; Basic Graph Algorithms; Depth-First Search; Minimum Spanning Trees; Shortest Paths; All-Pairs Shortest Paths; Maximum Flows &amp;amp; Minimum Cuts; Applications of Flows and Cuts; NP-Hardness.
Fast Fourier Transforms; Fast Exponential Algorithms; Dynamic Programming for Formal Languages and Automata; Advanced Dynamic Programming; Matroids; Balances and Pseudoflows; Minimum-Cost Flows; Linear Programming; Linear Programming Algorithms; Approximation Algorithms.
Discrete Probability; Nuts and Bolts; Treaps and Skip Lists; Tail Inequalities; Hashing; Filtering and Streaming; String Matching; Randomized Minimum Cut; Amortized Analysis; Scapegoat and Splay Trees; Disjoint Sets; Lower Bounds; Adversary Arguments; Proof by Induction; Solving Recurrences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CS 97SI: Introduction to Programming Contests</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/learning-resources/cs97si-intro-to-programming-contests/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/learning-resources/cs97si-intro-to-programming-contests/</guid>
      <description> Introduction Mathematics Data Structures Dynamic Programming (DP) Combinatorial Games Basic Graph Algorithms Shortest Path Algorithms Network Flow Problems Computational Geometry String Algorithms Suffix Arrays   CS 97SI: Introduction to Programming Contests.  Jaehyun Park. http://stanford.edu/class/cs97si/ . 2011.    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Networks, Crowds, and Markets</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/learning-resources/networks-crowds-and-markets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/learning-resources/networks-crowds-and-markets/</guid>
      <description>Overview    Graph Theory and Social Networks
  Graphs    String and Weak Ties    Networks in Their Surrounding Contexts    Positive and Negative Relationships    Game Theory
  Games    Evolutionary Game Theory    Modeling Network Traffic Using Game Theory    Auctions    Markets and Strategic Interaction in Networks</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CS261: Optimization and Algorithmic Paradigms</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/learning-resources/cs261-optimization-and-algorithmic-paradigms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/learning-resources/cs261-optimization-and-algorithmic-paradigms/</guid>
      <description>Approximation algorithms for Vertex Cover and Metric Steiner Tree Approximation of General Steiner Tree Versions of the Traveling Salesman Problem. Eulerian loops. 1.5-approximate Algorithm for Metric TSP. The Set Cover Problem. Introduction to Linear Programming Linear Programming Duality Linear Programming Relaxation of Vertex Cover Linear Programming Relaxation of Set Cover The Maximum Flow - Minimum Cut Theorem Maximum Flow Algorithms: Choosing the Fattest Augmenting Path Edmonds-Karp and Push-Relabel Algorithms Analysis of the Push-Relabel Algorithm Algorithms for the Global Min-Cut Problem Algorithms for Maximum Matching and Vertex Cover in Bipartite Graphs The Linear Programming Formulation of Maximum Cut and its Dual Multi-commodity Flows and the Sparsest Cut Problem Introduction to Online Algorithms Using Expert Advice   CS261: Optimization and Algorithmic Paradigms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Princeton Companion to Mathematics</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/learning-resources/princeton-companion-to-mathematics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/learning-resources/princeton-companion-to-mathematics/</guid>
      <description>Part I Introduction:
 What Is Mathematics About? The Language and Grammar of Mathematics Some Fundamental Mathematical Definitions The General Goals of Mathematical Research  Part II The Origins of Modern Mathematics:
 From Numbers to Number Systems Geometry The Development of Abstract Algebra Algorithms The Development of Rigor in Mathematical Analysis The Development of the Idea of Proof The Crisis in the Foundations of Mathematics  Part III Mathematical Concepts:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>