<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Aspnes, James on Chege's Blog</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/cited-authors/Aspnes-James/</link><description>Recent content in Aspnes, James on Chege's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.curiosities.dev/cited-authors/Aspnes-James/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>[ToDo] CPSC 465: Theory of Distributed Systems</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/todo/computer-science/theory-of-distributed-systems/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/todo/computer-science/theory-of-distributed-systems/</guid><description>Introduction
Message Passing
Model Broadcast and Convergecast Distributed Breadth-First Search Leader Election Logical Clocks Synchronizers Coordinated Attack Synchronous Agreement Byzantine Agreement Impossibility of Asynchronous Agreement Paxos Failure Detectors Quorum Systems Shared Memory
Model Distributed Shared Memory Mutual Exclusion The Wait-Free Hierarchy Atomic Snapshots Lower Bounds on Perturbable Objects Restricted-Use Objects Common2 Randomized Consensus and Test-and-Set Renaming Software Transactional Memory Obstruction-Freedom BG Simulation Topological Methods Approximate Agreement Other Communication Models</description></item><item><title>[ToDo] CPSC 469: Randomized Algorithms</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/todo/computer-science/randomized-algorithms/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/todo/computer-science/randomized-algorithms/</guid><description>Randomized Algorithms Probability Theory Random Variables Basic Probabilistic Inequalities Concentration Bounds Randomized Search Trees Hashing Martingales and Stopping Times Markov Chains Approximate Counting The Probabilistic Method De-randomization Quantum Computing Randomized Distributed Algorithms Sample Assignments from Fall 2019 Sample Assignments from Fall 2016 Sample Assignments from Spring 2014 Sample Assignments from Spring 2013 Sample Assignments from Spring 2011 Sample Assignments from Spring 2009 Probabilistic Recurrences CPSC 469: Randomized Algorithms. James Aspnes.</description></item></channel></rss>