<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Letting Go on c13u&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/personal_growth/letting_go/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Letting Go on c13u&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.curiosities.dev/personal_growth/letting_go/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>You Probably Won&#39;t Make it to the Top [DHH]</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/personal_growth/letting_go/2018-11-22-dhh-you-probably-wont-make-it-to-the-top/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/personal_growth/letting_go/2018-11-22-dhh-you-probably-wont-make-it-to-the-top/</guid>
      <description>You Probably Won&amp;#39;t Make it to the Top.  David Heinemeier Hansson (DHH). Signal vs. Noise. https://m.signalvnoise.com/youre-probably-won-t-make-it-to-the-top-8d2146abb790  . Nov 22, 2018.  Fallacy: If you really set your mind to it, you can do it&amp;hellip; That’s how I did it. I just wanted it more, worked hard, and eventually all my dreams came true. I won’t say it’s easy, but it’s up to you!
Odds are overwhelmingly that you will not make it to the top.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Humble Exits [Morgan Housel]</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/personal_growth/letting_go/2018-10-24-housel-humble-exits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/personal_growth/letting_go/2018-10-24-housel-humble-exits/</guid>
      <description>Humble Exits.  Morgan Housel. The Collaborative Fund. https://www.collaborativefund.com/blog/humble-exits/  . Oct 24, 2018.  Jack Welch declined $110m for a 10th season of Seinfeld because he was done with the show. He wanted to end the show on the same kind of peak.
The show was based on recreating real events from his and Larry David&amp;rsquo;s normal life. They were running out of material because it had been so long since they experienced a normal life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Slate Star Codex) No Clarity Around Growth Mindset</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/personal_growth/letting_go/2015-04-08-ssc-no-clarity-around-the-growth-mindset/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/personal_growth/letting_go/2015-04-08-ssc-no-clarity-around-the-growth-mindset/</guid>
      <description>No Clarity Around Growth Mindset.  Scott Alexander. Slate Star Codex. https://slatestarcodex.com/2015/04/08/no-clarity-around-growth-mindset-yet/  . Apr 8, 2015.  Growth mindset: people who believe effort - and not ability - determines success are more resilient, skillful, hard-working, perseverant in the face of failure.
Most of the growth mindset experiments prime their subjects, but recent priming experiments have famously failed to replicate. Dweck&amp;rsquo;s experiment:
 Group A: easy test (success) -&amp;gt; final bound-to-fail test Group B: hard test (told they&amp;rsquo;re not working hard enough) -&amp;gt; final bound-to-fail test Group B outperformed Group A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Yudkowsky) Letting Go</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/personal_growth/letting_go/2015-12-01-yudkowsky-letting-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/personal_growth/letting_go/2015-12-01-yudkowsky-letting-go/</guid>
      <description>Letting Go.  Eliezer Yudkowsky. Rationality: From AI to Zombies. Feb 1, 2015.  Learn when to admit failure It&amp;rsquo;s important to have a watershed moment and acknowledge a fundamental problem, instead of dividing it into palatable bite-size mistakes.
LTCM were exploiting market inefficiencies. Other people learned of the tricks. LTCM didn&amp;rsquo;t lose hope. They borrowed more and more leverage to exploit tinier and tinier margins.
And their math probably said the leverage was okay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Doctors Die [Zocalo]</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/personal_growth/letting_go/2011-11-30-how-doctors-die/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/personal_growth/letting_go/2011-11-30-how-doctors-die/</guid>
      <description>How Doctors Die.  Zocalo Public Square. https://www.zocalopublicsquare.org/2011/11/30/how-doctors-die/ideas/nexus/  .  Doctors tend to be fairly serene when faced with death themselves. They know enough about modern medicine to know its limits. They go gently into that good night - no heroics; no CPR.
Sometimes, a family really means &amp;lsquo;do everything&amp;rsquo;, but often they mean &amp;lsquo;do everything that’s reasonable.&amp;rsquo; But they may not know what’s reasonable.
People have unrealistic expectations of what doctors can accomplish.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
