<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Science on c13u&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.c13u.com/tags/science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Science on c13u&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.c13u.com/tags/science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>[BBC] Crows Could be the Smartest Animal Other Than Primates</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/physical-science/biology/2019-12-11-bbc-crows-might-be-the-smartest-animal-other-than-primates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/physical-science/biology/2019-12-11-bbc-crows-might-be-the-smartest-animal-other-than-primates/</guid>
      <description>Crows Could be the Smartest Animal Other Than Primates.  BBC. https://www.bbc.com/future/article/20191211-crows-could-be-the-smartest-animal-other-than-primates . Dec 11, 2019.  New Caledonian crows make hooked tools from soft twigs to scoop insects out of holes. Other animals that use tools: chimpanzees, parrots, alligators and crabs.
The crows found the desired stems even when they had been disguised with leaves from a different plant species.
There are anecdotes of crow intelligence too, e.g. using cars at a crosslight to crush cashews in Japan (more in this HN thread  )</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brainless Slime That Can Learn by Fusing [The Atlantic]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/physical-science/biology/2016-12-21-brainless-slime-that-can-learn-by-fusing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/physical-science/biology/2016-12-21-brainless-slime-that-can-learn-by-fusing/</guid>
      <description>Brainless Slime That Can Learn by Fusing.  The Atlantic. https://www.theatlantic.com/science/archive/2016/12/the-brainless-slime-that-can-learn-by-fusing/511295/ . https://old.reddit.com/r/todayilearned/comments/b245af/til_scientists_put_slime_mold_over_a_map_of_tokyo/ . Dec 21, 2016.  Building Transit Networks Can a cell learn? When a part of the plasmodium touches something attractive, e.g. food, it pulses more quickly and widens. If a part meets something repulsive, like light, it pulses more slowly and shrinks.
The article regards this as flowing in the best possible direction without conscious thought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Read a Paper [Keshav]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/knowing/2016-02-17-how-to-read-a-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/knowing/2016-02-17-how-to-read-a-paper/</guid>
      <description>How to Read a Paper.  S. Keshav. David R. Cheriton School of Computer Science, University of Waterloo. https://blizzard.cs.uwaterloo.ca/keshav/home/Papers/data/07/paper-reading.pdf . Feb 17, 2016.   The First Pass (5 - 10 min) Objectives: category, context, validity of assumptions, contributions and quality of writing.
 Carefully read the title, abstract, and introduction. Read the section and sub-section headings, but ignore everything else Glance at the math to determine the underlying theoretical foundations Read the conclusions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
