<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>financial-crime on Chege's Blog</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/tags/financial-crime/</link><description>Recent content in financial-crime on Chege's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.curiosities.dev/tags/financial-crime/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>02. The Madness of the Crowds</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/malkiel-a-random-walk-down-wall-street/part-1-stocks-and-their-value/malkiel-02-the-madness-of-the-crowds/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/malkiel-a-random-walk-down-wall-street/part-1-stocks-and-their-value/malkiel-02-the-madness-of-the-crowds/</guid><description>The Tulip Bulb Craze Virus causes colored stripes in tulip petals. The Dutch valued such bulbs. Prices rose (just when one thought they couldn&amp;rsquo;t go higher). Let the tulipmania begin.
Note: And that&amp;rsquo;s where FOMO comes in. You can&amp;rsquo;t argue with the results. You just want to dip your toes and get out. I watched Bitcoin keep climbing, until I got into the game with $50&amp;hellip;
Tulip bulbs options.</description></item><item><title>Online Markets</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/2021-10-04-online-markets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/2021-10-04-online-markets/</guid><description>WWW &amp;lsquo;21: The Web Conference 2021 REST: Relational Event-Driven Stock Trend Forecasting REST, an event-driven stock trend forecasting framework, that overcomes two limitations of existing event-driven models. Models the stock context, and learns the effect of event information on the stocks under different contexts. Constructs a stock graph and designs a new propagation layer to propagate the effect of event information from related stocks. #stock-trend-forecasting #computational-finance
#graph-based-learning
The value of stock trend forecasting is not unanimous, e.</description></item><item><title>Wall Street Potpourri</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/2021-01-30-potpurri/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/2021-01-30-potpurri/</guid><description>Maximizing the Value for Shareholders Suing a company for not following its code of ethics and therefore misleading investors doesn&amp;rsquo;t fly, but Signet Jewelers settled for $240m . Signet&amp;rsquo;s 70k female employees sued for discrimination, but the class action is yet to be resolved.
Tom Toro&amp;rsquo;s New Yorker cartoon : Yes, the planet got destroyed. But for a beautiful moment in time we created a lot of value for shareholders.</description></item></channel></rss>