<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Miscellaneous on Chege's Blog</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/miscellaneous/</link><description>Recent content in Miscellaneous on Chege's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/miscellaneous/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Finite Time as a SWE</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/miscellaneous/finite-time-swe/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/miscellaneous/finite-time-swe/</guid><description>Deliberately choose what to work on. Part of that is getting priority communicated by interested shareholders.
Empower less-experienced engineers so that they&amp;rsquo;re confident tackling different problems instead of me having to pick up said problems.
Improve my investigation and writing skills so that I can give folks enough context to execute on their own. Mostly communicating intent and trusting others to figure out the nitty gritty details.
Origins of Projects You&amp;rsquo;re invited to join.</description></item><item><title>Of Code Smells and Hygiene</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/miscellaneous/2020-07-05-code-smells-and-hygiene/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/miscellaneous/2020-07-05-code-smells-and-hygiene/</guid><description>#code-hygiene
Pick up from:
IEEE&amp;rsquo;s International Conference on Software Maintenance Improving Code: The (Mis)perception of Quality Metrics Springer&amp;rsquo;s Software Quality Journal On Abstractions If you find yourself adding more parameters and if-statements to an existing abstraction, is the abstraction still apt? Why not remove the old abstraction and re-extract a new [more apt] abstraction? Devs frequently succumb to the sunken cost fallacy thinking that there must have been a reason that the code was written in a certain way.</description></item><item><title>On Data Science</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/miscellaneous/2020-04-24-on-data-science/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/miscellaneous/2020-04-24-on-data-science/</guid><description>Data Science: Reality Doesn&amp;rsquo;t Meet Expectations Execs frequently ignore data science research when making decisions.
Data is often dirty, or insufficient to make decisions about majority of the users. Sometimes the infrastructure is poor - SQL queries take hours.
Data Scientists are usually the only &amp;lsquo;data person&amp;rsquo; on the team. Tons of request from teams, and most of the work is repetitive and &amp;lsquo;easy&amp;rsquo;.
Measuring impact is hard - especially on dollars that were hypothetically saved but never spent.</description></item><item><title>APIs Are Not In the Efficiency Business</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/miscellaneous/2020-04-11-apis-are-not-in-the-efficiency-business/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/miscellaneous/2020-04-11-apis-are-not-in-the-efficiency-business/</guid><description>CityFlo Reduces Google Maps API Bill by 94% Google Directions API limited their free tier . CityFlo uses this API to calculate ETAs. Initially, CityFlo queried the API every time a stop was registered.
This was the problem. The number of API calls should be dependent on the stops themselves, not the buses. For an MVP, sure - make that query - but if you&amp;rsquo;re running a growing business, those calls add up!</description></item><item><title>Kernighan's Remarks on the Digital Humanities</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/miscellaneous/2018-10-01-digital-humanities-with-kernighan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/miscellaneous/2018-10-01-digital-humanities-with-kernighan/</guid><description>OCR tends to miss (sometimes) really important context.
Make use of derived data, e.g. age at marriage, gender differences, mortality rates, mapping migrations, last names
Don&amp;rsquo;t spend all your time cleaning data.
Try a sequence of things, not one big idea.
Don&amp;rsquo;t expect existing tools to do the whole job. All the while, building new tools is not as straightforward.
Sample Digital Humanities Projects ORBIS by Stanford .</description></item></channel></rss>