<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>web.archive.org on Chege&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/domains/web.archive.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content in web.archive.org on Chege&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.curiosities.dev/domains/web.archive.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Academic Research</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/knowing/2021-06-15-on-academic-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/knowing/2021-06-15-on-academic-research/</guid>
      <description>Going to a talk is difficult for everyone because nobody understands the whole thing, but it&amp;rsquo;s especially difficult for undergraduates because they still expect to. 
   is a rich resource for understanding scholarly literature. Browse it. Some of the listed items are familiar, e.g. Google Scholar, SCImago, Sci-Hub, but it&amp;rsquo;d be informative to zoom out to the larger picture, e.g. good alternatives to Google Scholar.
  Why Even Read Papers?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wall Street Potpourri</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/2021-01-30-potpurri/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/2021-01-30-potpurri/</guid>
      <description>Maximizing the Value for Shareholders Suing a company for not following its code of ethics and therefore misleading investors doesn&amp;rsquo;t fly, but Signet Jewelers settled for $240m . Signet&amp;rsquo;s 70k female employees sued for discrimination, but the class action is yet to be resolved. 
 Tom Toro&amp;rsquo;s New Yorker cartoon   : Yes, the planet got destroyed. But for a beautiful moment in time we created a lot of value for shareholders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Health Ethics</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/2020-05-02-health-ethics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/2020-05-02-health-ethics/</guid>
      <description>Harden, a liberal behavior geneticist, is publishing a book, &amp;ldquo;The Genetic Lottery: Why DNA Matters for Social Equality&amp;rdquo;.  Watch this space as it casts doubt on prevailing social justice thesis that environmental factors, and not genetics, influence behavior or social outcomes.
Check back in Sept 2022 (one year from now).
  Faster Human Trials In 1986, AZT (AIDS treatment) showed 1/145 deaths compared to the placebo&amp;rsquo;s 16/137. 6,000 AIDS patients were offered AZT, helping it get to the public much faster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investing in Kenya</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/investing-in-kenya/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/investing-in-kenya/</guid>
      <description>Areas to Consider Capital Markets The Central Depository and Settlement Corporation (CDSC) runs the Central Depository System (CDS) that facilitates holding and trading of shares at the Nairobi Stock Exchange (NSE). A Central Depository Agent (CDA) is a Stockbroker, an Investment Bank, or a Custodian Bank, who has been authorized by the CDSC to open accounts in CDS on behalf of investors.  
In 2006, an Automatic Trading System was introduced so that orders are matched automatically and executed by stockbrokers on a first-come first-served basis.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
