<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Big Tech on Chege's Blog</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/tags/big-tech/</link><description>Recent content in Big Tech on Chege's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.curiosities.dev/tags/big-tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Free Speech in Cyberspace</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/politics-and-governance/2020-04-29-free-speech-in-cyberspace/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/politics-and-governance/2020-04-29-free-speech-in-cyberspace/</guid><description>Should Platforms Be Neutral? Facebook banned praise, support and representation of white nationalism and separatism, because the two concepts cannot be meaningfully separated from white supremacy and organized hate groups. Furthermore, people that search for related terms will have &amp;ldquo;Life After Hate&amp;rdquo; suggested to them.
Part of me is uncomfortable. Sure, Facebook is trying to do the right thing here. What if Facebook was replaced by some tyrannical government that censors opposition?</description></item><item><title>APIs Are Not In the Efficiency Business</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/miscellaneous/2020-04-11-apis-are-not-in-the-efficiency-business/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/miscellaneous/2020-04-11-apis-are-not-in-the-efficiency-business/</guid><description>CityFlo Reduces Google Maps API Bill by 94% Google Directions API limited their free tier . CityFlo uses this API to calculate ETAs. Initially, CityFlo queried the API every time a stop was registered.
This was the problem. The number of API calls should be dependent on the stops themselves, not the buses. For an MVP, sure - make that query - but if you&amp;rsquo;re running a growing business, those calls add up!</description></item><item><title>Facebook to Pay $550 Million to Settle Facial Recognition Suit</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/www/the-battle-for-the-web/2020-01-29-fb-550m-fine-for-facial-recognition/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/www/the-battle-for-the-web/2020-01-29-fb-550m-fine-for-facial-recognition/</guid><description>Facebook to Pay $550 Million to Settle Facial Recognition Suit. Natasha Singer; Mike Isaac. www.nytimes.com . Jan 29, 2020. Illinois' biometric privacy law requires companies to obtain written permission before collecting a person’s biometrics. Residents have the right to sue for up to $5,000 per violation.
Facebook&amp;rsquo;s Tag Suggestions harvested facial data without getting written consent nor telling Illinois users for how long the data would be kept.</description></item><item><title>Facebook Monetizing Encrypted Messaging by Analyzing Metadata [Twitter]</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/www/the-battle-for-the-web/2019-01-25-fb-monetizing-encrypted-messages/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/www/the-battle-for-the-web/2019-01-25-fb-monetizing-encrypted-messages/</guid><description>Facebook Monetizing Encrypted Messaging by Analyzing Metadata. @SarahJamieLewis. twitter.com . Jan 25, 2019. Claim: FB will track relationships and social groups and make that information accessible to law enforcement. FB is a corporation that needs to make money; surveillance makes them money.
Contention: Actual privacy and security must protect metadata as well as content.
Cwtch by OpenPrivacy aims to minimize metadata exposed by apps used.</description></item><item><title>IBM Watson's Health Saga</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/2018-06-25-ibm-watsons-health-saga/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/2018-06-25-ibm-watsons-health-saga/</guid><description>Layoffs at Watson Health Reveal IBM’s Problem with AI. Eliza Strickland. spectrum.ieee.org . news.ycombinator.com . Jun 25, 2018. Jefferies gives IBM Watson a Wall Street reality check. John Mannes. techcrunch.com . news.ycombinator.com . Jul 13, 2017. IBM acquired Phytel, Explorys and Truven for their troves of healthcare data and proprietary analytics.
From 2010 to 2015, IBM has spent +$15bn and Watson is still not profitable.</description></item><item><title>An Apology for the Internet - How It Went Wrong [Intelligencer]</title><link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/www/the-battle-for-the-web/2018-04-16-an-apology-for-the-internet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/www/the-battle-for-the-web/2018-04-16-an-apology-for-the-internet/</guid><description>An Apology for the Internet - How It Went Wrong. Noah Kulwin. nymag.com . Apr 16, 2018. Start with hippie good intentions. A generation embracing new technology as a tool to transform the world for good.
Can Duruk: You were going to Facebook not to work but to make the world more open and connected. Mix in capitalism on steroids. To save the world, you first need to take it over.</description></item></channel></rss>