<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The World Wide Web on Chege&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/www/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The World Wide Web on Chege&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/www/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reviews of WWW Proceedings</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/www/2021-10-12-reviews-of-www-proceedings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/www/2021-10-12-reviews-of-www-proceedings/</guid>
      <description>32nd ACM Conference on Hypertext and Social Media (HT &amp;lsquo;21) Reconstructing Ireland&amp;rsquo;s Lost History through the Beyond 2022 Project  Aims to create a virtual 3-D reconstruction of the &amp;ldquo;Record Treasury&amp;rdquo; of the Public Record Office of Ireland in Dublin. The original one was destroyed in Ireland&amp;rsquo;s Civil War of 1922. Reassembling will use copies, transcripts and records scattered among archival partners.
The full text of  discusses challenges presented by the Beyond 2022 project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy on the Web</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/www/2021-01-05-privacy-on-the-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/www/2021-01-05-privacy-on-the-web/</guid>
      <description>One can use curl -v &amp;lt;url&amp;gt; to see all of the redirections and cookies set.  found that generating a tiny URL for Zoom links gives a URL that first goes to redirect.viglink.com.
I tried this on https://tinyurl.com/yyte6pqv, which points to https://www.c13u.com/socioeconomics/2020-11-21-experiments-in-social-economics/, but didn&amp;rsquo;t observe any 3rd party cookies. tinyurl.com did set a cookie, but that&amp;rsquo;s probably expected.
   proposes Federated Learning of Cohorts, which aims to enable ad-targeting based on people&amp;rsquo;s general browsing interest without exposing the exact browsing history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chrome vs. Everybody</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/www/2020-05-19-chrome-vs-everybody/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/www/2020-05-19-chrome-vs-everybody/</guid>
      <description>Browser Market Share Worldwide (2009 - 2020). Source: statcounter | GlobalStats
  At the very least, Chrome is worth studying. Something worked out. I&amp;rsquo;m biased, I only plan to deeply explore Chromium-based browsers and Firefox.
  Stability, Testing and the Multi-Process Architecture  In a single-threaded browser, devs use asynchronous APIs - which may sometimes hold the browser up. Instead of multiple threads, Chromium chose multiple processes: isolation, independent crashes, better asymptotic memory management, identifying expensive sites, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Zooming Web Browser</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/www/1996-11-05-a-zooming-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 1996 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/www/1996-11-05-a-zooming-browser/</guid>
      <description>A Zooming Web Browser.  Bederson, Benjamin B.; Hollan, James D.; Stewart, Jason; Rogers, David; Vick, David; Ring, Laura; Grose, Eric; Forsythe, Chris. Multimedia Computing and Networking, 1996. Vol. 2667. https://www.osti.gov/servlets/purl/454001  . https://www.connectedpapers.com/main/05064f81c4a6352889d2057214e75bb729f39c2f/Zooming-Web-browser/list  .   Interesting because these were the early days of the web, back when Netscape was king. The web could have evolved in different ways. Why didn&amp;rsquo;t the zooming browser catch on?
  Problem Context Navigating the web presents a struggle between focus and context.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
