<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Battle for the Web on c13u&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/www/the-battle-for-the-web/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Battle for the Web on c13u&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/www/the-battle-for-the-web/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Politics of Free Speech</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/www/the-battle-for-the-web/2020-04-29-politics-of-free-speech/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/www/the-battle-for-the-web/2020-04-29-politics-of-free-speech/</guid>
      <description>Should Platforms Be Neutral? Facebook banned praise, support and representation of white nationalism and separatism, because the two concepts cannot be meaningfully separated from white supremacy and organized hate groups. Furthermore, people that search for related terms will have &amp;ldquo;Life After Hate&amp;rdquo; suggested to them. []
Part of me is uncomfortable. Sure, Facebook is trying to do the right thing here. What if Facebook was replaced by some tyrannical government that censors opposition?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook to Pay $550 Million to Settle Facial Recognition Suit [The New York Times]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/www/the-battle-for-the-web/2020-01-29-fb-550m-fine-for-facial-recognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/www/the-battle-for-the-web/2020-01-29-fb-550m-fine-for-facial-recognition/</guid>
      <description>Facebook to Pay $550 Million to Settle Facial Recognition Suit.  Natasha Singer; Mike Isaac. The New York Times. https://www.nytimes.com/2020/01/29/technology/facebook-privacy-lawsuit-earnings.html . Jan 29, 2020.  Illinois&amp;rsquo; biometric privacy law requires companies to obtain written permission before collecting a person’s biometrics. Residents have the right to sue for up to $5,000 per violation.
Facebook&amp;rsquo;s Tag Suggestions harvested facial data without getting written consent nor telling Illinois users for how long the data would be kept.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We ran the numbers, and there really is a pipeline problem in eng hiring. [interviewing.io]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/www/the-battle-for-the-web/2019-12-03-there-is-a-pipeline-problem-in-eng-hiring/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/www/the-battle-for-the-web/2019-12-03-there-is-a-pipeline-problem-in-eng-hiring/</guid>
      <description>We ran the numbers, and there really is a pipeline problem in eng hiring.  Aline Lerner. http://blog.interviewing.io/we-ran-the-numbers-and-there-really-is-a-pipeline-problem-in-eng-hiring/ . https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21694348 . Dec 3, 2019.  Wait, but research shows:
 STEM in early education is unfriendly to children from underrepresented backgrounds Lack of a level playing field and unequal access to quality STEM education Hostile university culture in male-dominated CS programs Biased hiring practices Non-inclusive work environments cause higher churn of underrepresented folk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The New York Times Sells Premium Ads Based on How an Article Makes You Feel [Poynter]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/www/the-battle-for-the-web/2019-04-10-nyt-sells-ads-based-on-how-an-article-makes-you-feel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/www/the-battle-for-the-web/2019-04-10-nyt-sells-ads-based-on-how-an-article-makes-you-feel/</guid>
      <description>The New York Times Sells Premium Ads Based on How an Article Makes You Feel.  Rick Edmonds. Poynter. https://www.poynter.org/business-work/2019/the-new-york-times-sells-premium-ads-based-on-how-an-article-makes-you-feel/ . Apr 10, 2019.  The NYT piloted ad placements based on the emotions certain articles evoke.
The average lift to an ad is 40% NYT can charge more for those ads.
Will the newsroom be tasked with producing lots of emotional stories? NYT&amp;rsquo;s claims:
 The newsroom turned out plenty of emotionally charged stories, anyhow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Trauma Floor: The Secret Lives of FB Moderators in America [The Verge]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/www/the-battle-for-the-web/2019-02-25-the-secret-lives-of-fb-mods-in-america/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/www/the-battle-for-the-web/2019-02-25-the-secret-lives-of-fb-mods-in-america/</guid>
      <description>The Trauma Floor: The Secret Lives of FB Moderators in America.  Casey Newton. The Verge. https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/25/18229714/cognizant-facebook-content-moderator-interviews-trauma-working-conditions-arizona . Feb 25, 2019.  Moderators in Phoenix will make just $28,800 per year — while the average FB employee has a total compensation of $240,000.
Team leaders micro-manage content moderators&amp;rsquo; every bathroom break. Two Muslim employees were ordered to stop praying during their 9min/day of allotted &amp;ldquo;wellness time&amp;rdquo;.
Employees can be fired after making just a handful of errors a week, and those who remain live in fear of former colleagues returning to seek vengeance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Monetizing Encrypted Messaging by Analyzing Metadata [Twitter]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/www/the-battle-for-the-web/2019-01-25-fb-monetizing-encrypted-messages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/www/the-battle-for-the-web/2019-01-25-fb-monetizing-encrypted-messages/</guid>
      <description>Facebook Monetizing Encrypted Messaging by Analyzing Metadata.  @SarahJamieLewis. https://twitter.com/SarahJamieLewis/status/1088914192847917056 . Jan 25, 2019.  Claim: FB will track relationships and social groups and make that information accessible to law enforcement. FB is a corporation that needs to make money; surveillance makes them money.
Contention: Actual privacy and security must protect metadata as well as content.
 Cwtch by OpenPrivacy   aims to minimize metadata exposed by apps used. It&amp;rsquo;s built on Tor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Apology for the Internet - How It Went Wrong [Intelligencer]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/www/the-battle-for-the-web/2018-04-16-an-apology-for-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/computer-science/www/the-battle-for-the-web/2018-04-16-an-apology-for-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>An Apology for the Internet - How It Went Wrong.  Noah Kulwin. NY Mag. http://nymag.com/intelligencer/2018/04/an-apology-for-the-internet-from-the-people-who-built-it.html . Apr 16, 2018.  Start with hippie good intentions. A generation embracing new technology as a tool to transform the world for good.
 Can Duruk: You were going to Facebook not to work but to make the world more open and connected.  Mix in capitalism on steroids. To save the world, you first need to take it over.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>