<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Business on Chege&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/tags/business/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Business on Chege&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.curiosities.dev/tags/business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bad Blood [John Carreyrou]</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/_meta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/carreyrou-bad-blood/_meta/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lean Startups vs. VC Money</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/on-starting-a-business/2020-12-18-lean-vs-vc-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/on-starting-a-business/2020-12-18-lean-vs-vc-money/</guid>
      <description>20 years later, JetBrains is valued at $7b without taking VC money. HN users praise JetBrains for being user-focused, and the prevailing argument is that VC money comes with growth-hacking attached. 
Is the Lean Startup Dead? Katzenberg (Paramount, Disney Studios &amp;amp; DreamWorks) has raised $1.75b for NewTV, a startup banking on consumers wanting a subscription for 10-minute programs on mobile.
They renamed to quibi.com/   . At least that makes them more searchable on Google.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Running a Business</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/2020-11-29-advice-on-running-a-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/2020-11-29-advice-on-running-a-business/</guid>
      <description>Consultants are not well suited for strategy (you probably have a deeper understanding). They are also an expensive way of proving your point to management. However, they are good for emergency horsepower, e.g. data analysis, and for primary research within your industry (they probably have a broader understanding). 
Having a competitive advantage may reduce the incentive to explore other ideas, especially ones that conflict with your chosen [successful] strategy. Additionally, having to maintain/exceed quarterly numbers dissuade incumbents from risk taking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Startup Ideation</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/on-starting-a-business/2020-07-05-startup-ideation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/on-starting-a-business/2020-07-05-startup-ideation/</guid>
      <description>How to Get Startup Ideas  Err on the side of having competitors, but make sure that you have a thesis that everyone else is overlooking, e.g. Google wasn&amp;rsquo;t averse to users leaving google.com ASAP.
The Startup Idea Matrix, ( B2B Edition   , B2C Edition   ) is a good start for knowing who to google.
  Big companies tend to be slow at changing their approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unorthodox Startups</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/on-starting-a-business/2020-05-20-unorthodox-startups/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/on-starting-a-business/2020-05-20-unorthodox-startups/</guid>
      <description>Innovation Africa &amp;amp; Water Availability  Bring in Israeli solar panels and drip irrigation. Pump water from the large reservoirs below. Cost $7,000.
Adapting to community: 6-8 weeks on committees, bank accounts; mobile charging stations and barbershops using solar panels for sustainability. Can&amp;rsquo;t sell the water, but you can subsidize it with complementary products.
Set up remote monitoring with real time stats in order to schedule maintenance.
Honorable Mentions Push Party by MSCHF is valued at $200m, led by The Founders Fund.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>APIs Are Not In the Efficiency Business</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/miscellaneous/2020-04-11-apis-are-not-in-the-efficiency-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/miscellaneous/2020-04-11-apis-are-not-in-the-efficiency-business/</guid>
      <description>CityFlo Reduces Google Maps API Bill by 94%  Google Directions API limited their free tier   . CityFlo uses this API to calculate ETAs. Initially, CityFlo queried the API every time a stop was registered.
This was the problem. The number of API calls should be dependent on the stops themselves, not the buses. For an MVP, sure - make that query - but if you&amp;rsquo;re running a growing business, those calls add up!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Financing the Disadvantaged</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/2020-02-12-financing-the-disadvantaged/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/2020-02-12-financing-the-disadvantaged/</guid>
      <description>Short Term Loans A common narrative for loan providers is financial inclusion. 69% of global adult population is not covered by credit bureaus. Using non-traditional data (e.g. text messages, location, contacts, call logs), more people can get scored. 
If only \(x\%\) of people pay you back, then \(\frac{x}{100}(1 + r) \ge 1 \) suggests \(r \ge \frac{100}{x} - 1 \). If \(75\%\) tend to pay back, \(r = 33\frac{1}{3} \%\).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/</guid>
      <description>Content related to financial matters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AT&amp;T to pay $60m in settlement for slowing cellphone data on unlimited plans</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/optimism_and_deception/2019-11-05-att-pay-60m-in-settlement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/optimism_and_deception/2019-11-05-att-pay-60m-in-settlement/</guid>
      <description>AT&amp;amp;T to pay $60m in settlement for slowing cellphone data on unlimited plans.  www.reuters.com  . Nov 5, 2019.     Complaint filed in 2014 by the FTC: AT&amp;amp;T charged smartphone users for &amp;lsquo;unlimited&amp;rsquo; data plans, but throttled them after ~2GB within a month.
  AT&amp;amp;T: None of these allegations were ever proved in court. We were fully prepared to defend ourselves, but decided settling was in the best interests of consumers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Dentistry a Science? [The Atlantic]</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/2019-05-01-is-dentistry-a-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/2019-05-01-is-dentistry-a-science/</guid>
      <description>Is Dentistry a Science?  Ferris Jabr. www.theatlantic.com  . May 1, 2019.    Cochrane Oral Health   reviews dental procedures in a systematic manner. Unfortunately, most of the reviews don&amp;rsquo;t find substantive support for dental interventions.
There is currently no substantive evidence for: binannual cleanings, fluoridation reducing tooth decay in adults; regular flossing combating plaque (gum disease? probably); preventative wisdom teeth removal; tooth-colored resin instead of metal amalgam fillings; crown vs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Shady Economics of Buy-One-Get-One Free Deals [The Hustle]</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/optimism_and_deception/2019-02-17-shady-economics-of-buy-one-get-one-free-deals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/optimism_and_deception/2019-02-17-shady-economics-of-buy-one-get-one-free-deals/</guid>
      <description>The Shady Economics of Buy-One-Get-One Free Deals.  Zachary Crockett. thehustle.co  . Feb 17, 2019.   BOGO goods are usually low-demand, non-efficient, lacking in quality and/or close to the expiration date. The BOGO deal is usually a 50% discount off of the manufacturer’s suggested retail price (MSRP). And oftentimes, this price is artificially marked up to begin with.
 MyPillow offered BOGO deal on their pillows, but really just doubled the price of the first pillow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monopolistic Tendencies in the Prescription Glasses Industry</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/2019-01-22-why-are-glasses-so-expensive/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/2019-01-22-why-are-glasses-so-expensive/</guid>
      <description>Luxottica - Queen of the Seven Kingdoms  Luxottica owns and licenses Armani, Brooks Brothers, Burberry, Chanel, Coach, DKNY, Dolce &amp;amp; Gabbana, Michael Kors, Oakley, Oliver Peoples, Persol, Polo Ralph Lauren, Ray-Ban, Tiffany, Valentino, Vogue and Versace.
Italy&amp;rsquo;s Luxottica also runs EyeMed Vision Care, LensCrafters, Pearle Vision, Sears Optical, Sunglass Hut and Target Optical. It also merged with the world&amp;rsquo;s leading maker of prescription eyeglass lenses and contact lenses, to form EssilorLuxottica.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IBM Watson&#39;s Health Saga</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/2018-06-25-ibm-watsons-health-saga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/2018-06-25-ibm-watsons-health-saga/</guid>
      <description>Layoffs at Watson Health Reveal IBM’s Problem with AI.  Eliza Strickland. spectrum.ieee.org  . news.ycombinator.com  . Jun 25, 2018.   Jefferies gives IBM Watson a Wall Street reality check.  John Mannes. techcrunch.com  . news.ycombinator.com  . Jul 13, 2017.     IBM acquired Phytel, Explorys and Truven for their troves of healthcare data and proprietary analytics.
  From 2010 to 2015, IBM has spent +$15bn and Watson is still not profitable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>U.S. Files Criminal Charges Against Elizabeth Holmes and Ramesh Balwani [WSJ]</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/2018-06-15-theranos-disaster/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/2018-06-15-theranos-disaster/</guid>
      <description>U.S. Files Criminal Charges Against Elizabeth Holmes and Ramesh Balwani.  John Carreyrou. www.wsj.com  . news.ycombinator.com  . Jun 15, 2018.   (Ask HN) Holmes has 200 Patents. If tech didn&amp;#39;t work, why not noticed?  news.ycombinator.com  . Jun 18, 2018.   Theranos Lessons.  Morgan Housel. www.collaborativefund.com  . Jun 19, 2019.   This CEO is Out for Blood.  Roger Parloff. www.fortune.com  .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Creator&#39;s Code: The Six Essential Skills of Extraordinary</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/on-starting-a-business/creators-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/on-starting-a-business/creators-code/</guid>
      <description>[These creators] prove that little daring and discipline can go a long way, and that entrepreneurship is accessible to everyone.
Is it though? Some are born into situations where entrepreneurial risk is unbearable. It&amp;rsquo;s not as meritocratic as the author claims.
  The author arrived at the 6 essential skills via Grounded Theory analysis of interviews with ~200 creators.
Grounded Theory: pose question; collect data; iteratively review that data while encoding ideas/concepts that &amp;ldquo;emerge&amp;rdquo; from the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Submarine [Paul Graham]</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/optimism_and_deception/2005-04-01-the-submarine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/business/optimism_and_deception/2005-04-01-the-submarine/</guid>
      <description>The Submarine.  Paul Graham. www.paulgraham.com  . Apr 1, 2005.   Many people rely on social proof to form opinions; therein lies the power of PR.
PR firms are not dishonest for they need good reputation with news outlets. But PR firms serve overworked reporters with selective truths.
The firms feed the same story to different publications at once. Readers see similar stories in multiple places and assume a new trend has come.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Dentists Rip Us Off [William Ecenbarger]</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/1997-02-01-how-dentists-rip-us-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 1997 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/1997-02-01-how-dentists-rip-us-off/</guid>
      <description>How Dentists Rip Us Off.  William Ecenbarger. digitalsmiledesign.com  . Feb 1, 1997.   This piece was brought up in &amp;ldquo;Is Dentistry a Science?&amp;quot;   ( summary  ). Looks like this piece has done its rounds in dentist online spaces.
  Ecenbarger pitch: moving into the area; had done gum surgery; had a direct-reimbursement program to cover expenses; interested in good oral health; no desire for cosmetic improvements</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
