<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>dx.doi.org on Chege&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/domains/dx.doi.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content in dx.doi.org on Chege&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.curiosities.dev/domains/dx.doi.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Socio-Economic Equity in Tech</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/2021-10-28-socio-economic-equity-in-tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/computer-science/2021-10-28-socio-economic-equity-in-tech/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to STEM diversity goals, Asian American and Pacific Islander (AAPI) tends to be excluded from the URMs under discussion, e.g. .
However, AAPI as a blanket term obscures the struggles of member groups, e.g. \(62\%\) of AAPI adults aged 24 and older have an associate&amp;rsquo;s degree or higher, compared to 28% of Native Hawaiians and Pacific Islanders of the same age. AA comprises \(\approx 50\) ethnic groups, while PI has \(\approx 20\).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Future of Corporate Governance Part I: The Problem of Twelve</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/trading-and-investing/2018-10-03-problem-of-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/trading-and-investing/2018-10-03-problem-of-12/</guid>
      <description>The Problem of Twelve: In the near future, roughly 12 individuals will have practical power over majority of US public companies.
A Short History of Corporations  In the first stage, entrepreneurs get money from savings, &amp;ldquo;friends, family, and fools&amp;rdquo;, and VCs. Securities law restricts this to sophisticated investors only.
On generating revenue and stability, the entrepreneur takes the firm public (IPO) under oversight from the SEC. Ownership is separated from control, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Political Correctness</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/politics-and-governance/2021-09-03-political-correctness/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/politics-and-governance/2021-09-03-political-correctness/</guid>
      <description>From my vantage point, it seems there are two camps. But reality is often a shade of grey. Interested in various arguments that frequently arise in this area. I have my opinions/biases, but nothing that I can defend rigorously.
Some (most?) of these claims are supported by anecdotal evidence, which is an avenue for belief fixation, and therefore makes it hard to come to a resolution  .
I don&amp;rsquo;t know if it&amp;rsquo;s because anti-PC material is more viral, but most of the prominent publications are either anti-PC, or anti-anti-PC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10,000 Hours &#43;/- 10,000 Hours</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/sports/epstein-sports-gene/02-10k-hours-pm-10k-hours/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/sports/epstein-sports-gene/02-10k-hours-pm-10k-hours/</guid>
      <description>10,000 Hours, YMMV  10,000 hours introduced here    10,000 hours has been lauded by popular authors, e.g. Malcolm Gladwel&amp;rsquo;s Outliers, and Geoff Colvin&amp;rsquo;s Talent is Overrated. Notably, Ericsson has dismissed the &amp;ldquo;10,000 hours rule&amp;rdquo; as misconstruing his positions: genetics play a role; 10,000-hours of deliberate practice is not all that counts. 
Most data in support of the 10,000-hours rule has been cross-sectional and retrospective.
A cross-sectional study is a type of observational study that analyzes data from a population (or a representative subset) at a specific point in time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
