<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Politics in Technology on c13u&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Politics in Technology on c13u&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>We ran the numbers, and there really is a pipeline problem in eng hiring. [interviewing.io]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2019-12-03-there-is-a-pipeline-problem-in-eng-hiring/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2019-12-03-there-is-a-pipeline-problem-in-eng-hiring/</guid>
      <description>We ran the numbers, and there really is a pipeline problem in eng hiring.. Aline Lerner. http://blog.interviewing.io/we-ran-the-numbers-and-there-really-is-a-pipeline-problem-in-eng-hiring/. https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21694348. 2019-12-03.  Wait, but research shows:
 STEM in early education is unfriendly to children from underrepresented backgrounds Lack of a level playing field and unequal access to quality STEM education Hostile university culture in male-dominated CS programs Biased hiring practices Non-inclusive work environments cause higher churn of underrepresented folk.  Systemic issues can be hard to fix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The New York Times Sells Premium Ads Based on How an Article Makes You Feel [Poynter]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2019-04-10-nyt-sells-ads-based-on-how-an-article-makes-you-feel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2019-04-10-nyt-sells-ads-based-on-how-an-article-makes-you-feel/</guid>
      <description>The New York Times Sells Premium Ads Based on How an Article Makes You Feel. Rick Edmonds. Poynter. https://www.poynter.org/business-work/2019/the-new-york-times-sells-premium-ads-based-on-how-an-article-makes-you-feel/. 2019-04-10.  The NYT piloted ad placements based on the emotions certain articles evoke.
The average lift to an ad is 40% NYT can charge more for those ads.
Will the newsroom be tasked with producing lots of emotional stories? NYT&#39;s claims:
 The newsroom turned out plenty of emotionally charged stories, anyhow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standing Against Hate [Facebook]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2019-03-27-fb-standing-against-hate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2019-03-27-fb-standing-against-hate/</guid>
      <description>Standing Against Hate. https://about.fb.com/news/2019/03/standing-against-hate/. https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19503094. 2019-03-27.  Main Article We now ban praise, support and representation of white nationalism and separatism on FB and Instagram
We didn&#39;t ban them before because their broader concepts, e.g. American pride and Basque separatism, are an important part of people&#39;s identity.
Experts in race relations have confirmed that white nationalism and separatism cannot be meaningfully separated from white supremacy and organized hate groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Trauma Floor: The Secret Lives of FB Moderators in America [The Verge]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2019-02-25-the-secret-lives-of-fb-mods-in-america/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2019-02-25-the-secret-lives-of-fb-mods-in-america/</guid>
      <description>The Trauma Floor: The Secret Lives of FB Moderators in America. Casey Newton. The Verge. https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/25/18229714/cognizant-facebook-content-moderator-interviews-trauma-working-conditions-arizona. 2019-02-25.  Moderators in Phoenix will make just $28,800 per year — while the average FB employee has a total compensation of $240,000.
Team leaders micro-manage content moderators&amp;rsquo; every bathroom break. Two Muslim employees were ordered to stop praying during their 9min/day of allotted &amp;ldquo;wellness time&amp;rdquo;.
Employees can be fired after making just a handful of errors a week, and those who remain live in fear of former colleagues returning to seek vengeance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FB Under Pressure to Halt Rise of Anti-Vaccination Groups [The Guardian]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2019-02-12-fb-versus-antivaxx-groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2019-02-12-fb-versus-antivaxx-groups/</guid>
      <description>FB Under Pressure to Halt Rise of Anti-Vaccination Groups. Ed Pilkington, Jessica Glenza. The Guardian. https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2019/feb/12/facebook-anti-vaxxer-vaccination-groups-pressure-misinformation. 2019-02-12.  Vitamin C &amp;amp; Orthomolecular Medicine for Optimal Health. Closed Group. 49,000 approved members.
 Gironda, an admin, sells high-dose Vitamin C in bulk through Revitalize Wellness. The &amp;lsquo;shop now&amp;rsquo; button links to her firm. Revitalize Wellness carries a disclaimer saying that its products are “not intended to treat, diagnose, cure or prevent disease”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Chinese Govt Controls the Media [SoECS]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2018-10-01-chinese-media-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2018-10-01-chinese-media-control/</guid>
      <description>Seeing government influence through coordination of sensitive coverage, localization of negative news &amp;amp; crowding out other stories on the front page.
Structural topic models (LDA + context, e.g. topic prevalence, choice of words) analyze fundamental aspect of the news that can&#39;t be changed.
Instead of assuming news follows events, investigate!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons Learned in Tech Policy [SoECS]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2018-10-01-lessons-learned-in-tech-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2018-10-01-lessons-learned-in-tech-policy/</guid>
      <description>Local governments face severe constraints. Liaising with big tech for employees on sabbaticals could alleviate this.
State legislators may have unfounded opinions, but they have the sway, so work with them.
Rural-urban differences. Rural folk were more active. Urban folks wrote angry blogs and that was it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wolf that Tried to Play Nice [SoECS]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2018-10-01-the-wolf-that-tried-to-play-nice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2018-10-01-the-wolf-that-tried-to-play-nice/</guid>
      <description>AT&amp;amp;T restricted FaceTime from running on some data plans. Justifications?
 FaceTime is preloaded, therefore 100% of users have it FaceTime wasn&#39;t efficient in network usage. The capacity was asymmetrical, but video chat is symmetrical  Interestingly enough, AT&amp;amp;T required Apple to greenlight it, which they did. AT&amp;amp;T worked with top developers to teach network etiquette.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computers Can Solve Your Problem. You May Not Like the Answer. [Boston Globe]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2018-09-21-boston-public-school-equity-algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2018-09-21-boston-public-school-equity-algorithm/</guid>
      <description>Computers Can Solve Your Problem. You May Not Like the Answer. What happened when Boston Public Schools tried for equity with an algorithm. David Scharfenberg. The Boston Globe. https://apps.bostonglobe.com/ideas/graphics/2018/09/equity-machine/. 2018-09-21.  Teens need their sleep: sleep-deprived teens are at increased risk for poor academic performance, binge drinking, and suicide.
BPS laid out the algorithm’s four guiding principles:
 Increase the number of high school students starting school after 8am Decrease the number of elementary school students dismissed after 4pm Accommodate the needs of special education students wherever possible Generate transportation savings that could be reinvested in the schools  Officials picked a solution that attempted to balance several goals — student health, cost savings, and parental happiness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cambridge Analytica Uncovered: Secret filming reveals election tricks [Channel 4]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2018-03-19-cambridge-analytica-uncovered/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2018-03-19-cambridge-analytica-uncovered/</guid>
      <description>Cambridge Analytica Uncovered: Secret filming reveals election tricks. Channel 4 News. https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mpbeOCKZFfQ. 2018-03-19.  Pay people to take surveys but through an app. Mine their profile data, and also crawl their friends.
Identify swayable voters and their sensitivities. Craft targeted ads. Play on (unconscious) fears and hopes.
Elections are about emotions, not facts. Data science and social media can help us make sense of and manipulate the chaos.
An alternative argument: political misinformation is&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So You Want to Reform Democracy [Medium]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2015-11-22-so-you-want-to-reform-democracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/notes/technology/politics-in-technology/2015-11-22-so-you-want-to-reform-democracy/</guid>
      <description>So You Want to Reform Democracy. Joshua Tauberer. https://medium.com/civic-tech-thoughts-from-joshdata/so-you-want-to-reform-democracy-7f3b1ef10597. 2015-11-22.  If there was an idea that could &amp;lsquo;fix&amp;rsquo; democracy, it would have been thought-up already. If you don&#39;t see your idea out there, it’s because it didn’t work the hundreds of other times someone tried it.
Let’s tell representatives what their constituents think. Then they HAVE to vote with us!
 They don’t necessarily want to know what their constituents are thinking.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>