<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Knowing on c13u&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.c13u.com/knowing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Knowing on c13u&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.c13u.com/knowing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading and Writing to Know</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/knowing/2020-05-02-reading-and-writing-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/knowing/2020-05-02-reading-and-writing-to-know/</guid>
      <description>Reading to Know Choose your content. Some books [and articles] are not worth the effort. Sometimes you just don&#39;t care whether you&#39;ll remember what you&#39;ve read. []
But even if you don&#39;t remember the specifics, the effect on your model of the world persists. As your mental model evolves, re-reading books is beneficial because the material compiles differently. []
When reading, annotate connections from previous knowledge, unanswered questions and unjustified assumptions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theory About Theories</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/knowing/2020-01-08-theory-about-theories/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/knowing/2020-01-08-theory-about-theories/</guid>
      <description>On Coming Up With New Theories A crackpot publicizes a theory that feels right. A theorist goes further to try and disprove a theory that feels right, before publishing it. []
There is still value in an earnest well-thought out theory, even if it turns out wrong, e.g. saving others the trouble. Juniors spend far more time making sure they know everything, while seniors release more half-baked ideas - yet the senior&#39;s half-baked ideas will probably be more widely read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Deep Work &amp; The 30-Hour Method for Learning a New Skill [Azeria Labs]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/knowing/2018-05-26-azeria-labs-importance-of-deep-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/knowing/2018-05-26-azeria-labs-importance-of-deep-work/</guid>
      <description>The Importance of Deep Work &amp;amp; The 30-Hour Method for Learning a New Skill.  Azeria Labs. https://azeria-labs.com/the-importance-of-deep-work-the-30-hour-method-for-learning-a-new-skill/. https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17163251.  30 Hour Deep Work Tryout:
 Scan resources and pick the ones that seem most useful (5 hours) Set up the environment and define structured goals (3 hours) Work towards increasingly difficult goals set in step 2 (22 hours)  Each session should be about 4 hours. It takes about 20min to get into the flow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Summary] (Syll) What is Ergodicity?</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/knowing/2016-11-23-syll-what-is-ergodicity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/knowing/2016-11-23-syll-what-is-ergodicity/</guid>
      <description>What is Ergodicity?  Lars P. Syll. https://larspsyll.wordpress.com/2016/11/23/what-is-ergodicity-2/. Nov 23, 2016.  A random process is ergodic if all of its statistics can be determined from a sample function of the process. That is, the ensemble averages equal the corresponding time averages with probability one.
Role of Ergodicity in Human Inference  A newspaper has previously printed some inaccurate information, therefore, the newspaper is going to publish inaccurate information in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Read a Paper [Keshav]</title>
      <link>https://www.c13u.com/knowing/2016-02-17-how-to-read-a-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.c13u.com/knowing/2016-02-17-how-to-read-a-paper/</guid>
      <description>How to Read a Paper.  S. Keshav. David R. Cheriton School of Computer Science, University of Waterloo. https://blizzard.cs.uwaterloo.ca/keshav/home/Papers/data/07/paper-reading.pdf. Feb 17, 2016.  The First Pass (5 - 10 min) Objectives: category, context, validity of assumptions, contributions and quality of writing.
 Carefully read the title, abstract, and introduction. Read the section and sub-section headings, but ignore everything else Glance at the math to determine the underlying theoretical foundations Read the conclusions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>