<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Knowing on Chege&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/knowing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Knowing on Chege&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.curiosities.dev/knowing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Misconstructions and Misconceptions</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/knowing/2021-08-02-misconstructions-and-misconceptions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/knowing/2021-08-02-misconstructions-and-misconceptions/</guid>
      <description>A collection of instances in which I believed something that wasn&amp;rsquo;t true. A reminder to read not to believe, but to weigh and consider  .
  The Four Color Theorem does not claim that 4 colors suffice to color a planar map. Instead, 4 colors are sufficient to color any planar graph so that no two vertices connected by an edge are colored with the same color. For any \(n\), there is a map that requires at least \(n\) colors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Academic Research</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/knowing/2021-06-15-on-academic-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/knowing/2021-06-15-on-academic-research/</guid>
      <description>How to Read a Paper  The First Pass (5 - 10 min) Objectives: category, context, validity of assumptions, contributions and quality of writing.
 Carefully read the title, abstract, and introduction. Read the section and sub-section headings, but ignore everything else Glance at the math to determine the underlying theoretical foundations Read the conclusions. Mentally tick off references that you&amp;rsquo;ve already read.  Most of the papers will not make it beyond this step.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Learning</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/knowing/2020-05-02-on-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/knowing/2020-05-02-on-learning/</guid>
      <description>Choose your content. Some material not worth the effort. Learning comes from repetition, but sometimes you just don&amp;rsquo;t care whether you&amp;rsquo;ll remember what you&amp;rsquo;ve read. 
But even if you don&amp;rsquo;t remember the specifics, the effect on your model of the world persists. As your mental model evolves, re-reading books is beneficial because the material compiles differently. 
When reading, annotate connections from previous knowledge, unanswered questions and unjustified assumptions. Make flashcards of facts/quotes that you wish to analyze.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
