<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Health and Medicine on Chege&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Health and Medicine on Chege&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Contact Tracing for COVID-19</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/2020-05-06-contact-tracing-for-covid-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/2020-05-06-contact-tracing-for-covid-19/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Apps&amp;rdquo; in this context means contact tracing apps released by public health authorities to do contact tracing. The APIs are limited to them.
  Big Picture  Release APIs to enable apps to interoperate between Android and iOS devices.  Bluetooth-based contact tracing baked into Android and iOS, such that no app is needed for broadcasting/listening.  This ensures broad adoption, but will be on an opt-in basis.   Interesting debate for privacy, ethics and public health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Health Ethics</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/2020-05-02-health-ethics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/2020-05-02-health-ethics/</guid>
      <description>Faster Human Trials In 1986, AZT (AIDS treatment) showed 1/145 deaths compared to the placebo&amp;rsquo;s 16/137. 6,000 AIDS patients were offered AZT, helping it get to the public much faster. 
Different rules apply in a pandemic. If the treatment is sufficiently promising, we should skip to human clinical trials. Covid-19 has a lower fatality rate than AIDS, which set a precedent. 3,000 altruists have even offered to deliberately expose themselves to covid-19!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Dentistry a Science? [The Atlantic]</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/2019-05-01-is-dentistry-a-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/2019-05-01-is-dentistry-a-science/</guid>
      <description>Is Dentistry a Science?  Ferris Jabr. The Atlantic. https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2019/05/the-trouble-with-dentistry/586039/  . May 1, 2019.   Cochrane Oral Health   reviews dental procedures in a systematic manner. Unfortunately, most of the reviews don&amp;rsquo;t find substantive support for dental interventions.
There is currently no substantive evidence for: binannual cleanings, fluoridation reducing tooth decay in adults; regular flossing combating plaque (gum disease? probably); preventative wisdom teeth removal; tooth-colored resin instead of metal amalgam fillings; crown vs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monopolistic Tendencies in the Prescription Glasses Industry</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/2019-01-22-why-are-glasses-so-expensive/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/2019-01-22-why-are-glasses-so-expensive/</guid>
      <description>Luxottica - Queen of the Seven Kingdoms  Luxottica owns and licenses Armani, Brooks Brothers, Burberry, Chanel, Coach, DKNY, Dolce &amp;amp; Gabbana, Michael Kors, Oakley, Oliver Peoples, Persol, Polo Ralph Lauren, Ray-Ban, Tiffany, Valentino, Vogue and Versace.
Italy&amp;rsquo;s Luxottica also runs EyeMed Vision Care, LensCrafters, Pearle Vision, Sears Optical, Sunglass Hut and Target Optical. It also merged with the world&amp;rsquo;s leading maker of prescription eyeglass lenses and contact lenses, to form EssilorLuxottica.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On DNA Testing</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/2018-09-18-on-dna-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/2018-09-18-on-dna-testing/</guid>
      <description>The human genome has sequences of nucleotide base pairs that are repeated over and over again. At each locus of interest, a person has two sets of repeats inherited from each parent. Each possible difference at a locus is an allele. The combinations of the possible differences at multiple loci form a DNA profile that can be used to tie suspects to a crime scene. 
The Accuracy of DNA Testing is Wanting  74/108 crime labs erroneously incriminated a suspect during a mock study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IBM Watson&#39;s Health Saga</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/2018-06-25-ibm-watsons-health-saga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/2018-06-25-ibm-watsons-health-saga/</guid>
      <description>Layoffs at Watson Health Reveal IBM’s Problem with AI.  Eliza Strickland. IEEE. https://spectrum.ieee.org/the-human-os/robotics/artificial-intelligence/layoffs-at-watson-health-reveal-ibms-problem-with-ai  . https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17393560  . Jun 25, 2018.  Jefferies gives IBM Watson a Wall Street reality check.  John Mannes. https://techcrunch.com/2017/07/13/jefferies-gives-ibm-watson-a-wall-street-reality-check/  . https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=14766793  . Jul 13, 2017.    IBM acquired Phytel, Explorys and Truven for their troves of healthcare data and proprietary analytics.
  From 2010 to 2015, IBM has spent +$15bn and Watson is still not profitable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>U.S. Files Criminal Charges Against Elizabeth Holmes and Ramesh Balwani [WSJ]</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/2018-06-15-theranos-disaster/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/2018-06-15-theranos-disaster/</guid>
      <description>U.S. Files Criminal Charges Against Elizabeth Holmes and Ramesh Balwani.  John Carreyrou. The Wall Street Journal. https://www.wsj.com/articles/u-s-files-criminal-charges-against-theranoss-elizabeth-holmes-ramesh-balwani-1529096005  . https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17323485  . Jun 15, 2018.  (Ask HN) Holmes has 200 Patents. If tech didn&amp;#39;t work, why not noticed?  Hacker News. https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17328664  . Jun 18, 2018.  Theranos Lessons.  Morgan Housel. Collaborative Fund&amp;#39;s Blog. https://www.collaborativefund.com/blog/theranos-lessons/  . Jun 19, 2019.  This CEO is Out for Blood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Dentists Rip Us Off [William Ecenbarger]</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/1997-02-01-how-dentists-rip-us-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 1997 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/1997-02-01-how-dentists-rip-us-off/</guid>
      <description>How Dentists Rip Us Off.  William Ecenbarger. Reader&amp;#39;s Digest. https://digitalsmiledesign.com/files/Old-Website-Assets/PDF/How-Dentists-Rip-Us-Off.pdf  . Feb 1, 1997.  This piece was brought up in &amp;ldquo;Is Dentistry a Science?&amp;quot;   ( summary  ). Looks like this piece has done its rounds in dentist online spaces.
  Ecenbarger pitch: moving into the area; had done gum surgery; had a direct-reimbursement program to cover expenses; interested in good oral health; no desire for cosmetic improvements</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toward a Theory of Medical Fallibility</title>
      <link>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/1976-01-01-toward-a-theory-of-medical-fallibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1976 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.curiosities.dev/health-and-medicine/1976-01-01-toward-a-theory-of-medical-fallibility/</guid>
      <description>Medical care is like the opposite of moving fast and breaking things. If it&amp;rsquo;s so taboo to admit error, then that could make errors more common because fewer people are learning from past errors.
  Norms for Scientific Activity and the Sources of Error &amp;ldquo;Science&amp;rdquo; is taken to mean &amp;ldquo;Natural Science&amp;rdquo;.
  Internal norms derive from a cognitive pursuit of science. They are:
 Focus on the central rather than the peripheral problems of the science in in question.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
